<?xml version="1.0"?>
<articlecomments>
  <comments articlename="comments_enabled">
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2010-04-18 15:49</datetime>
      <message>It works! ;)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Robert</name>
      <datetime>2010-04-19 11:04</datetime>
      <message>Finally! Keep up the nice work. I like the way your site is evolving. </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Pesito</name>
      <datetime>2010-04-21 17:12</datetime>
      <message>Ich freue mich schon auf den RSS-Feed. In 3 Jahren dann ungef&amp;Atilde;&amp;curren;hr? ;-)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2010-04-21 23:43</datetime>
      <message>RSS-Feed habe ich schon mal &amp;Atilde;&amp;frac14;berlegt. Mal sehen. ;)</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="rss_feed_added">
    <comment>
      <name>Robert</name>
      <datetime>2010-04-28 13:33</datetime>
      <website>http://www.cms-testlabor.de</website>
      <message>Woo Hoo, Erik was listening to me :-) &#xD;
I've added you to my feed reader.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Robert</name>
      <datetime>2010-04-28 14:28</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Oh, I have a design suggestion for your website, maybe you'll like it: http://bit.ly/bBeZC7</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2010-04-30 16:51</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Yeah, I guess some animated gifs and looping background music could really add something to my site. :)</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="windows7_backup_error_code_0x810000ff">
    <comment>
      <name>Robert</name>
      <datetime>2010-06-11 11:11</datetime>
      <website>http://www.cms-testlabor.de/blog</website>
      <message>I have also setup a regular backup on my external hard drive, so far without any weird error hex codes.&#xD;
But I am also experimenting with Microsofts SkyDrive, which gives you 25 GB (!) of free storage. So far it worked really well. This way if my place burns down or I am travelling with my laptop I will still keep my important files :-)</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="sony_ericsson_xperia_x10_mini_pro_hands-on_review">
    <comment>
      <name>Robert</name>
      <datetime>2010-07-30 10:33</datetime>
      <website>http://www.cms-testlabor.de</website>
      <message>Nice review! I really is a pretty decent phone. &#xD;
I am a bit shocked by a max of 2 days battery life, though. My HTC Magic can make 3 days if I don't use it much.&#xD;
Totally agree on the crappy music player that comes with it - I recently installed Mort Player (free), which seems to be a lot better.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2010-08-01 14:03</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>About battery life: I learned it the hard way after the phone died on me - after just some 36 hours of usage. NES emulation seems to need a lot of juice. YMMV, as always.&#xD;
&#xD;
I also use and can warmly recommend the Mort Player. Look at the picture of the phone in this review - the upper right shortcut actually points to Mort and not the default player (you can tell by the icon).</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>P&amp;Atilde;&amp;curren;r</name>
      <datetime>2010-08-07 18:20</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Emulation is a battery hog. Usually the emulator is written in a way that it doesn't sleep at all and is running the emulated CPU etc. all the time. &#xD;
I don't know what the official standby time is but the journalist tech geeks seems to charge their cellphones every evening.&#xD;
Only android 1.6... that ain't new... but it may be easier on the batteries with less features.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2010-08-09 21:06</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Yeah, 1.6 may not sound very exciting - it does work pretty well though so I can't really complain. But I am secretly looking forward to that rumored 2.x upgrade. Let's just wait and see.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-03-12 22:47</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Just to make things clear, an Android 2.1 update is available for this phone since several months back and it is working well. It does not slow down the phone (noticeably) and it fixes some problems - some web pages not working properly in the browser before now show up as expected, for example.</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="plantronics_.audio_995_vs_creative_hs-1200">
    <comment>
      <name>rob</name>
      <datetime>2011-01-03 20:48</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hey man great review.  I was actually considering buying both these products and returning the one I didn't like but now I don't need to.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Hab</name>
      <datetime>2011-02-13 00:56</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hey man, graet review. I just have 1 question. You say the Plantronic one is not chargable while using it. Is that becuase of the range of the USB cable or the fact that it has no power in it while its battery is dead? I mean if I were to buy a longer miniusb to usb cable and the headset died, could I plug that on in, w8 10 min and use it while being charge?&#xD;
&#xD;
Thanks fpr reading // Hab</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-03-12 22:42</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Sorry for taking so long time replying to this, but better late than never I guess. Fact is, the headset cannot be used when charging at all, it basically stays switched off while charging. The Creative headset does not suffer from this.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Don McGuiney</name>
      <datetime>2011-04-03 05:23</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I really enjoyed your review. I have a problem. I bought the Plantronics unit but it won't play any sound. It installed very easyband shows in the control panel but I can't use them. Any suggestions?&#xD;
Thanks,</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-04-03 15:41</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Don,&#xD;
&#xD;
there are a few things you can do to make sure things are set up properly. A common problem is that Windows is sending sound to the wrong device, since the OS can only direct sound output to one device at a time.&#xD;
&#xD;
After connecting the USB dongle and having turned on the headset, right click the speaker icon next to the Windows clock and select "Playback devices". The headset should show up in the list. Now, select the headset and click the "Set Default" button (or select "Default communication device" if you only want to use it with Skype and the like). Click "Properties" and make sure the volume is not set to zero (under the "Levels" tab).&#xD;
&#xD;
For mic setup, just select "Recording devices" instead of "Playback devices" and you will be able to figure out the rest.&#xD;
&#xD;
The changes should take effect immediately, but in some cases you may have to restart the application playing sounds (Windows Media Player, Skype or whatever).&#xD;
&#xD;
If this doesn't help, try using the headset with another PC.</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="shiny_icon_maker_-_new_features">
    <comment>
      <name>Erik Jonson</name>
      <datetime>2011-01-08 12:21</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>No need using fancy graphics program. This do the work in a minute.&#xD;
Thanks!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik Jonson</name>
      <datetime>2011-01-08 12:26</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Tweaking suggestion :-)&#xD;
It would be nice to have a digit showing what font size (and rotation) value is selected.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-01-08 20:18</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks for the feedback! The suggested functionality has been implemented, just waiting to be tried out. ;)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Robert (WebsiteToolTester)</name>
      <datetime>2011-01-11 11:25</datetime>
      <website>http://www.websitetooltester.com</website>
      <message>Cool new features! I'll give your icon maker a test run and write an article about it soon.</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="save_a_bundle_using_old_camera_lenses">
    <comment>
      <name>AJ Velazco</name>
      <datetime>2011-01-14 04:36</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Nice information...Excellent pictures</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="getting_started_with_star_trails">
    <comment>
      <name>Henrik</name>
      <datetime>2011-02-18 21:04</datetime>
      <website>http://henrikpettersson.blogg.se</website>
      <message>Nicely done! I have tried this to, but only with one long exposure. They are - as you probably know - not that good. Even at ISO100 is there a lot of grain and all those annoying hot pixels on the sensor are visible. And just as you&#xB4;ve written will parts of the image be overexposed by the surrounding city lights. I don&#xB4;t have a remote shutter (besides the IR) and will thus keep this project in mind for the future.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-03-12 22:55</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks! I think I will give this a shot again sometime - I just got myself a brand new tripod just waiting to be tried out. ;)</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="diy_drop_handlebars_to_bullhorns">
    <comment>
      <name>Pamo</name>
      <datetime>2011-03-20 15:32</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Ser ju riktigt elegant ut!&#xD;
-M&#xE5;ster testas!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Ilja</name>
      <datetime>2011-03-24 19:39</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>V&#xE4;lt&#xE4;nkt och v&#xE4;lutf&#xF6;rt. Fem ringklockor av fem m&#xF6;jliga.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-03-24 19:46</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Man tackar! S&#xE5;gen l&#xF6;ser alla problem, som man ju s&#xE4;ger.</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="ask_731sp_3g_smartpad_review">
    <comment>
      <name>Raphael</name>
      <datetime>2011-03-22 16:32</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hia, &#xD;
&#xD;
I have the same thing, i got it when i went to hong-kong, but i hate android 2.1&#xD;
&#xD;
is there a way to root this thing?&#xD;
&#xD;
Thnx!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-03-23 18:44</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Well, I'm not sure rooting it will really solve any of the inherent limitations of 2.1 - the lack of flash support is a major flaw, and I have yet to find a working solution.&#xD;
&#xD;
But rooting is fun, so why not? I recommend you head over to the nice people at android tablets, they have a lot of good tips:&#xD;
&#xD;
http://www.androidtablets.net/forum/&#xD;
&#xD;
As for myself, I may do it sometime in the future. However, I'm not risking bricking this thing yet. ;)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>mark</name>
      <datetime>2011-04-09 01:25</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I purchased the ASK smart pad at HG as well. Have the keyboard as well. Can anyone tell me how to activate it?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-04-09 01:25</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>To use the keyboard, you need to activate USB Host mode. Go to Settings, select "USB Mode Select" and tick "Host Mode". The keyboard (or other USB devices, like USB sticks) can now be connected.&#xD;
&#xD;
After a reboot, the setting is reset and need to be reactivated. Apparently, it draws a lot of power so this should be a "good thing".</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>julie clarke</name>
      <datetime>2011-04-28 16:28</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I have one, my husband just brought it back from Hong Kong.  Its an ASK 741 SP if that helps.  I cant wait to get playing on it but I cant get it to log in to our wifi at home.  It finds it but then says its weak and drops off.  I know our wifi is strong and so I dont know what to do to get on and start playing.  Please please help</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-04-28 19:48</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Julie,&#xD;
&#xD;
tough one. I had zero problems setting mine up. The router was set to use WPA2 with AES and a pre-shared key. My network showed up in the list (Wireless &amp; network settings), I chose it, left security to auto, entered password and it just worked.&#xD;
&#xD;
I would do the usual things; reboot the router, play around a bit with the security settings (on both ends), and, if nothing helps, try the tablet on a friend's network. Maybe the tablet just doesn't play nice with your router. Also, I have heard that there are compatibility issues between some 802.11n devices, 802.11b/g (slower/older router) should be fine though. &#xD;
&#xD;
Hope this helps.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Alexander</name>
      <datetime>2011-05-07 10:27</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Erik, hi&#xD;
I've bought ASK 741SP (not 731SP)&#xD;
Device don't work, don't load OS - only start page&#xD;
Serviceman say that it's necessary to upgrade (firmware is damaged) , but manufacturer refused to upload firmware in order to I can solve my problem. Have U a firmware for 741SP, can U help me?&#xD;
&#xD;
Thanks a lot! </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-05-08 13:25</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Alexander,&#xD;
&#xD;
I'm afraid I will have to disappoint you. I don't have the firmware for 741, neither do I know which one it uses or how to acquire it. If it's under warranty, just exchange for a new one.&#xD;
&#xD;
If that is not an option, you can find a lot of information on how to install firmware/fixing bricked tablets here:&#xD;
&#xD;
http://www.slatedroid.com&#xD;
&#xD;
Please note that you always flash at your own risk.&#xD;
&#xD;
Good luck!</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="fake_raindrops_macro_photography">
    <comment>
      <name>Robert</name>
      <datetime>2011-04-07 17:32</datetime>
      <website>http://www.snapp.de</website>
      <message>Good stuff, where's the Like button?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-04-07 19:11</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks! And to answer your question: nowhere - yet. Facebook integration should be a piece of cake though, maybe I'll have a look at it this weekend or so.</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="getting_linux_on_that_dingoo">
    <comment>
      <name>Erik F.</name>
      <datetime>2011-04-12 13:10</datetime>
      <website>http://threemilesfinal.com</website>
      <message>Nice article and great site!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-04-12 19:52</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks! And nice name, by the way. ;)</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="the_social_network">
    <comment>
      <name>Robert</name>
      <datetime>2011-04-26 10:48</datetime>
      <website>http://www.snapp.de</website>
      <message>I really liked the movie, so you won't get a like this time ;-)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-04-26 22:30</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>There are other options as well. If you don't Like it - Tweet it!</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="vignetting_with_the_gimp">
    <comment>
      <name>Marky T</name>
      <datetime>2011-05-05 13:51</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Excellent way to make a subtle effect. Just what I was looking for so thanks for the info.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-05-07 13:13</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Glad to be of help. :)</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="diy_dslr_camera_sling_strap">
    <comment>
      <name>Henrik</name>
      <datetime>2011-05-15 21:53</datetime>
      <website>http://henrikpettersson.blogg.se</website>
      <message>I was close to buy a Blackrapid RS-4 for the hideous price of 700 SEK. Until a found that my the bag to my new lens came with a basic sling strap. Everyone should have a sling strap, because it&#xB4;s just better! &#xD;
Get an extra strap and fasten to your tripod aswell. It isn&#xB4;t perfect but it makes life a bit easier.&#xD;
Great article btw.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-05-17 22:12</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Good idea about a tripod strap. I like my tripod, it was definitely a big upgrade from the el cheapo I had before. But the better they are, the bigger and heavier they get (mostly). Next DIY project, maybe?</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="simple_photo_studio_at_home">
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-06-01 20:17</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Testing.</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
</articlecomments>
