<?xml version="1.0"?>
<articlecomments>
  <comments articlename="comments_enabled">
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2010-04-18 15:49</datetime>
      <message>It works! ;)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Robert</name>
      <datetime>2010-04-19 11:04</datetime>
      <message>Finally! Keep up the nice work. I like the way your site is evolving. </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Pesito</name>
      <datetime>2010-04-21 17:12</datetime>
      <message>Ich freue mich schon auf den RSS-Feed. In 3 Jahren dann ungef&#xE4;hr? ;-)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2010-04-21 23:43</datetime>
      <message>RSS-Feed habe ich schon mal &#xFC;berlegt. Mal sehen. ;)</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="rss_feed_added">
    <comment>
      <name>Robert</name>
      <datetime>2010-04-28 13:33</datetime>
      <website>http://www.cms-testlabor.de</website>
      <message>Woo Hoo, Erik was listening to me :-) &#xD;
I've added you to my feed reader.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Robert</name>
      <datetime>2010-04-28 14:28</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Oh, I have a design suggestion for your website, maybe you'll like it: http://bit.ly/bBeZC7</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2010-04-30 16:51</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Yeah, I guess some animated gifs and looping background music could really add something to my site. :)</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="windows7_backup_error_code_0x810000ff">
    <comment>
      <name>Robert</name>
      <datetime>2010-06-11 11:11</datetime>
      <website>http://www.cms-testlabor.de/blog</website>
      <message>I have also setup a regular backup on my external hard drive, so far without any weird error hex codes.&#xD;
But I am also experimenting with Microsofts SkyDrive, which gives you 25 GB (!) of free storage. So far it worked really well. This way if my place burns down or I am travelling with my laptop I will still keep my important files :-)</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="sony_ericsson_xperia_x10_mini_pro_hands-on_review">
    <comment>
      <name>Robert</name>
      <datetime>2010-07-30 10:33</datetime>
      <website>http://www.cms-testlabor.de</website>
      <message>Nice review! I really is a pretty decent phone. &#xD;
I am a bit shocked by a max of 2 days battery life, though. My HTC Magic can make 3 days if I don't use it much.&#xD;
Totally agree on the crappy music player that comes with it - I recently installed Mort Player (free), which seems to be a lot better.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2010-08-01 14:03</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>About battery life: I learned it the hard way after the phone died on me - after just some 36 hours of usage. NES emulation seems to need a lot of juice. YMMV, as always.&#xD;
&#xD;
I also use and can warmly recommend the Mort Player. Look at the picture of the phone in this review - the upper right shortcut actually points to Mort and not the default player (you can tell by the icon).</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>P&amp;Atilde;&amp;curren;r</name>
      <datetime>2010-08-07 18:20</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Emulation is a battery hog. Usually the emulator is written in a way that it doesn't sleep at all and is running the emulated CPU etc. all the time. &#xD;
I don't know what the official standby time is but the journalist tech geeks seems to charge their cellphones every evening.&#xD;
Only android 1.6... that ain't new... but it may be easier on the batteries with less features.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2010-08-09 21:06</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Yeah, 1.6 may not sound very exciting - it does work pretty well though so I can't really complain. But I am secretly looking forward to that rumored 2.x upgrade. Let's just wait and see.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-03-12 22:47</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Just to make things clear, an Android 2.1 update is available for this phone since several months back and it is working well. It does not slow down the phone (noticeably) and it fixes some problems - some web pages not working properly in the browser before now show up as expected, for example.</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="plantronics_.audio_995_vs_creative_hs-1200">
    <comment>
      <name>rob</name>
      <datetime>2011-01-03 20:48</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hey man great review.  I was actually considering buying both these products and returning the one I didn't like but now I don't need to.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Hab</name>
      <datetime>2011-02-13 00:56</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hey man, graet review. I just have 1 question. You say the Plantronic one is not chargable while using it. Is that becuase of the range of the USB cable or the fact that it has no power in it while its battery is dead? I mean if I were to buy a longer miniusb to usb cable and the headset died, could I plug that on in, w8 10 min and use it while being charge?&#xD;
&#xD;
Thanks fpr reading // Hab</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-03-12 22:42</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Sorry for taking so long time replying to this, but better late than never I guess. Fact is, the headset cannot be used when charging at all, it basically stays switched off while charging. The Creative headset does not suffer from this.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Don McGuiney</name>
      <datetime>2011-04-03 05:23</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I really enjoyed your review. I have a problem. I bought the Plantronics unit but it won't play any sound. It installed very easyband shows in the control panel but I can't use them. Any suggestions?&#xD;
Thanks,</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-04-03 15:41</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Don,&#xD;
&#xD;
there are a few things you can do to make sure things are set up properly. A common problem is that Windows is sending sound to the wrong device, since the OS can only direct sound output to one device at a time.&#xD;
&#xD;
After connecting the USB dongle and having turned on the headset, right click the speaker icon next to the Windows clock and select "Playback devices". The headset should show up in the list. Now, select the headset and click the "Set Default" button (or select "Default communication device" if you only want to use it with Skype and the like). Click "Properties" and make sure the volume is not set to zero (under the "Levels" tab).&#xD;
&#xD;
For mic setup, just select "Recording devices" instead of "Playback devices" and you will be able to figure out the rest.&#xD;
&#xD;
The changes should take effect immediately, but in some cases you may have to restart the application playing sounds (Windows Media Player, Skype or whatever).&#xD;
&#xD;
If this doesn't help, try using the headset with another PC.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>rex</name>
      <datetime>2011-09-18 20:01</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>i was wondering if i had more than 1 pair of 995 headphones&#xD;
can i pair both of them to the one usb dongle if both paired  ?&#xD;
thank you</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-09-21 19:11</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi rex,&#xD;
&#xD;
according to Plantronics, the dongle does not support multipoint. Thus, it is only possible to connect one headset, not two.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Barry</name>
      <datetime>2011-10-19 22:04</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Erik,&#xD;
Wanted to thank you for your help with the Windows Media, but also wanted to add that I had to change the option in Windows Media Player under Tools, Options, Devices, Speakers, Properties and select the Plantronics headset under that.&#xD;
thnx</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-10-19 22:21</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Barry,&#xD;
glad to be of help. :) And you have a good point - often the audio device can be selected directly from within the application in question. Skype is another example.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>richard</name>
      <datetime>2013-01-18 13:09</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>i bought 995h audio wireless,unfortunately when i play my songs cannot hear by other party specially on skype? TY.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-01-19 16:10</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Richard,&#xD;
&#xD;
to make sure that Skype is using the headset, go to Tools-&gt;audio settings and select the Plantronics as both microphone and speakers. Also see tip above in comments regarding setting the default audio devices in Windows.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Vin</name>
      <datetime>2013-12-03 04:55</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thank you Eric for this nice comparison a few years ago. I was actually using the 995 for many years. I found it buy chance on a website and got stuck with it.
Every one of my headsets lasts for 1-1.5 years and dies (either the battery stops being able to be charged and it is irreplaceable or it just stops communicating with the dongle) and now I'm sick of it.
The last one I had died months ago and now I am looking for a better option and thinking to myself "they must've developed a new thing that is better after all these years".
Better, I mean, a Plantronics that:
1. works while charging
&amp;
2. has a replaceable battery
I am actually willing to pay much more because I am so used to those things.
Any suggestions?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-12-04 00:15</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Vin,

you may not like my answer, but I currently use a wired Steelseries Siberia V2 headset and I have no complaints. Cutting the cord still has its share of problems, mostly battery life. Some colleagues of mine use wireless headsets for Skype (Logitech H800) and because of the battery drain, they simply keep them plugged in most of the time, mostly defeating the purpose of using a wireless headset. But at least you can charge while using them. Maybe worth a shot?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>AlexL</name>
      <datetime>2018-09-13 02:58</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>The microphone of Logitech Wireless Headset H800 may not working sometime, especially on Windows 10.</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="shiny_icon_maker_-_new_features">
    <comment>
      <name>Erik Jonson</name>
      <datetime>2011-01-08 12:21</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>No need using fancy graphics program. This do the work in a minute.&#xD;
Thanks!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik Jonson</name>
      <datetime>2011-01-08 12:26</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Tweaking suggestion :-)&#xD;
It would be nice to have a digit showing what font size (and rotation) value is selected.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-01-08 20:18</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks for the feedback! The suggested functionality has been implemented, just waiting to be tried out. ;)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Robert (WebsiteToolTester)</name>
      <datetime>2011-01-11 11:25</datetime>
      <website>http://www.websitetooltester.com</website>
      <message>Cool new features! I'll give your icon maker a test run and write an article about it soon.</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="save_a_bundle_using_old_camera_lenses">
    <comment>
      <name>AJ Velazco</name>
      <datetime>2011-01-14 04:36</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Nice information...Excellent pictures</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Mithun Basak</name>
      <datetime>2011-07-08 15:05</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I like this Camera...........</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-07-09 13:27</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Yeah, it's pretty cool. ;)</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="getting_started_with_star_trails">
    <comment>
      <name>Henrik</name>
      <datetime>2011-02-18 21:04</datetime>
      <website>http://henrikpettersson.blogg.se</website>
      <message>Nicely done! I have tried this to, but only with one long exposure. They are - as you probably know - not that good. Even at ISO100 is there a lot of grain and all those annoying hot pixels on the sensor are visible. And just as you&#xB4;ve written will parts of the image be overexposed by the surrounding city lights. I don&#xB4;t have a remote shutter (besides the IR) and will thus keep this project in mind for the future.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-03-12 22:55</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks! I think I will give this a shot again sometime - I just got myself a brand new tripod just waiting to be tried out. ;)</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="diy_drop_handlebars_to_bullhorns">
    <comment>
      <name>Pamo</name>
      <datetime>2011-03-20 15:32</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Ser ju riktigt elegant ut!&#xD;
-M&#xE5;ster testas!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Ilja</name>
      <datetime>2011-03-24 19:39</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>V&#xE4;lt&#xE4;nkt och v&#xE4;lutf&#xF6;rt. Fem ringklockor av fem m&#xF6;jliga.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-03-24 19:46</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Man tackar! S&#xE5;gen l&#xF6;ser alla problem, som man ju s&#xE4;ger.</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="ask_731sp_3g_smartpad_review">
    <comment>
      <name>Raphael</name>
      <datetime>2011-03-22 16:32</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hia, &#xD;
&#xD;
I have the same thing, i got it when i went to hong-kong, but i hate android 2.1&#xD;
&#xD;
is there a way to root this thing?&#xD;
&#xD;
Thnx!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-03-23 18:44</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Well, I'm not sure rooting it will really solve any of the inherent limitations of 2.1 - the lack of flash support is a major flaw, and I have yet to find a working solution.&#xD;
&#xD;
But rooting is fun, so why not? I recommend you head over to the nice people at android tablets, they have a lot of good tips:&#xD;
&#xD;
http://www.androidtablets.net/forum/&#xD;
&#xD;
As for myself, I may do it sometime in the future. However, I'm not risking bricking this thing yet. ;)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>mark</name>
      <datetime>2011-04-09 01:25</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I purchased the ASK smart pad at HG as well. Have the keyboard as well. Can anyone tell me how to activate it?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-04-09 01:25</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>To use the keyboard, you need to activate USB Host mode. Go to Settings, select "USB Mode Select" and tick "Host Mode". The keyboard (or other USB devices, like USB sticks) can now be connected.&#xD;
&#xD;
After a reboot, the setting is reset and need to be reactivated. Apparently, it draws a lot of power so this should be a "good thing".</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>julie clarke</name>
      <datetime>2011-04-28 16:28</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I have one, my husband just brought it back from Hong Kong.  Its an ASK 741 SP if that helps.  I cant wait to get playing on it but I cant get it to log in to our wifi at home.  It finds it but then says its weak and drops off.  I know our wifi is strong and so I dont know what to do to get on and start playing.  Please please help</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-04-28 19:48</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Julie,&#xD;
&#xD;
tough one. I had zero problems setting mine up. The router was set to use WPA2 with AES and a pre-shared key. My network showed up in the list (Wireless &amp; network settings), I chose it, left security to auto, entered password and it just worked.&#xD;
&#xD;
I would do the usual things; reboot the router, play around a bit with the security settings (on both ends), and, if nothing helps, try the tablet on a friend's network. Maybe the tablet just doesn't play nice with your router. Also, I have heard that there are compatibility issues between some 802.11n devices, 802.11b/g (slower/older router) should be fine though. &#xD;
&#xD;
Hope this helps.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Alexander</name>
      <datetime>2011-05-07 10:27</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Erik, hi&#xD;
I've bought ASK 741SP (not 731SP)&#xD;
Device don't work, don't load OS - only start page&#xD;
Serviceman say that it's necessary to upgrade (firmware is damaged) , but manufacturer refused to upload firmware in order to I can solve my problem. Have U a firmware for 741SP, can U help me?&#xD;
&#xD;
Thanks a lot! </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-05-08 13:25</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Alexander,&#xD;
&#xD;
I'm afraid I will have to disappoint you. I don't have the firmware for 741, neither do I know which one it uses or how to acquire it. If it's under warranty, just exchange for a new one.&#xD;
&#xD;
If that is not an option, you can find a lot of information on how to install firmware/fixing bricked tablets here:&#xD;
&#xD;
http://www.slatedroid.com&#xD;
&#xD;
Please note that you always flash at your own risk.&#xD;
&#xD;
Good luck!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>edgar</name>
      <datetime>2011-06-16 09:39</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi erik,&#xD;
Hi bought 741 sp in HK, can you teach me how to remove the web site in the history, i want to remove some of the sites that i browsed but i don't know how. Please help. Thanks.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-06-18 10:58</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi edgar,&#xD;
&#xD;
to clear the history, open the browser and tap the menu button (top right of the screen, as always). From the menu, tap "more", then "Settings". Scroll down to "Privacy". From here, cache, history and cookies can be deleted.&#xD;
&#xD;
Google also saves your search history, which you can delete separately. From the Google start page, tap the "Settings" link. Scroll down to "Search history" and tap "Clear saved searches".&#xD;
&#xD;
Hope this helps.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Nigel</name>
      <datetime>2011-06-20 00:34</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I bought a 741 in HK and every time you swithch it on it say for all applications eg - The application AK Notepad (process com akproduction.notepad) has stopped unexpectedly. Please try again. Then is has  FORCE CLOSE. what has gone wrong, any ideas ?? Thanks </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-06-20 19:15</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Nigel,&#xD;
&#xD;
I am not familiar with the AK Notepad myself, but I guess it's possible that it just doesn't work on the SmartPad. This just tends to happen sometimes - it is a quite cheap product with almost zero support, after all. I'm afraid the only tip I can give you is to reinstall the app, and if that doesn't work, try to find an alternative (there should be plenty).</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Paul T</name>
      <datetime>2011-06-22 14:15</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Eric&#xD;
I have a 7" Tablet (Optus ZTE) It came with Android 2.1 but I upgraded it to 2.2. Only problem is 2.1 had a 'Host Mode' option in settings and the Case/Keyboard worked fine, but in 2.2 there is no Host Mode option in settings, and now the Keyboard case, doesn't work when I plug in the micro usb connector?&#xD;
Any Suggestions?&#xD;
Thanks.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-07-09 13:21</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Paul,&#xD;
&#xD;
I have yet to try to upgrade my device, and this is one reason. I have not been able to find any info on how to do this. Hopefully, a helpful soul will find your post and provide an answer.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Kate</name>
      <datetime>2011-08-15 14:34</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi&#xD;
I also bought ASK 731SP 3G in Hong Kong. Disappointed with it but would accept even being able to use it as a Kinder! Can I download my own selection of books from Amazon and if so HOW!! Please help.&#xD;
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-08-15 20:25</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Kate,&#xD;
&#xD;
sure thing! (Assuming you mean Kindle.) Just use the ASK and open the Android Market, then search for "Amazon Kindle" or something similar. The official Kindle app should show up. Download and install, then start the application. Log on with your Amazon username and password, and you are good to go. They have a few free samples (classics like Dracula or Pride and Prejudice) that you can try first.&#xD;
&#xD;
The application runs just fine on the ASK, maybe a bit sluggish when flipping but perfectly acceptable.&#xD;
&#xD;
Have fun!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Ronald Fung</name>
      <datetime>2011-09-15 11:42</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Do it has a root?  My 741 sp do not run root apps.  How can I fix it?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-09-17 13:47</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Ronald,&#xD;
&#xD;
I've been playing around with this, but no dice so far. I gave SuperOneClick a shot but it just kept hanging. :(</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Lilac </name>
      <datetime>2011-10-05 15:17</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Erik, &#xD;
I found the tablet turns itself back on very often. It uses more battery. I only installed Aldiko as my bookreader and  juice defender. I couldn't work out what cause the problem.&#xD;
Any idea?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-10-11 23:05</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Lilac,&#xD;
&#xD;
weird problem. My tablet only turns itself on when I plug in the charger, which seems to be a "feature". If you feel bored, you might try a factory reset, it's always a blast. ;)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>alex</name>
      <datetime>2011-10-16 05:43</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Eric. I have bought ASK 741 in HK this summer. Very nice item...but...the same problems with skype that you posted above. Please tell me could you solve this problem to use the skype application on ASK? Thank you in advance.&#xD;
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-10-16 15:52</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Alex,&#xD;
&#xD;
I have not been able to resolve this issue. Skype on Android is still immature and crashes on many devices (it works great on my SonyEricsson X10 Mini Pro though). Just keep updating to the latest version, I hope they will have these issues sorted out soon.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Bryanna</name>
      <datetime>2011-11-10 03:01</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I also bought a 3gSmart pad from HK. It is okay to play games and read books but the battery life is only about 1 hour. There was a message sent to it to say to click here and upgrade your battery life which I did. I have downloaded the file and it is in the book marks but now I can't find where the bookmarks are&#xD;
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Yuifann</name>
      <datetime>2011-11-22 13:33</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Everyone,&#xD;
&#xD;
Android 2.3 to 3.0 upgrade is available for ASK 741SP.&#xD;
I've dropped off the device to the local technical support center 2 weeks ago...approved the wifi connection as well &#xD;
***Required to drop off the smartpad for at least 3-5 days/Technician works part-time; therefore, expect pick up the other days later***</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-11-22 20:56</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Sounds interesting. Is there any way to upgrade the 731SP as well? It's running 2.1 which really starts to show its age.&#xD;
&#xD;
Anyway, post back here and let us know how it worked.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Christopher</name>
      <datetime>2012-01-05 04:24</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message> Hi Eric,I have a problem with my ASK 7 inch 3G Smartpad, model: ASK 741SP. I cannot unlock now for I attempted to unlock it for more than 5 times. It's advised now to sign-in with my GOOGLE account but I cannot because the unit is not activated to get WIFI signal. My other option is to reset the unit or go back to it's original factory setting....Please help me.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-01-08 21:27</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hello Christopher,&#xD;
&#xD;
I'm very sorry to hear that! I've never had this problem myself, but this thread at AndroidTablets may be of some help:&#xD;
&#xD;
http://www.androidtablets.net/forum/android-tablet-usage-tips-tricks/6280-forgot-your-unlock-pattern.html&#xD;
&#xD;
If you are still stuck, try searching the forum for other threads or open up a new one. A lot of helpful people over there.&#xD;
&#xD;
Hope it works out!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>mark</name>
      <datetime>2012-01-27 18:26</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>hi can u help me because every tym i open  my ask 741sp only start page what im doing to do?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-01-30 22:48</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi mark,&#xD;
&#xD;
I'm not quite sure what you mean. If it does not boot up at all and you just got it, it may be a hardware of firmware problem. Try contacting the shop where you bought it to see if you can get a new one. By the way, a corrupt firmware can usually be fixed by downloading the latest one from the manufacturer and extracting it to the root of the SD card. I'm afraid I don't know where to get the firmware though. Try contacting ASK. Their home page address is:&#xD;
http://uthk.com</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Yuifann</name>
      <datetime>2012-02-03 13:38</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Mark &amp; Erik,&#xD;
&#xD;
You may contact the Technican at ASK (support at uthk dot com)&#xD;
&amp; I advise to upgrade your OS to Android 3.0 ....Things will be solve out &gt;&gt;&gt; Remember to download it by Desktop PC &amp; connect your smartpad by OTG later on</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Yuifann</name>
      <datetime>2012-02-03 13:53</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Christopher,&#xD;
&#xD;
The device is required to sign in by gmail's account (first time use...won't ask again) Android - free OS is connect with google's &amp; gmail is now free for register.  Afterward, you'll able to access to Wifi connection...If you need dump screens, please leave your email's contact or write to me (dreamycloset at gmail dot com)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-02-04 17:27</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Yuifann,&#xD;
 &#xD;
and thanks for your interest in this article. Now, you did link to a Honeycomb system image which I highly doubt will work right off the bat for the SmartPad. To avoid people bricking their devices, I removed the download link. Please let me know (using the contact form) if you have successfully updated the device to 3.0 using the image. If so, I apologize and will re-add the link.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>mark</name>
      <datetime>2012-02-04 19:25</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Yuifann, &#xD;
&#xD;
Hi yuifann u have a link of Android 3.0 so i can download the file  to upgrage my os thx....</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>wildlizard</name>
      <datetime>2012-02-10 01:32</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>i have same to but there is a log-in how can i remove the log-in</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>joven</name>
      <datetime>2012-06-30 05:12</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>how to hard reset this pad...please tell me</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-06-30 09:42</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Joven,&#xD;
&#xD;
you can find instructions in doing a factory reset here:&#xD;
&#xD;
http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kqOSicNPFIY&#xD;
&#xD;
BTW: A regular reset, that is, restarting the unit if it freezes, is simply done by inserting a pin into the hole marked "Reset" next to the power button.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>J. Lab,</name>
      <datetime>2012-09-08 23:32</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi, I bought a ASK 750 SP in HK in May. I am looking for the owner manual, if there is one.&#xD;
Glad to read you soon.&#xD;
Thanks.&#xD;
JL.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-09-09 01:37</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi J. Lab,&#xD;
&#xD;
not sure there is one! It should work just like any "standard" Android 4.0 device though, so if you are having specific questions about the software, googling it should do it. Plenty of forums and blogs around with info on Android 4.0. Otherwise, just contact ASK directly: &#xD;
http://uthk.com</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Nkay</name>
      <datetime>2012-09-13 16:20</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hello Erik,&#xD;
just got an ASK 755SP and its in chinese. been trying to change to english language please can you help</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>J. Lab,</name>
      <datetime>2012-09-14 01:24</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi,&#xD;
good idea. Thanks.&#xD;
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-09-15 20:45</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Nkay,&#xD;
&#xD;
simply check out this video which contains instructions on how to change language from Chinese to English on Android 4:&#xD;
&#xD;
http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=M_LR5mFGDsw&#xD;
&#xD;
Good luck. :)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Wagne</name>
      <datetime>2012-12-30 01:10</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I  had ASK 750SP 3G running Android 4.0.  The pad contains a HDMI Out Port and the package comes with a HDMI cable.  When I connected the cable to TV and changed TV source to HDMI.  The TV displayed "No Signal".  Please advise how to use TV as a display screen?&#xD;
&#xD;
Thank you. </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-01-07 23:28</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Wagne,&#xD;
&#xD;
sorry for the late reply... and for not having an answer! I have a Gemei G9 tablet, and I have never gotten  the HDMI port on it to work. Apparently, just connecting it to the TV and switching TV to the correct HDMI port should do it. Maybe another TV and cable would solve it?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Morph</name>
      <datetime>2013-01-14 01:41</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi, I recently got an ASK 913SP tablet and I forgot the password to my google account and the lock pattern. Are you familiar on how to reset this unit back to factory defaults. I have been googling a lot but this unit seems not popular&#xD;
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-01-14 19:04</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Morph,&#xD;
&#xD;
I will check with ASK on how to do this. In the meantime, maybe you should simply try to recover the password for the Google account? Go here:&#xD;
&#xD;
https://accounts.google.com/RecoverAccount</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>mona</name>
      <datetime>2013-04-08 11:13</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Erik
My Aunt buy me an ASK 755sp in hongkong.
After using it in 2 weeks, the smart pad didnt charge and turn on.
I already checked the charger and it is properly working. Is there any possible way to address my problem. Thank you.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Mehrad</name>
      <datetime>2013-05-27 19:20</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Eric I have bought this tablet ASK118sp 3g smart pad  from hong kong but unfortunately Im trying to using it in Canada , Toronto and it doesnt read any sim card that i put in it I have tried every single service provider to get the reception but unfortunately non of them works I started thinking maybe its a different frequency or something would you pleaseee help me
appreciate it a lotttt</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-06-13 23:37</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>@mona: Not sure about the 755SP, but many tablet can be charger using a special USB cable (usually provided), but also using the regular mini/micro-USB (sync) port. So if one does not work, try the other one.

@Mehrad: Possibly, the countries use different standards. But I know very little about this, feel free to post back here if you manage to solve it.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>George</name>
      <datetime>2013-07-03 17:19</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>how to factory reset my ask 701sp </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-07-11 13:05</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi George,

not sure how to do  hard reset, but if a soft reset is enough, it can be done from the settings menu. Here is a video of how it's done:

http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HU_VSUAf21Q</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Nay</name>
      <datetime>2014-03-30 01:57</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I brought the tablet, randomly it started asking for a password to get in to it although I never gave it one. Only option left was to reset to factory settings after finding out how to do that the options on that menu come up in chinese so am none the wiser as to how to reset it. Any advice? </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2014-03-31 16:55</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Nay,

the factory reset is found under Settings -&gt; Privacy (5th item in the list, with a fence icon). Tap the last option ("Factory data reset") and tap the button that shows up ("reset device").

If the language on the whole device changes, go to Settings -&gt; Language &amp; keyboard (7th item, with a keyboard key icon). Tap the first item ("Select locale") and select a language.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>aplikasi android</name>
      <datetime>2014-04-18 16:34</datetime>
      <website>http://androidesia.blogspot.com/</website>
      <message>i want to upgrade to another android. my device using froyo 2.2</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2014-05-05 08:24</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi aplikasi android,

if your device manufacturer has not released an update by now, your best bet may be CyanogenMod (Google it). Haven't tried it with this particular device, but had some luck with an older SonyEricsson android phone.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Eric</name>
      <datetime>2014-10-04 21:38</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Erik
I am using android 4.2 smart pad, all works well apart from when I connect to tv via hdmi cable the picture on tv &amp; pad turns upside down, when I remove hdmi cable from smart pad it turns right way up, do you have any ideas ?
Thank  you, Eric</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>alan </name>
      <datetime>2016-02-09 19:05</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I a 9" smart pad with case but the keyboard lead is damaged is this easy to get fixed

</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2016-02-09 19:37</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Alan,

if you are sure that the connector is the problem, then it should not be a big deal. You need to crack open the USB port to check how the cables are connected (it's only three or four), then replace the connector and solder the cables onto it. A USB connector for soldering can be found in many electronics shops.

Good luck - you might need it, I assume no responsibility! ;)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>eddie</name>
      <datetime>2021-01-16 07:56</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi eric I have an ASK 851sp model please help me we lost the charger please tell me which volt dc powers use in this pad???
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2021-01-16 13:40</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi eddie,

I cannot speak for that particular model, but the 731SP uses 5v so basically any USB charger will do.</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="fake_raindrops_macro_photography">
    <comment>
      <name>Robert</name>
      <datetime>2011-04-07 17:32</datetime>
      <website>http://www.snapp.de</website>
      <message>Good stuff, where's the Like button?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-04-07 19:11</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks! And to answer your question: nowhere - yet. Facebook integration should be a piece of cake though, maybe I'll have a look at it this weekend or so.</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="getting_linux_on_that_dingoo">
    <comment>
      <name>Erik F.</name>
      <datetime>2011-04-12 13:10</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Nice article and great site!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-04-12 19:52</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks! And nice name, by the way. ;)</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="the_social_network">
    <comment>
      <name>Robert</name>
      <datetime>2011-04-26 10:48</datetime>
      <website>http://www.snapp.de</website>
      <message>I really liked the movie, so you won't get a like this time ;-)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-04-26 22:30</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>There are other options as well. If you don't Like it - Tweet it!</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="vignetting_with_the_gimp">
    <comment>
      <name>Marky T</name>
      <datetime>2011-05-05 13:51</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Excellent way to make a subtle effect. Just what I was looking for so thanks for the info.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-05-07 13:13</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Glad to be of help. :)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>G</name>
      <datetime>2012-08-27 07:37</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>This is too easy, thanks for sharing.  Method 2 is surely my favourite.</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="diy_dslr_camera_sling_strap">
    <comment>
      <name>Henrik</name>
      <datetime>2011-05-15 21:53</datetime>
      <website>http://henrikpettersson.blogg.se</website>
      <message>I was close to buy a Blackrapid RS-4 for the hideous price of 700 SEK. Until a found that my the bag to my new lens came with a basic sling strap. Everyone should have a sling strap, because it&#xB4;s just better! &#xD;
Get an extra strap and fasten to your tripod aswell. It isn&#xB4;t perfect but it makes life a bit easier.&#xD;
Great article btw.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-05-17 22:12</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Good idea about a tripod strap. I like my tripod, it was definitely a big upgrade from the el cheapo I had before. But the better they are, the bigger and heavier they get (mostly). Next DIY project, maybe?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Benjamin</name>
      <datetime>2012-05-10 17:21</datetime>
      <website>http://www.idea27.net</website>
      <message>Hey dude this article is great.&#xD;
&#xD;
Something I wanted to add, I have a nikon d700 and I think all nikon's have on their sides triangular "keychains" placed to attach your strap. I managed to place my hook directly on it, eliminating the need for the tripod base.&#xD;
&#xD;
Keep up the good work&#xD;
Ben</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-05-10 19:38</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Benjamin,&#xD;
&#xD;
why, thank you. :) And yeah, that makes things easier. Just don't let it fall, it's a great body!</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="dingoo_a320_-_first_impressions">
    <comment>
      <name>Sebastian</name>
      <datetime>2011-07-12 22:08</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Yeah I just ordered one last night I got it black because the wite ones where expensive</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-07-13 22:07</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Kinda the same here, they had no white ones in stock where I got it. On the other hand, I like black devices better than white ones. Makes one stand out from the Apple crowd. ;)</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="photo_gift_tips_3_items_for_100_eur_each">
    <comment>
      <name>Robert</name>
      <datetime>2011-11-14 10:24</datetime>
      <website>http://www.snapp.de</website>
      <message>Ok, nice stuff. But where can I get it?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-11-14 19:38</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I often get my stuff from Amazon. It may cost a bit more, but they are reliable and usually deliver fast. Check the links above.&#xD;
&#xD;
Seems like they don't have the Nissin SpeedLite Di622 Mark I anymore though. You will need to pay up a bit to get the Mark II, but the new features should be worth it.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Robert</name>
      <datetime>2011-11-16 14:30</datetime>
      <website>http://www.snapp.de</website>
      <message>Cool, just ordered the lens. Wasn't able to use your link, though. They don't ship to Germany...</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-11-16 20:49</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Aw, that's too bad. But anyway, great choice buddy! Have fun with the lens. :)</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="photo_sunday_illusion">
    <comment>
      <name>quimby</name>
      <datetime>2012-03-04 18:26</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I think that this is really awesome.&#xD;
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-03-05 18:57</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thank you quimby! :)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>karina</name>
      <datetime>2012-06-23 22:27</datetime>
      <website>http://vk.com</website>
      <message>how to do that??&#xD;
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-06-24 01:22</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Karina,&#xD;
&#xD;
it's quite simple actually - for folding instructions, just follow the link:&#xD;
&#xD;
http://www.coolopticalillusions.com/illusions/coolprinttriangle.pdf&#xD;
&#xD;
I found using a fairly a long lens (&gt;100mm) helps "flatten" the look of the triangle. Getting the right angle is critical. Put the triangle on the floor or on a table and walk around it to find the right spot. Mount the camera on a tripod there. The tripod helps, since you can make small adjustments to the angle and composition without having to start over every time. Hand-holding gets very tiresome. Keep shooting and adjusting until you get it right.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>mohsin</name>
      <datetime>2012-09-11 18:42</datetime>
      <website>http://grafixyard.com</website>
      <message>well done </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>lola</name>
      <datetime>2013-03-17 03:20</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>so easy to do but hard to see !!!</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="sweet_dreams">
    <comment>
      <name>Henrik</name>
      <datetime>2012-03-14 22:29</datetime>
      <website>http://www.henrikpettersson.nu</website>
      <message>Grymt kreativt och inte minst snyggt. Saknar fotos&#xF6;ndag en del. Jag vet, jag ligger p&#xE5; latsidan. Eller ja, tiden g&#xE5;r &#xE5;t till annat om man ska skylla p&#xE5; n&#xE5;got. Bra jobbat iaf!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-03-15 22:39</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Tackar tackar! Jo, jag f&#xF6;rst&#xE5;r att du har en del annat att g&#xF6;ra. Men att ta kort &#xE4;r skoj, gl&#xF6;m inte det! Fotar vatten nu i min hemmastudio byggd av en stol och ett bord. Handduken &#xE4;r n&#xE4;ra till hands. ;)</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="gemei_g9_android_tablet_hands-on">
    <comment>
      <name>MrTasselhof</name>
      <datetime>2012-04-10 04:43</datetime>
      <website>http://www.youtube.com/user/mrtasselhof?feature=mhee</website>
      <message>Decent run down of the device.  Sorry to hear you have had some of those build quality type issues, but glad to hear it is workable for you.  In regards to your article here are some things that may you or your readers out.&#xD;
1) Head on over to SlateDroid.com Forums.&#xD;
 - You will find plenty of threads and support for the Gemei G9 in it's own section&#xD;
2) Download the ICS firmware posted there and install it&#xD;
3) Run the "SuperScript" and you can open up the market and compatibility along with rooting and tweaking.&#xD;
&#xD;
In regards to Skype, there is a fully working previous version 2.5.x.x posted in a separate thread that you can download and install to have working video both ways.&#xD;
&#xD;
The battery life on the device is already great, but can be made even better by downloading SetCPU and following the settings guide thread in the Benchmark section of SlateDroid.&#xD;
&#xD;
Keep up the good work!&#xD;
&#xD;
Tasselhof</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-04-11 19:11</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks for the feedback! I will try out what you suggested; I might post another article about it later on how it went.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Spaceman</name>
      <datetime>2012-08-15 09:50</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Erik,&#xD;
I have tried getting the HDMI connection to work also but I also get nothing (please post something if you have any update to why).</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-08-16 20:30</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Spaceman,&#xD;
guess I'm not the only one then. ;) I'll post info here if I get it to work.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Jon</name>
      <datetime>2012-10-12 18:45</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Have you heard of the GemeiG9T?... you should probably do a review on that!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-10-12 18:50</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Jon,&#xD;
&#xD;
thanks for the info. Since my G9 is faulty (broken buttons), I will try to have it replaced or repaired. Maybe I could pay a little extra to get the G9T? Will have a look next time I'm in Hong Kong.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-12-18 20:14</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Just a quick update - they let me change the G9 in Hong Kong for a new one. The buttons now work, and the built-in browser is much more stable. :)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Shana</name>
      <datetime>2013-05-22 06:41</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I recently bought the Gemei small tablet G3A in china for about $70 Australian and am happy with it- use the small SD card to play movies and the wifi works good enough- charging it now but don't know how good battery life is. </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-05-22 23:30</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Shana: Sound good, have fun! :)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>rama</name>
      <datetime>2015-01-14 15:13</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I just bought it ana I am very happy </message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="canon_eos_600d_vs_1000d">
    <comment>
      <name>Alix</name>
      <datetime>2012-08-30 23:02</datetime>
      <website>http://https://www.facebook.com/hufaholder</website>
      <message>Awesome comparison between the Canon EOS 600D and 1000D! I just wanted to leave a quick comment to let you know about our awesome gadget for photographers of every level. :) The Hufa Holder lens cap clip was designed by photographers after they had, like many other photographers do, lost a TON of lens caps. The nifty little device just clips right on your strap and keeps your cap in place while you're shooting! Turns out, we lose a whole lot less lens caps this way! :) This also works no matter what camera you are using. Here is a video for you to check it out http://bit.ly/Nu7FPx. Thanks again for sharing your Canon EOS comparison! Hope you'll check out our gadget when you get a chance.&#xD;
&#xD;
Have a great day,&#xD;
Alix&#x2028;&#xD;
www.facebook.com/HufaHolder&#xD;
www.hufaholder.com</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-09-01 19:22</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Alix&#x2028;,&#xD;
&#xD;
I usually don't tolerate advertising disguised as comments, but the item seems fairly nifty so I'll let it slip. However, I have been using my DSLR for over three years and I have never lost a lens cap.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Simran</name>
      <datetime>2013-10-29 10:43</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks for sharing this review. This has helped me a lot. I have a 1000d and was thinking of upgrading the body, but have decided to stay put with 1000d since I shoot only using optical viewfinder and the center focus point, and usually in daylight. At night I use the 50mm 1.8 so I don't need to use a higher ISO. I will spend the money on a wide angle lens instead and work on my composition skills.

I think the only thing that would have really helped me is Spot Metering, and a faster shutter speed - but I will try to make do with the Partial Metering for now.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Thor </name>
      <datetime>2014-12-27 21:48</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Those who are Comparing Canon 1000D with 600D take a shower bro !! 600D Considered as so many professional's choice, where 1000D is almost OUTDATED basic DSLR(Aug 2008). I have used both of em several times. You don't have to argue with me, there is so many Experts Review as well as Users review available on thousand of websites across the INTERNET not for COMPARE THOSE , I am talking about the Advantages of 600D over 100D . Blindly anyone can Upgrade from 1000D to 600D. Beside being a Nikon user I cannot stop myself to write these words after reading this stuff. Though its for those who have time can read below-

The Canon EOS 600D is a logical, if not strictly necessary, update of the 550D. It's not a camera that'll go down in history but it's a decent SLR that takes good pictures and has plenty of settings. With EF-S 55-250mm the toy works like a charm , Buttery smooth with Crisp Results more than Any Beginner's expectation.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2014-12-27 23:48</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Thor,

Thank you for the input. I agree that the 600D is definitely the better camera and I'm still quite happy with it myself. But I just noticed this article is two years old, and by now, both cameras feel rather dated! I might consider an upgrade soon. ;)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Tutu</name>
      <datetime>2015-01-08 19:04</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Erik, your review is excellent. I have read at several times but could not reach the conclusion. I own a 1000D. Happy with it. Want to upgrade to 600D. Brain says 'Yes' but Heart says 'No'. What should I do? </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2015-01-08 20:58</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Tutu,

just follow you heart! Or toss a coin. ;)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Tutu</name>
      <datetime>2015-03-27 18:34</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Erik, Help me once more. Still I'm in love very much with my 1000D. Will with be with this for another couple  of Years. I'm using a Canon Zoom Lens EF-S 18-55 mm (1:3.5-5.6 II NON-IS) and a Canon Zoom Lens EFS 55-250 mm (1:4-5.6 IS II). Both the lenses are good. But they create a problem in emergency when  lens change is required. I plan to change them with a Tamron AF 18-200mm F/3.5-6.3 XR Di II LD Aspherical [IF] MACRO? Is my decision correct? I'm normally a General Clicker. Love to click everything.
 </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2015-03-27 20:51</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Tutu,

I have a similar lens myself, a Tamron 18-270. I wrote a little review here:

http://www.erikmoberg.net/article/new_lens_-_tamron_18-270_3.5-6.3_di_ii_vc

What it lacks in optical quality, it makes up in flexibility. So when I know what will be shooting, I usually pick another lens. But when I don't, i take this one and it makes sure I always get the shot.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Tutu</name>
      <datetime>2015-03-28 06:55</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks a lot, Eric :-)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Tutu</name>
      <datetime>2015-03-28 07:00</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Dear Eric, Just let me know
1) Whether the quality of Tamron AF 18-200mm F/3.5-6.3 XR Di II LD Aspherical [IF] MACRO is better than the Canon Zoom Lens EF-S 18-55 mm (1:3.5-5.6 II NON-IS) or not?
2) Is Tamron AF 18-200mm F/3.5-6.3 XR Di II LD Aspherical [IF] MACRO is better than Canon Zoom Lens EFS 55-250 mm (1:4-5.6 IS II)?   </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2015-03-29 00:27</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Tutu,

to both questions, at least from what I can gather from the reviews, the answer would be "about the same". The image quality of the Tamron is good, but hardly spectacular, and comes in a convenient package. The price point is also good. However, the lack of an optical stabilizer might be a problem at longer focal lengths, unless you are using a tripod. Your 55-250 has IS, try shooting with it switched off to find out.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Tutu</name>
      <datetime>2015-03-29 06:28</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks a lot Eric. It seems that I will need your constant support as far as suggestions in optics is concerned. May I have your email id please?</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="shiny_icon_maker_-_more_new_features">
    <comment>
      <name>Jon</name>
      <datetime>2012-10-12 18:42</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I love this.. it is really cool. </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-10-12 18:46</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks Jon. :)</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="canon_50mm_1.8_stuck_on_camera_body">
    <comment>
      <name>Suliman</name>
      <datetime>2012-10-29 20:24</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I just had the same problem in my canon 550D. My 50mm 1.8 II fell on the ground. I did not check it after that and inserted it into the camera. The lens stuck in the camera. After few attempts I forced the lens and end up with the same result you show on the picture. Happy that my camera is woking perfectly without a problem.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-11-11 20:47</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Suliman,&#xD;
&#xD;
sorry to hear you had the same problem, but happy you solved it without any nasty side effects! I noticed that my camera has started to sporadically have problems communicating with some lenses afterwards - seems like the pins inside the mount took a beating. :(</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="installing_android_2.3_gingerbread_on_sonyericsson_xperia_x10_mini_pro">
    <comment>
      <name>power ranger</name>
      <datetime>2012-12-18 14:10</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>is there any safer way?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-12-18 20:11</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi power ranger,&#xD;
&#xD;
let me put it this way: If you feel worried about doing this, don't do it! It's unsupported and will void your warranty. The main reason I did this was because my phone felt old. If a new version of Android could breathe new life into it, great - if only for a few months. And if I would brick it, I would just be looking forward for a new Christmas gift for myself.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Pelle</name>
      <datetime>2012-12-20 17:11</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hej Erik!&#xD;
In English:&#xD;
I rooted my phone, using SuperOneClick. Downloaded xRecovery installer from "Google Play", ran it, get the same look as on the guide you linked to. However when I click to install, only thing that happens is that the three little icons turn into crossed red rings. Do I have to do something before this step?&#xD;
Thanks</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-12-20 20:24</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Pelle,&#xD;
&#xD;
I did not point this out in my guide, but the AddictiveTips page I link to states that BusyBox need to be preinstalled. This might be you problem. Check out this thread:&#xD;
&#xD;
http://androidforums.com/sony-ericsson-xperia-x10/265818-having-trouble-installing-xrecovery.html&#xD;
&#xD;
I will update this article to point that out.&#xD;
&#xD;
Good luck!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Simon </name>
      <datetime>2012-12-21 07:26</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hey Erik&#xD;
&#xD;
This is a great guide, thanks for this. I am from Denmark, but will write in English for the sake of the wide world. Pelle says that when installing xRecovery he gets just red rings. As far as I understand from the comments on xRecovery, this is because read/write permission is needed on the rooted device, and not because of a lack of Busybox. I will continue to play with it:-)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Pelle</name>
      <datetime>2012-12-21 10:39</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hej Erik,&#xD;
I did have Busybox. What I did was instead to download a Root Manager Lite and put the files directly into /system/bin instead of using the failing installer. It worked fine! Simon you can try it!&#xD;
&#xD;
Now I am on MiniCM7Pro V21 of CM for 2.3.7. It's like a fresh phone! Why did you opt to use another mod, Erik?&#xD;
&#xD;
My Swedish (physical) keyboard is mismatching BTW. Did you solve that?&#xD;
&#xD;
Tack&#xD;
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Pelle</name>
      <datetime>2012-12-21 14:45</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>More: I tried the app Mini ROM Manager and changed HW Keyboard layout to qwerty-se-fi, according to some tips, but it still didn't work, no &#xE5;&#xE4;&#xF6; etc. Rebooted, the setting is kept, but keyboard is still wrong. Just to add to the above...</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-12-21 22:05</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>@Simon: Have fun!&#xD;
&#xD;
@Pelle: Should work. The only thing I can think of is that under "Language &amp; Keyboard" in the settings, the keyboard should be set to "Default input". Hope this helps.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Simon</name>
      <datetime>2012-12-22 08:34</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hey again, &#xD;
thanks for the tips on this site. After spending quite a long time on this, I finally got another mod to work but only to find out that it did not fix the thing where my touchscreen stops working when I use the keyboard. That means I will have to buy some Galaxy now:-)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-12-24 11:00</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Simon,&#xD;
&#xD;
thanks! :) Just a matter of time until I replace it myself. Currently leaning towards the Huawei Ascend P1.&#xD;
&#xD;
Merry Christmas!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>tanvay</name>
      <datetime>2013-01-11 23:32</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hey,&#xD;
@Pelle: have you used this mod (MiniCM7Pro V21 of CM for 2.3.7. ) for x10 mini pro ?&#xD;
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>rob7000</name>
      <datetime>2013-01-23 21:12</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi, I have to access the Service menu but the numer  *#*#7378423#*#* doesn't work anymore ! probably because the file ServiceMenu.apk is not installed with this ROM... I have problems with my internal speaker and I have to go on this secret menu to try fixing it. I found a file ServiceMenu.apk  2.3.3 but my phone tels me "App not installed" , my phone is rooted..</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>shimanto</name>
      <datetime>2013-02-15 18:13</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>hey Erik,&#xD;
thanks for your help and advise. i'm from bangladesh. i've sony ericsson x10 (not mini). i want to upgrade android 2.3. how can i do that . will you help me to do that  </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-02-15 23:05</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi shimanto,&#xD;
&#xD;
I cannot help you directly with that, but do take a look at these SonyEricsson X10 forum sections at CyanogenMod and XDA Developers:&#xD;
&#xD;
http://forum.cyanogenmod.org/forum/438-sony-ericsson-xperia-x10/&#xD;
http://forum.xda-developers.com/forumdisplay.php?f=614&#xD;
&#xD;
They should provide all information you need. Have fun!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Zombodii</name>
      <datetime>2013-02-24 06:35</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I WANT TO DO IT. DO I USE CYANOGEN?????</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Bikash Thada Magar</name>
      <datetime>2013-03-03 08:25</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hey friends i have also Xperia X10 mini pro and i tried to download the application "Busybox" and "xRecovery" but i can't so please friends if possible please help me by sending this two file in my email id my mailing id is (removed by admin)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-03-03 15:33</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Bikash Thada Magar,&#xD;
&#xD;
I removed your email address to protect you from spammers. The links to both applications can be found in the article and they work for me; I would suggest you simply try it again. If you have any problems downloading or installing, just post back here, including any error messages.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Deepan</name>
      <datetime>2013-03-04 04:44</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>After update gingerbread 2.3.7, but I did all I see an animation of andoid logo like in clouds and flashes,freeze my screen.&#xD;
restart my phone xrecovery menus can not come why, please help&#xD;
&#xD;
What can I do ?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Deepan</name>
      <datetime>2013-03-04 04:54</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>After update sony ericsson x10 mini to gingerbread 2.3.7,then anroid logo comes in flashing lights.Than the android logo stops flashing and freezes. And nothing happens than  next move. I waited (12 hours) so long but still the same. How much should i wait for that logo screen to boot up my phone&#xD;
&#xD;
please help</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Deepan</name>
      <datetime>2013-03-04 09:24</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hello erik my phone still now android logo stops flashing and freeze &#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
pls help me...........</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-03-04 20:57</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Deepan,&#xD;
&#xD;
that doesn't sound good at all! The update process should only take a few minutes. If all else fails, you could try to restore the original firmware. Here is a very short video on how to do that:&#xD;
&#xD;
http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zS2LIuy6YfY&#xD;
&#xD;
I can confirm that this works; I just did it five minutes ago. The basic steps are:&#xD;
&#xD;
1. Install and launch PC Companion&#xD;
2. Select to update the phone software&#xD;
3. Click to start, and when it complains it cannot find the phone, select "repair phone"&#xD;
4. Confirm that all data will be deleted and that you're OK with that&#xD;
5. (Not in the video) I was asked to switch off the phone, and connect it to the PC while holding the back button.&#xD;
&#xD;
After a few minutes, the update is complete. Start the phone and you're back with stock 2.1.&#xD;
&#xD;
Hope this helps.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>viswa</name>
      <datetime>2013-03-05 09:52</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>can any body tell where can i get the firm ware of 2.3.7 for my xperia x 10 mini pro</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>deepan</name>
      <datetime>2013-03-06 07:11</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>thanks erik................</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Joao</name>
      <datetime>2013-03-06 14:31</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Can you download the rom - http://forum.xda-developers.com/showthread.php?t=1291845&#xD;
&#xD;
And put in another link?&#xD;
I want to use your version, but I can't download it. Multiupload blocks my country.&#xD;
&#xD;
Please, give me a help :)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-03-06 18:56</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Joao,&#xD;
&#xD;
the link seems to be dead. In the xda-developers thread, someone added a new link which you could try:&#xD;
&#xD;
http://forum.xda-developers.com/showthread.php?t=1291845&amp;page=80&#xD;
&#xD;
Otherwise, maybe you could contact the person who started the thread and ask for an update of the links in the first post.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Stoneman</name>
      <datetime>2013-03-07 07:03</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>gingerbread 2.3.7 to 4.0 ics after update "sony ericsson" white text logo freeze in one day and many more time switch off my mobile but automatically restart mobile and then freeze it&#xD;
 &#xD;
pls help me .......  </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Stoneman</name>
      <datetime>2013-03-07 08:42</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hello erik,&#xD;
&#xD;
pls help me</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>stoneman</name>
      <datetime>2013-03-07 09:22</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hello erik please help me&#xD;
&#xD;
this problem continue for more then one day&#xD;
&#xD;
after update 4.0 "sony ericsson" white&#xFEFF; text logo freeze in one day and many more time switch off my mobile but automatically restart mobile and then freeze it&#xD;
&#xD;
how can i solve this problem?&#xD;
&#xD;
what i do ?&#xD;
&#xD;
pls help me</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-03-07 19:38</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Stoneman,&#xD;
&#xD;
this article is about upgrading to 2.3 Gingerbread, not 4.0 Ice Cream Sandwich. ICS is not likely to work on this device. Try flashing with the original firmware to set things right again:&#xD;
&#xD;
http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zS2LIuy6YfY&#xD;
&#xD;
However, if you are using another device than the X10 Mini Pro and the ICS firmware is official, contact Sony support instead. &#xD;
&#xD;
Good luck!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>stoneman</name>
      <datetime>2013-03-08 04:28</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>"sony ericsson" white&#xFEFF; text logo freeze its dont to go next step.&#xD;
then how to connect my phone to sony ericsson pc campaign &#xD;
&#xD;
please help me</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>stoneman</name>
      <datetime>2013-03-08 08:02</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>phone wont connect to pc campaign please help me erik......&#xD;
&#xD;
off/on button not working while (power + home button press) restart mobile but freeze it&#xD;
&#xD;
cont take any movement &#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
please help............&#xD;
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-03-08 15:42</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi again Stoneman,&#xD;
&#xD;
if the phone is frozen and cannot be switched off using the power button, just take out the battery. After putting it back in, wait a while to make sure the phone doesn't turn itself back on automatically. You might have to give it a minute after taking the battery out or try a few times. After making sure the phone is off, you can hold the back button and connect it to the PC while PC Companion is waiting.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Joao</name>
      <datetime>2013-03-11 00:56</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hello Erik, I'm having another problem,&#xD;
&#xD;
I put a 2.3.7 rom in my xperia x10 mini pro, and i'm having a little problem sending large text to my gf. I only can send few words in a message.&#xD;
If I send a very large message, the messages doens't send. &#xD;
I try to look on the internet about this problem, but i just found nothing. &#xD;
&#xD;
Can you help pls?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Mr.Bheem</name>
      <datetime>2013-03-11 16:03</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>After update gingerbread successfully.&#xD;
&#xD;
But battery backup very poor (only 2 hours).....&#xD;
&#xD;
How to improve my battery backup&#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
please help.......</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-03-11 18:46</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Joao,&#xD;
&#xD;
it could be a problem with SMS splitting:&#xD;
&#xD;
http://forum.cyanogenmod.org/topic/22587-cant-send-long-text-messages/&#xD;
&#xD;
OR a problem with message center number:&#xD;
&#xD;
http://forum.xda-developers.com/showthread.php?t=1253013&#xD;
&#xD;
It might also be a problem with your carrier. Try sending/receiving from someone with a different carrier.&#xD;
&#xD;
If you cannot find a solution... install WhatsApp! ;)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-03-11 18:47</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Mr.Bheem,&#xD;
&#xD;
there could be several reasons. After a quick Google, here are some things people have tried, some of which may work:&#xD;
&#xD;
 - Turning off and turning on the phone&#xD;
 - Install and run the JuiceDefender app&#xD;
 - Factory reset the phone&#xD;
 - Let the phone drain the battery until it switches off itself, then recharge the phone to 100%, then switch it on&#xD;
&#xD;
See if any of these work for you. Otherwise, Google is your friend.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Joao</name>
      <datetime>2013-03-13 00:16</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Just for curiosity, how many hours you battery can handle?&#xD;
&#xD;
In the morning i have 100% battery, and 5/6 hours later I just have 5%&#xD;
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-03-13 23:52</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Joao,&#xD;
&#xD;
that sounds low. The capacity of the battery in this phone is, however, rather weak. In stand by with GSM only, I get maybe 48 hours. If I actually use the phone - calling, surfing, listening to music - then it might last just about a day. So it depends mainly on what you use it for and what apps you have running.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Yan</name>
      <datetime>2013-03-23 05:49</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Erik, can you please tell me the name of the android 2.3.7 distro that used to tale the screenshots in this article? Thanks in advance.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-03-23 11:42</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Yan,&#xD;
&#xD;
it's called "Flame.GDX ICS v1.0" and is based on CyanogeMod 7.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>saad</name>
      <datetime>2013-03-23 19:58</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>hi sir, actually i'm not sure what to do and as well as how to do this... i want to change the os of my x10 mini pro via my laptop for this i need a flashtool and i already have it, and then i downloaded the CM 7, and now when i was going to download the rom's and kernel there it was MINI CM? now what the hell that is?? i mean i already downloaded one os for my mob( 83 mb ) nd that minicm i 138 mb? now what??? i dont know that where to put all those files please help me. thanks...... </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-03-24 13:57</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi saad,&#xD;
&#xD;
from their website: "MiniCM is a custom-built ROM for the X10 Mini / X10 Mini Pro / X8 based on CyanogenMod."&#xD;
&#xD;
So with this ROM, you should be able to run Gingerbread, ICS or JB on the X10 Mini Pro. To find out more, go to their website:&#xD;
&#xD;
http://minicm.dyndns.org/site/&#xD;
&#xD;
Check out the information under the menu: Information =&gt; MiniCM[version] =&gt; mimmi</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Ester</name>
      <datetime>2013-03-30 08:21</datetime>
      <website>http://eekhaba@gmil.com</website>
      <message>Hi sir how can I download whatssap</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-03-31 14:02</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Ester,

it may not be relevant to this thread, but just open Google Play on your phone and search for WhatsApp.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Avro</name>
      <datetime>2013-04-23 15:02</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hey bro!!ater updating my sd caard is not working!!!now what to do?? :'(</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-04-23 21:23</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Avro,

I would like to help, but need some more details on what actually doesn't work. Is the phone not booting, or is it unable to read the SD card?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Avro</name>
      <datetime>2013-04-24 07:52</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>It is unable to read the sd card!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-04-25 21:02</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi again Avro,

I don't know if this issue applies to the X10 mini pro, but seems to be relatively common with the "regular" X10. Basically, you can try:
 - Formatting the SD card using a PC or another phone
 - Trying/buying another SD card
Check this thread over at SonyMobile (reply #21):

http://talk.sonymobile.com/thread/21406?start=20&amp;tstart=0

If this is an official update from SonyEricsson (not CyanogenMod), you might get support from them directly. Hope things work out!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>kiba</name>
      <datetime>2013-04-25 22:15</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>sorry please where can i download function busybox and xrecovery
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Dave</name>
      <datetime>2013-04-27 15:06</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Erik, all the root programs like superoneclick has virus!! OR? My anti virus program blocked it from download</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-04-27 18:41</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>@kiba: Check out the paragraphs "3. Installing BusyBox" and "4. Installing xRecovery" above.

@Dave: The applications are hosted by other providers so I cannot control whether they contain malware. I should point out though, that some antivirus programs report hacking tools as viruses, even though they are harmless (provided the users know what they are doing). On the SuperOneClick download page, there is a comment thread - check out the comments and consider asking if anyone else has the problem.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Tommhani</name>
      <datetime>2013-04-29 22:42</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Does the same steps will work with X10i ?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Md jobayer</name>
      <datetime>2013-05-20 07:34</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Erik
i am facing a problem that in my x10 mini pro, bluetooth connection is truning on and off automatically. i cannot use my bluetooth .please help me. firmwire version is 2.1   </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-05-21 23:20</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>@Tommhani: Probably not. The procedure would be similar, but the firmware is most likely not the same. Check out the XDA Developer forums and see if you can find anything there.

@Md jobayer: Thank your for your post. However, it is difficult to tell what the problem might be. Maybe try upgrading to 2.3 using the instructions on this page? Could be worth a shot.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>nhel</name>
      <datetime>2013-05-26 15:24</datetime>
      <website>http://facebook.com</website>
      <message>hi erik,,nothing happens when i press the back button continously..</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-06-13 18:59</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi nhel,

did you press it repeatedly or did you keep the button pressed? The latter should work.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>jerome</name>
      <datetime>2013-06-14 02:44</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>hi erik.. i also have x10mini pro.. i have all the requirements that i can use for the gingerbread update but i dont know how to do it.. i already rooted my device and downloads all the files that is needed to upgrade.. i have.. xrecovery, MiniCM7Pro_V21 of CM for 2.3.7, and the root explorer.. what is the next step?

please help..


i just watch a video the final steps there is to turn off the device and turn on
when the device vibrated he said keep pressing the back space but it didn't work</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Pawan</name>
      <datetime>2013-06-14 12:41</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message> XPERIA X10 MINI . . . . . during the installation of xRecovery software i receive three error messages that system\bin\chargemon file exist . . . and same error messages for busybox and xrecovery . . . . i also tried to manually copy those three files to system\bin and i did so . . . . but during boot there is no dialogue box from xrecovery . . . . i tried it for more than twenty times but its not working . . . .</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Pawan</name>
      <datetime>2013-06-14 12:46</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>i tried in both way by pressing the back button repeatedly and holding it , but it still didn't work . . . no dialogue box from Xrecovery  . . .
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-06-14 19:12</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>@jerome &amp; Pawan: Difficult to figure out what's wrong. Maybe some other tutorial has more details? Google is hopefully your friend: http://bit.ly/1bE61Fq</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>sargam</name>
      <datetime>2013-06-16 08:22</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>hi erik sir i want to upgrade my x10 mini pro bt when i upgrade bt 2.1 into 2.3 the pc companion only show 2.1
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-06-16 13:44</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi sargam,

PC Companion cannot be used upgrade the device to 2.3. Please use the guide in this article instead.

To check the currently installed version, use the phone and go to Settings and select About Phone (refer to screenshot above).</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>vincent</name>
      <datetime>2013-06-24 00:16</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>My phone cant accept my google account, even when im connected with wi-fi. What should i do

please help!!!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-06-25 00:02</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Vincent,

had this problem as well with some custom rom (can't remember which), but I did not really try to solve it, instead just installed another rom and that worked.

A guess: Maybe the layout of the keyboard changed in the software so that it does not correspond to the physical keyboard? This could be a problem eg. if you have a German phone and the layout changes to English - the Y and Z keys will then be swapped.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Gseli</name>
      <datetime>2013-06-25 09:55</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Can it work at sony x10 mini (no pro)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Gseli</name>
      <datetime>2013-06-25 11:41</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I have sony x10 mini.i haven't install android 2.3.7 but i don't know if it is possible to install it at my phone.can you answer me erik please.(my english may be not so good becouse i am greek)
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>kiran tanka</name>
      <datetime>2013-06-25 13:49</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Erik, at first I will say thanks to you for giving a good article. Erik I have got some stuff like this from other sites, but ur explains are good among the others. actually what I need, is it supports to my SE Xperia X10 mini? coz, your guide is on fully supported to X10 mini pro. and onemore thing is ... I was partitioned my memory card into two (FAT32 and ex2) to support Link2SD app. The partitions are 3GB,1GB respectively. the question is .. in which partition I have to installed the update file? after updating the os, the ex2 partition part is visible in device ?give me the step by step guide...</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-06-25 22:23</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Gseli, hi kiran tanka,

thank you for the feedback! About compatibility with the non-pro, I would recommend you use a rom specifically for that version. You can look at the cyanogenmod for xperia mini:

http://forum.cyanogenmod.com/topic/32772-cyanogenmod-7-for-the-xperia-mini-v7102-24-oct-2011/

There is also a whole forum section dedicated to the device at XDA Developers, where you can find more info and custom roms:

http://forum.xda-developers.com/forumdisplay.php?f=726

It could also be a good place to sort out the question regarding where to install it when the SD card is partitioned, because I'm afraid I don't know the answer myself.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Power Arc</name>
      <datetime>2013-07-24 01:57</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Eric
Can U please do a video of this??so that it would be helpful for the users who wanna do this stuff </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Power Arc</name>
      <datetime>2013-07-24 03:15</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Erik
Also if I only Root (Not installing Custom ROM) my Xperia x10 mini pro what features can I get??</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-07-24 09:02</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Power Arc,

I'll consider making a video - but don't get your hopes up! I picked up the Nexus 4 recently and I now find it difficult to go back to the X10 Mini Pro. ;)

About benefits of rooting: Some applications require rooting to work - like file explorers that let you access more of the file system, powerful backup tools, or hardware tweaking tools. Titanium backup os one example, Root explorer another.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Power Arc</name>
      <datetime>2013-07-25 06:15</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Eric

Man please try to make a video of that in your free time...

And When it comes to only ROOTING, can we get APP2SD feature after rooting and expansion of internal memory coz got rid of this low internal memory....:( Running 2.1 compared to present world of Android Power makes  me SAD so </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Power Arc</name>
      <datetime>2013-07-26 10:10</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Pell

I need ur assistance in installing MiniCM7Pro V21 of CM for 2.3.7

I read that it seems stable ROM

I need your help
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>tarun sharma</name>
      <datetime>2013-08-07 14:45</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>hiii erig, i don't understand how to do it please tell me in detail please.....!!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-08-07 22:31</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Power Arc, hi tarun sharma,

the guide should provide all the information needed to perform the upgrade. If you feel that anything is unclear or that some steps are missing, please tell and I will try to help. The more specific, the better.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>tarun sharma</name>
      <datetime>2013-08-10 18:32</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>hiii erig,i have download all requirements but how to install in mobile i have try many times but i don't do it please tell mee.......pleaseeeeeee
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>tarun sharma</name>
      <datetime>2013-08-11 12:37</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>hiii erig, i have root the device but how to to install xrecovery.update.and update to 2.3.... pleaseeee tell meeee
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>tarun sharma</name>
      <datetime>2013-08-11 13:02</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>hiii erig,i have download xrecovery but install in phone phone showing there is parse problem how to solve it</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-08-11 19:50</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi tarun sharma,

a parse problem may indicate a bad download or incompatible phone. Make sure your phone is compatible and download the package again.

Also have a look in the XDA Developers xRecovery thread, this could be a good place to search for answers:

http://forum.xda-developers.com/showthread.php?t=859571</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>ujjwal silwal</name>
      <datetime>2013-08-15 18:47</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>i bricked my x10 mini pro. then i tried the youtube link u have shared on repairing my phone bt it told that my phone has already the latest version.
and i am not able to get my 2.1 back as it told i have already latest version.
please help</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-08-19 23:27</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi ujjwal silwal,

sorry to hear the phone is bricked. You might want to check this thread to see if it helps you:

http://forum.xda-developers.com/showthread.php?t=1268064</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>chris</name>
      <datetime>2013-09-11 22:25</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Great tutorial, except I can't get xRecovery to start. can you help me?
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>prior</name>
      <datetime>2013-09-12 16:31</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>hiii erig,  how to install x recovery, </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-09-14 11:14</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi chris, hi prior,

as described above, just follow these instructions:

http://www.addictivetips.com/mobile/how-to-install-latest-xrecovery-to-sony-ericsson-xperia-x10/

Make sure all prerequisites are met. Are you getting any error messages?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>philoz</name>
      <datetime>2013-09-29 17:39</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>hi Erik. Great guide of course. Thanks for that. I managed to upgrade my daughter's x10mini pro to recente Android version. The problem now is that she grew affectionated to Sony optimized  Active User interface. Do you know any way to install that launcher  or similar ? Thanks in advance for any help. </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>sayan</name>
      <datetime>2013-10-04 11:44</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>hi erik,i had updated my sony ericsson w8 2.1 eclairs to ginger dx 2.3.7 ginger bread......but can't go back to my oiginal 2.1 os...so i decided to move to ginger xperia....but after installing its only showing Sony ericsson and freezes the screen....no movement...
i opened my battery and tried it for more over than 20 times...
but nthng happens...all remain freeze at sony ericsson...
what to do??????
plz help me out of this.....plzzzz  ;(</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-10-08 23:34</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>@philoz: Thank you! You might want to check out a ROM with a similar look and feel as the original interface. Here is one (that I haven't tried, but it looks good):

http://forum.xda-developers.com/showthread.php?t=1151499

@sayan: You might be able to use PC Companion from SonyEricsson to unbrick the device. You can find brief instructions in a previous comment. Hope this helps!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Titto</name>
      <datetime>2013-10-29 08:52</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>hi Erik,

i rooted my xperia x10 mini pro,then installed busybox.But when try to install xRecovery, in its home screen "install xrecovery" button is showing.when clicked on it, nothing happening after that.pls help....</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>praveen</name>
      <datetime>2013-11-13 15:10</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>how to update the sony ericsson xperia x10 mini 2.1 to any other version

</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>vishal</name>
      <datetime>2014-01-08 20:11</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I'm getting this error when I try to install the update.zip from xrecovery
"error in update.zip status 7 installation aborted"</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Fareed</name>
      <datetime>2014-01-27 12:43</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi! Erik I`m sorry my english isn`t  gud enough.
what I nid u 2 help me is  tht, my xperia x10 mini pro deny 2 install sm apps 'This app could not be installed in this phone' plz help me</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>tmc</name>
      <datetime>2014-01-27 17:26</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>erik, fair play to you, you have some patience!!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2014-01-31 19:18</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi everyone,

Erik here. I just wanted to let you know that while you are still welcome to post new comments to this article, I probably won't be replying to them anymore. Reason is, since I got a new phone I have stopped using my X10. But thank you all for the feedback! :)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>ananth</name>
      <datetime>2014-02-25 08:47</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>i break my phone what can i do</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Anu</name>
      <datetime>2014-04-24 17:50</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Followed your instructions and installed 2.3. But the phone froze at bootup. Again following your instructions, installed 2.1.
What an experience! End of the I am where I started.. :D </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2014-05-05 08:25</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Any,

to bad the update didn't work, but sometimes just *not* bricking the device already feels like a victory. ;)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Sinisa</name>
      <datetime>2014-08-05 21:56</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I rooted my phone and everythink else but when i instal my new softvare and reboot my phone i see just a logo screen, what to do ?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Scelo</name>
      <datetime>2014-08-20 01:04</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I've wondering if such thing was possible, I can not bring up the system recovery I have tried like you said but it just doesnt work</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>oneil</name>
      <datetime>2014-10-08 15:42</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>this xperia x10 mini pro is so really suck. can anyone help me to up to date this phone to new android? I need help!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>martin</name>
      <datetime>2014-10-24 12:15</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>No commet</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Write my Essay Now UK</name>
      <datetime>2017-02-09 06:20</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Extraordinary guide obviously. I figured out how to overhaul my little girl's x 10 mini than expected genius to late Android adaptation. The issue now is that she became friendly to Sony advanced Active User interface. Do you know any approach to introduce that launcher or comparative? Much obliged ahead of time for any offer assistance.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Elmer Malubay</name>
      <datetime>2018-01-14 01:36</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>will you please help me secure this sony xperia x10 i am more than willing to pay exact amount for this</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="save-and-load-your-icons">
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-03-31 14:19</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Note: if you clear the local storage in the browser, the saved icons will disappear.</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="canon-ef-50mm-11-8-ii-vs-canon-ef-40mm-f-2.8-stm-which-to-get">
    <comment>
      <name>rich</name>
      <datetime>2013-04-23 06:07</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>thanks erik, it's been decided. im going to buy 40mm dis month. - rich</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-04-23 21:11</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Rich,

excellent choice! ;) Feel free to post back here after trying it out, I would really like to know what you think about it.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Maritza</name>
      <datetime>2013-04-30 15:33</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I've been searching like a mad women for a lens I can use to take Birth pictures for a friend. Not knowing the lighting situation i need a lens that is good in low light and that i can capture great fast pictures without having to walk out of the room or be on top of the mother... What do you think of the 40mm in this situation?
Thank you!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-04-30 22:47</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Maritza,

first of all: There is no such thing as a perfect lens - stop looking! ;)

That said, if you are on a crop sensor, the 40mm is a quite good choice. It should get you close enough for detail shots without you having to move too close, and it is still wide enough to capture both mother and child. Also, you will probably want to stay out of the way as much as possible, and you will not find a less intrusive lens than the pancake.

The not-so-fast 2.8 aperture may seem like a weak spot, but newborns tend to move very little so it should hopefully not be a problem.

By the way, check with the hospital in advance to make sure photography is not a problem. Also, some doctors are fine with flash use, which could come in handy.

Good luck!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Maritza</name>
      <datetime>2013-05-01 12:06</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I went ahead and ordered the 40mm... I'm exited to see what it can do.
Thank you so much for getting back to me Erik.

</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-05-01 16:23</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>That's great! I hope it lives up to your expectations. :)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Rita</name>
      <datetime>2013-05-02 14:55</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hey Erik!
I'm getting into newborn photography, specially at home (as i don't have a studio) and actually I've seen a tutorial that advice the use of a 50mm prime lens. But after reading this post I'm confused! Maybe it's just this specific 50mm that it's not very good as it's really cheap compared to other 50mm I've seen.
Do you think to get started I can use this 50mm or it's just a bad investment?
Is there any other lens that you advice for this kind of photography?
Thank you so much,

Rita</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-05-02 17:21</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Rita,

I would say it has a lot to do with personal preference, and what camera you have. I have seen people recommending everything from 28 mm to 85 mm for this purpose.

Personally, I find the 50 mm a bit too tight for many situations, especially indoors - but that is on a crop sensor camera, which makes it an 80 mm. This can be a good thing though if you prefer to stand further away from your subject. Try shooting at the long end of the kit lens to see if that focal length suits you, just to get a feel for it.

On a full frame however, the 50 mm focal length is quite versatile. Considering its price, the image quality is excellent. If you want to go professional, you might want to invest in something higher-grade though.

Hope this helps somewhat!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Rita</name>
      <datetime>2013-05-02 21:14</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Still don't know what to choose! :) Too many options, too little knowledge!! If I ask you which one would you recommend to start with? Of course I would love to go professional, but that's still far in the future i guess! And my camera it's a canon 600d... if that helps. And I've got the kit lens, and a tamron 18-200mm f/3.5-6.3 (if) macro.
Thank you so much for your help!
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-05-02 21:58</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I have the 600D myself, and while both lenses have good optics, I find the focal length of the 40 mm much more usable. This, combined with the compact format, makes it a great walkaround lens.

Still, the 50 mm is cheaper, and also faster. And the focal length is great for portraits, with its large aperture allowing for nicely blurred backgrounds.

The choice is yours. ;)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Rita</name>
      <datetime>2013-05-02 23:23</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thank you so much! :)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Joel</name>
      <datetime>2013-05-12 23:30</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hey Erik, I do a lot of night photography and automotive photography also is the 40mm lens as good without the bokeh because I usually like my backgrounds in focus with the cars. what do you think?

-T3i</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-05-13 23:05</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Joel,

well, that's basically three questions, so let's split it up:

1. Night photography: With an f/2.8 aperture and no optical image stabilizer, it's a bit slow for handheld night shots. Better bring a tripod.

2. Cars: If you mean car shows with a lot of people and little space, the 40 mm might prove a bit too tight. Some rough numbers: With the 40 mm, to shoot a 4 meter (13 ft) long object (small car), you will have to move back around 6 meters (20 ft). The kit lens at 18 mm needs only half the distance. The 40 mm makes a great lens for detail shots though.

3. Getting everything in focus: Sure, the 40 mm can do it. But a shorter lens can do it better. Anyway, you can experiment with the DOF calculator to see if 40 mm is the focal length for you:
http://dofmaster.com/dofjs.html

Hope this helps!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Joel</name>
      <datetime>2013-05-14 00:30</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thank you Erik for your the reply and yes this really does help me out! take care </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Huang</name>
      <datetime>2013-05-22 06:53</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>hi, kindly allow me to ask few questions :)
I own 600D as well and one of my lens is the 50mm f/1.8.
However, lately I rarely use 50mm because it can't focus quick and to myself, the result is not so crisp especially at f/1.8.

what is your opinion about 40mm for my issues above? can it replace my 50mm with way more accurate focus and sharp result?

thanks in advance
Huang</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>huang</name>
      <datetime>2013-05-22 07:17</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>sorry, I forgot to ask 1 more question.

I also have tamron 28-75 f/2.8, which also cover the focal length of canon 40mm. if you were me, do you think it's worth it to have them both?

once again, thanks.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-05-22 23:48</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Huang,

I never had any focusing issues with the 50 mm. The 40 mm does feel slightly faster though, and definitely more quiet. Not enough to warrant buying a new lens only for this reason in my opinion (unless you do sports photography or something). If sharpness is the bigger problem, simply try stopping down to 2.8. It should be sharp enough, and still as fast as the 40 mm. Give it a shot.

The Tamron is a nice lens and definitely more versatile focal length-wise than the 40 mm prime. Unless you feel the biggest problems are size and weight, just keep using it.

The interesting thing about primes is mostly that they force you to think differently  about how to get the shot - you cannot just lazily stand around and zoom. But whether this is good or not is up to you. ;)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Chris</name>
      <datetime>2013-06-13 08:01</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thank you Erik for your review.

If possible let me know your thoughts about portrait uses. Which one would you recommend, or how you would use both to optimize portraiting performance ?

Thanks

Chris (Canada) </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-06-13 23:51</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Chris,

on a crop body, the focal lengths of both lenses are good - many say around 80mm (35mm equivalent) lenses make the subject look their best.

The 50mm, with its slightly longer focal length and larger aperture, would be able to make the subject stand out more, since the background will be more blurred. Great for outdoor shots.

Obviously, portrait photography is more than just having a suitable lens. Maybe I'll exeriment a bit and write an article or two about it someday.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Chris</name>
      <datetime>2013-06-14 03:52</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Erik,

I just stumbled across this in doing some research. I'm purchasing a canon 60d and have been looking at 3 lenses. I shoot mostly street, low light still, urban landscapes. I'm looking at the 50mm 1.8, the 40mm 2.8 pancake, and a tamron 17-50 which do you feel would work best?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-06-14 19:03</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Chris,

for any kind of landscape photography, be it urban or not, you will benefit from the larger field of view of the Tamron. The 40mm and 50mm are great for street (ie people) photography though - partly because they force you to think different about your shot, requiring you to move around to compose, and because they are small and light to carry anywhere.

But if I had to choose only one lens of those you mention, it would probably be the Tamron. The image quality should be good, and such a zoom lens comes in handy very often.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Jonathan Job</name>
      <datetime>2013-06-16 04:27</datetime>
      <website>http://www.facebook.com/jonathanjob123</website>
      <message>This article makes lens hunting so much easier! Thank you so much for the input Erik! Im gonna pick up the 40 mm now! :)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-06-16 13:37</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Jonathan,

glad to be of help. Have fun with the lens!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Apurva</name>
      <datetime>2013-07-18 14:50</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Erik,

Can you tell me whether the 50mm f/1.8 is significantly faster than the 40mm pancake?

I basically want one of the two for my low light photography as my second lens.

Thanks.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-07-19 14:42</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Apurva,

since f/1.8 is one and a half stop faster than f/2.8, the 50mm will enable you to cut your exposure times by more than half if shooting open compared to the 40mm.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Apurva</name>
      <datetime>2013-07-20 07:32</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thank you very much, Erik.

You're doing a get help to people like me. :-)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Peter</name>
      <datetime>2013-07-23 09:41</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hello Erik!

I thought this review was superb!

One quick question: I will be leaving to Rome/Venice/Florence next week, and I was planning to buy a new lens for the trip. I will be shooting monuments, landscapes, and art. I will also shoot a couple videos here and there of the family...which lens (of the two above) do you think would be best for my personal uses. I'm leaning toward the pancake but have heard different opinions. Thanks!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-07-23 19:11</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Peter,

thank you for the kind words!

As you probably already have understood, I tend to lean towards the 40mm. It's small and sharp and difficult not to like.

However, you might feel a bit limited by the fixed focal length. 40mm (and 50mm) is great for detail shots and should also work well for art, but a shorter focal length would probably be more useful when shooting landscapes. Also, for videos, the 40mm is good but it lacks an image stabilizer which helps a lot to reduce shake.

Consider getting the 40mm and then, keeping things on a budget, simply bring the kit lens along. It's light, has a useful focal range and optical image stabilization. Aperture and image quality may not be great, but that's what the 40mm is for.

Hope this helps.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Peter</name>
      <datetime>2013-07-23 20:45</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>If you were to choose between...

1. The 40mm 2.8 STM
2. Canon - EF-S 55-250mm f/4-5.6 IS II
3. Canon - EF 75-300mm f/4-5.6 III
4. Canon - EF-M 22mm f/2 STM Standard Lens
5. Canon - EF-S 18-55mm f/3.5-5.6 IS II
6. Canon - EF 75-300mm f/4-5.6 III USM

Which one would you choose for the purposes that I will use. Thanks.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-07-23 21:43</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Peter,

what kind of camera do you have? Because lens number 4 (the 22mm) is using the EF-M mount and is not compatible with "standard" Canon SLRs.

I think you could benefit from something that is a bit wider than the 40mm, and the only lens that does that from those you listed is the kit lens (number 5 in the list). On a budget, the kit lens is a safe choice in many situations, but it may not have the best optical quality.

The rest are rather long zoom lens, which seems less useful for what you intend to use it for.

Above, Chris asked whether a Tamron 17-50 is a good option... and I think it is! Consider adding it to the list. ;)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Peter</name>
      <datetime>2013-07-23 21:44</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>If America, it is called Canon Rebel t2i</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-07-23 22:32</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Ah, the T2i. It's called 550D here and is similar to the 600D, which is what I am using. So I guess what I stated above applies.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Peter</name>
      <datetime>2013-07-24 04:33</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hey Erik,

 Just picked up my new pancake lens! So far, I think it's a great addition to my camera. I do have one quick question, and it's probably a stupid question but please bear with me since I am just starting DSLR's and am quite old and not too good with technology, 85 and still going strong! The 40mm lens does not zoom at all, is that how it is supposed to be? Or am I doing anything wrong? Thanks so much for your help!

-Peter</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-07-24 08:55</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>No, you are not doing anything wrong. :) The 40mm is a prime lens, not a zoom lens - it has a fixed focal length. Zoom lenses may provide more flexibility, but prime lenses are usually lighter and have better optical quality.

Shooting with a prime lens may be difficult sometimes, but it also forces you to think differently about the shot - it takes more than just standing and zooming.

Keep shooting with it, it is certainly very rewarding.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Peter</name>
      <datetime>2013-07-24 10:09</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks Erik!

Leaving tomorrow to Venice!

-Peter</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Dami&#xE1;n</name>
      <datetime>2013-07-26 16:54</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Danke!
Du hast meine kaufentscheidung positiv beeinflusst.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Gab</name>
      <datetime>2013-08-02 00:05</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Very good review! THANKS! I learned that neither the 40mm nor the 50mm was for me. I'm glad to have the picture samples with a crop camera!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Ahmed</name>
      <datetime>2013-08-04 20:15</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi, Erik!

Firstly, thanks for this wondeful article. :)

Secondly,
Which one you would choose for video shooting? (for Canon EOS-M)

1- EF-M 22mm f/2
2- EF 50mm f/1.8 II (with EF Adapter)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-08-04 22:36</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks Ahmed! :)

For video, the 22mm should be more quiet while focusing, unless you stick to manual focus. Also, 22mm is a quite convenient focal length and you will not have to back off as much as with the tighter 50mm, especially if shooting indoor. I also feel that using the EOS-M with an adapter in part defeats its purpose.

The 50mm has a very shallow DOF so it will allow you to isolate subjects very effectively, more so than with the 22mm. Looks cool if that's your style. Otherwise, I would go for the 22mm with the EOS-M.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Ian</name>
      <datetime>2013-08-06 13:10</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks for your comparison. Plastic fantastic is so weak and ugly that i cannot let me buy such a piece of shit. EF 50mm 1.4 is much better but overpriced twice. So I decided to get one nice 40mm. Good built quality and sharp lens. And one more thing that 40mm have 7 blades diaphragm versus 6 blades on 50mm. It means more round bokeh</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Bruna</name>
      <datetime>2013-08-21 16:10</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hey Erik!

I have a canon t3 (1100d) and i still have doubts between getting the 50mm or 40mm lens. I want to be able to get night shots, but I don't know if it's worth to get the 50mm because of the quality of the mount and the sharpness of the 40mm. But as I said, f/1.8 is quite better for night shots. Can i get an advice for that? :)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Marielle</name>
      <datetime>2013-08-21 16:48</datetime>
      <website>http://twistedminded.blogg.se</website>
      <message>So awesome that you compair with photos and everything. I'm gonna go for 40mm now! :D</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-08-21 17:35</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>@Bruna:

Guess that depends on the type of shot. For cityscapes, both lenses are too long and you are probably better off with the kit lens and a tripod. For other types of shot, you will probably want as much light as possible. I have found even the 1.8 to be barely enough for shooting people in a poorly lit restaurant, so I would say try the 50 mm.

@Marielle:

Thank you, and have fun with the lens! By the way, if you just like comparing photos in general, you might be interested in this comparison between DSLR, cell phone and compact:

http://www.erikmoberg.net/article/dslr-vs-cell-phone-camera-vs-digicam</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Vivek</name>
      <datetime>2013-08-26 05:30</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hello Erik,

Really a nice article comparing both the lenses. I've been using 18-55mm kit lens on my new 600D since last 2-3 months however I've noticed that most of the photos (60%) are not sharp as I'd have liked. Like others on this thread, I am also confused about 40mm /or/ 50mm. I mostly do portraits and close-ups so based on the discussion I feel I should go with 40mm. Can you shed some light on how sharp (in %) is 50mm as compared to 18-55mm kit lens? Also how sharp (in %) is 40mm as compared to 50mm? So this way we'll have a better idea of sharpness for all 3 lenses. Thank you.

My flickr id is vivsaby</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-08-30 00:47</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Vivek,

good comment! I should really compare the sharpness more carefully. However, it's a bit of work and worthy a blog post on its own. I will see what I can do.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Vivek</name>
      <datetime>2013-09-02 06:01</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thank you Erik. I look forward to reading your new blog post. Have a nice week ahead.

Vivek</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>james</name>
      <datetime>2013-09-09 14:02</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Erik ,
Loved the way you keep things simple and explain stuffs which most other websites fail to do .I have a similar question like Vivek has--
Which lens should i go with my canon 60d- canon 50mm 1.8 or canon 40mm f.2.8 ? I need lens for the below reasons

1)Street photography
2)Outdoor portraits
3)Landscape /outdoor photography

James</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Robin S.</name>
      <datetime>2013-09-09 22:00</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hello,
I'm really confused...
I own a canon eos 650D and i don't know which one to choose..

The 40mm f/2.8 stm or the 50mm f/1.8 II?

I want to use it for portrait/landscape/street.

Which one should i get?

Robin</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-09-09 23:02</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Robin, hi James,

seems like you are both asking the same question! The 650D and 60D are similar in many ways, so this should apply to both:

Portrait: Either will do, but the 50mm has a slight edge thanks to a shallower depth of field which isolates the subject. Also, the resulting focal length on a crop sensor camera is around 80mm, ideal for portraits.

Street: The compactness and wider field of view makes the 40mm the better choice in my book. Some may still find it a bit too long though.

Landscape: You're better off with the kit lens! Both lenses are too short for this purpose. Still, you can use either of them and software stitch the shots later. There might be better programs out there, but I sometimes Microsoft ICE which works for me:

http://research.microsoft.com/en-us/um/redmond/groups/ivm/ice/

Hope this helps somehow. ;)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>ruud</name>
      <datetime>2013-09-09 23:13</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>So if i read the comments...
If i would walk around in the city and just want to shoot pictures of people and other interresting stuff and i would like to do a little portret of people and animals inside and outside.

I can better get the 40mm above the 50mm  right?

Or am i wrong?

Ruud</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Dave</name>
      <datetime>2013-09-10 13:07</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Same question as Ruud, please help us.

Greets,
Dave</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-09-10 18:15</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi ruud, hi Dave,

sure! As I see it, the 40mm should get the job done better. The 50mm feels too tight for such situations (unless you are on full frame). If you plan on shooting animals in low light, the 2.8 aperture might be too slow though - especially since animals tend to move when you don't want them to. A standard zoom lens (for flexibility) and an external flash gun (for quick shutter speeds) might serve you better in this case.

And also, there is no "right" or "wrong" here - it all depends on what you are comfortable shooting with. I know myself that I had the 50mm for quite some time without using it much, but the 40mm has basically stayed on since I got it - but that's just me. ;)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>lloyd</name>
      <datetime>2013-09-11 21:17</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>hi erik,
i just wanted to ask if this lens is better or same quality of canon 50 1.4??
im planning to buy 40mm but my friend suddenly sell his 50mm 1.4
so what you think 40 2.8 or 50 1.4?
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-09-14 11:12</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi lloyd,

tough one! I have not tried the 1.4 myself, but from what I have heard, the price difference to the cheaper 50mm 1.8 is hard to justify for many. If the price is right and bokeh is your thing, it might be worth going for though. It should be great for portraits.

If possible, ask your friend if you can borrow and try out the lens for a day or two - that should make the decision easier.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-09-20 19:11</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>To Vivek (and everyone else),

I just posted a quick comparison between the 40mm, 50mm, kit lens, and the Tamron 18-270. It could provide some more guidance:

http://www.erikmoberg.net/article/quick-sharpness-comparison</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Tyrone</name>
      <datetime>2013-09-25 00:08</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hey mate I have a 600d and I am slowly getting into automotive photography would either of these else's be good for that I'm having a hard time finding what lense to go to next for car portrait shots. Thanks mate</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-09-27 09:47</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Tyrone,

while both lenses have good optical quality, they might be a bit too tight. Detail shots would work well though. Please read my previous comment on this:

http://bit.ly/192lkLU</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Sally</name>
      <datetime>2013-09-30 21:18</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Erik,

I'm looking to get another lens other than my kit lens for the Rebel T2i that I own.  I'm mainly wanting to use it to shoot newborn and child photography.  I thought about just picking up the Prime 50mm lens since it's so inexpensive, but after reading your review I'm thinking the 40mm pancake lens is the way to go. In your opinion, which one do you think is better for newborn photography (mainly indoor) the 50 or the 40? And is there another "all purpose" lens that you can recommend I add that would also be good to have other than the kit lens and the prime lens? (I was thinking the Canon EF 24-105mm f/4, but feel it may be to heavy duty for what I need it for)

Thanks so much!
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>razu</name>
      <datetime>2013-10-01 21:01</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>hi erik..

i want to do  portrait/street photography. i want better bokeh and sharpness. i have canon 600D.  cost is not my concern, i just want better quality of picture.
which will be better for me?

50mm f1.8 ? or
40mm f2.8?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-10-02 19:45</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>@Sally: The 50mm is a must for any canon user according to some, so do feel free to pick it up! The shallow depth of field and the slight fuzziness fully open can really create some magic. Personally, I still prefer the 40mm though, mostly because of its more usable focal length and build quality.

For an all-purpose lens, consider the Canon 15-85. Its weight and zoom range should be more fit for an APS sensor camera than the 24-105, and it's cheaper (although still a bit pricey). You might want to google some reviews to see if it's for you.

@razu: I prefer the 40mm, it's very sharp and has rounder bokeh. It's also smaller and focuses more quietly.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Sally</name>
      <datetime>2013-10-07 13:06</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks for the quick response Erik! You've been very helpful :)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Mitrava</name>
      <datetime>2013-10-23 18:21</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Erik

I have been using 50mm for a few months, until I dropped it and it parted into 2. I'm really into travel photography and 50mm hardly was of ne use as its angle was too narrow and if I focus an object close by the background is barely visible at 1.8 fstop. Though the 'object' comes out to b real awesum. Sharpness is an issue in long distance shots. And I find it too bright in daylight even at iso 100. For travel Its of no good. But for portraits its unmatched.
How's 40mm for travel, long shots, and how wide is it?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>kenneth</name>
      <datetime>2013-11-04 11:48</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>hello Erik,
i just really want your opinion about this.
Is 40mm is really a good upgrade from Canon 18-55isII?
or should i just stay in my kit lens?
what you think ?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Adrian</name>
      <datetime>2013-11-06 22:21</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>War hilfreich und ich habe mich f&#xFC;r das 40mm entschieden..
Sch&#xF6;n, einen Frankfurter im Internet zu entdecken (zumindest Fotos aus Ffm)
:)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-11-13 20:08</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>@kenneth: The 40mm is sharper and faster, but it lacks optical image stabilizer and also zoom. In that sense, it's not a pure upgrade since there are tradeoffs. If you think the 40mm will suit your needs, by means, go for it. But if you feel that zoom and IS are important, consider a quality zoom lens instead.

@Adrian: viel Spa&#xDF; mit dem Objektiv! Bin mittlerweile umgezogen, war aber eine sch&#xF6;ne Zeit in FFM. :)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Rusty</name>
      <datetime>2013-12-01 16:16</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Very helpful review! 40mm is the one for me!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Logan</name>
      <datetime>2013-12-28 08:26</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks so much for this...im strapped on budget and i just needed a lens that can stay on my 60d. I have a zoom,but it's too heavy for walk around and the 50 is just too tight, i was looking for a review that actually has photos from cropped sensor bodies..thanks so much for this. (I have a 50 1.8 and im trading it for a 40 for the "little" extra wide) thanks again.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-12-28 13:07</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Logan,

I hope the 40mm has what you are looking for. Since I got it, it has stayed on the camera much longer than the 50mm ever did - definitely a good sign.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Zajden</name>
      <datetime>2013-12-30 17:15</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks a lot !! Really nice blog you have there</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Jane</name>
      <datetime>2014-01-05 16:06</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thank you so much!!

This thing with canon 50 mm also happened to me. It just fell apart. I got very sad because I had it only for 5 days and at that time I went for a vacation, so I couldn't take photos.
After your article I realized that it wasn't my fault and thank you for good advice! </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Aniruddha</name>
      <datetime>2014-01-06 10:40</datetime>
      <website>http://https://www.facebook.com/pages/xeno-photography/355653014549103</website>
      <message>I have a canon 550D
i have the basic 18-55 mm lens
i'm more into portrait and nature photography as you may see on my page
i plan to buy another lens to enhance my photography in these two areas
also i need lens with which i get good bokehs
which lens do you think i should go for ?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2014-01-06 14:14</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>@Zajden: thank you, glad you like it!

@Jane: yes, the build quality of the 50mm is very poor. Luckily, after mine feel apart, I was able to push the two pieces back together and it has been working since.

@Aniruddha: the 50mm has a focal length suitable for portrait photography on your camera and offers great bang for the buck. Just be careful not to drop it! The 40mm should also work well, but will not be able to blur the background as much. For nature photography, neither is very suitable. You will probably need a good quality zoom lens that's wide enough for landscape shots. The Canon 15-85 is a good general purpose lens that should work well for you. Have fun!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Glenn</name>
      <datetime>2014-02-13 01:40</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thought I'd chime in with my recommendation for those with  full-frame cameras. If I'm indoors, the 50 is on due to it's larger aperture. If I'm out and about, it's the 40 due to the size. I feel the loss of aperture is a fair trade for the compactness. That said, for most portraits I prefer my 85/1.8 or the 50 in a pinch because to 40 distorts faces too much. So, as you can see, there's a place for both lenses with a full-frame body. I had a cropped body before and used the 40 for a walk-around normal lens and the 50 for my portraits.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Sanchit</name>
      <datetime>2014-02-18 11:22</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Erik,

Firstly, great article!!

I have a Canon 600D too and as it is evident I am confused between the 50mm and the 40mm lens.

I do a lot of low light photography, pet photography(my dog is my fav. subject), children photography (during their workshops, in side a room and loads of movement) and landscapes.

I have the standard 18-55 and 55-250mm lenses, could you suggest which one of the two 40mm and 50mm will be more suitable for my photography style?

Thanks!!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>David</name>
      <datetime>2014-03-09 01:34</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Very informative.  Thanks.
On the street shot of the bike with the 40,  what was the aperature?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2014-03-09 19:58</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>@Sanchit: Sorry for the late reply! Neither the 40mm nor the 50mm is very suited for landscape shots, but both are good for portraits, especially on a crop body. You may benefit some from the faster aperture of the 50mm if you shoot in low light and want to freeze action. Otherwise, keep the lenses you have and get a flash instead (preferably one with a swivel head for light bouncing).

@David: thank you for your interest in this article! The aperture in that shot is f/2.8, with a shutter speed of 1/400th, at ISO 100.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Bob</name>
      <datetime>2014-03-18 11:29</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I am a insect lover and i love to click insects only...Can you suggest that which lens give a better satisfaction for insect photography????</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2014-03-18 15:01</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Bob,

in my opinion, neither can focus close enough to be used for serious macro photography. Also, macro lenses are typically a bit longer, usually equivalent to 100mm. But if I have to choose one over the other, it would be the 40mm since it can focus a bit closer as shown in the macro shot in the article. Hope this helps!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Emiliano</name>
      <datetime>2014-03-21 14:33</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Erik,

Great page!

I need your opinion here.

I have been recently robbed and now I'm purchasing my equipment again and think I think about buying two lenses (primes).

50mm 1.8+85mm 1.8 (I read great thing regarding the 85mm and I had the 50mm with nice results, but think that 85mm and 50mm will be some kind of "close")

40mm 2.8+85mm 2.8 (I read nice things regarding the pancake and think even it is slower it has the half focal lenght than the 85mm which is also faster).

Also, I really like models, beauty and "people" shooting so think that 40mm + 85mm will be a good option to shoot close portraits and mid body photos.

What do you think?

Thanks and greetings from Argentina :)

</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Emiliano</name>
      <datetime>2014-03-21 14:37</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Oh, I have a 60D and the kit lens.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2014-03-21 16:34</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Emiliano,

sorry to hear you got robbed, hope you are OK!

About the lenses, if you have used the 50mm before and liked it, I see no problem picking it up again. The focal length is great for portraits on a crop body and it can produce a very shallow depth of field to make the subject stand out. But I understand what you mean, and also feel that the 50mm and 85mm might be a bit close. So if you are getting the 85mm anyway, I also think the 40mm would be the better companion. The compactness is also a nice plus.

However, personally I feel that 85mm is a bit to long on a crop sensor for portraits. Have you considered the 50mm for portraits, and using something 30mm-ish for full body shots or as a walk around lens?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Emiliano</name>
      <datetime>2014-03-21 18:08</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks!

Any recomendations for 30mm?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2014-03-22 02:58</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Canon has a 28mm f/1.8 and Sigma a 30mm f/1.4, either one should probably be okay in your case. By looking at some reviews, it seems that many lean slightly towards the Canon. Both lenses cost more than the 40mm pancake, but the price point is still within reason.

Please be aware that I don't own either of these lenses, or the 85mm! You might want to read some reviews before blindly following my advice. ;)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>abhijeet</name>
      <datetime>2014-03-30 22:17</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>hi
i have canon 60d with 18-55 and 55-250.
pls help me to choose lenses .
i like to click in house or street photography.and  some time function pics.
so, suggest me for buying the lenses 50 mm 1.8 or 40 mm 2.8 stm.
i got sharper also.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2014-03-31 16:47</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi abhijeet,

the kit lens you already own, the 18-55, is pretty OK for indoor and landscape much thanks to is reasonably wide angle. Neither of these two lenses are very wide and may be awkward to use. For street however, I would prefer the 40mm for more compactness. As already mentioned, it's also very sharp. Hope this helps!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>abhijeet</name>
      <datetime>2014-04-02 21:27</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>thank u Erik..
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Agness</name>
      <datetime>2014-04-07 10:13</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I got totally confused. I am going to by the Canon EOS 600D + the 18-55mm lens, BUT would also love to have a lens for portraits.  I like taking pictures of individuals and mainly outdoor. Sooo, my question is whether it is worth buying the 50mm lens (for shoulder and full-length photography)/ Thank you in advance.,\ </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2014-04-07 22:29</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Agness,

the 50mm can create a nice, blurry background with its shallow depth of field, so is great for portraits. And it's cheap too! Start using the kit lens first (at the long end), if you feel that it doesn't deliver on portraits, the 50mm is a cheap upgrade and usually well worth it.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Agness</name>
      <datetime>2014-04-08 09:11</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks a lot! :)
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Pardeep</name>
      <datetime>2014-04-08 14:21</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Erik,
I have Canon 600D and 18-55mm and 55-250mm lense. But I want a lense for a portrait photography,or fashion photography. I know both these lense are actually not meant for this. But still I want your suggestion on this. I read the review, but still in a confusion regarding 50mm or 40mm.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Chinmay</name>
      <datetime>2014-05-15 08:50</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thank you so much Erik!!! Going with 40mm...</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Vineet</name>
      <datetime>2014-05-15 14:42</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Well, Erik thanks for the full fleged decription. :) both the lenses have amaZing aperture. Well I'm use to shoot short films and now want to go ahead with lot of low light photpgraphy.  I have tried my hands on 50mm (though I don't own it.)
As per my experience. 50mm will give you perfect results as you desire when there's more light.
So, as per my requirement what do you suggest, 40mm or 50mm?  I own 550D with kit lens and i'm thinking to also buy 75-300mm lens:</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2014-05-16 23:06</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>@Pardeep: The 50mm is a good portrait lens, feel free to go ahead and get it! ;)

@Chinmay: Glad I could help! :)

@Vineet: If you tried the 50mm and liked it, maybe that's a good choice already? You could consider the 40mm if you want more compactness and better build quality, and don't mind the slower aperture.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Vineet</name>
      <datetime>2014-05-17 13:52</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Okay. Well then i'll go for 40mm as well. Thanks for the advice.
Can you also guide me with 55-250mm f4-5.6 and 75-300mm f4-5.6 one? I have heard 75-300mm is not good. But i'll surely be missing the extra 50mm if I go for 55-250mm! </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Lee Joonmin</name>
      <datetime>2014-05-31 12:50</datetime>
      <website>http://www.isleofdroid.com</website>
      <message>Hey, I currently own a 50mm f/1.8 and I demoed the 40mm f/2.8 STM in a store and I really liked the bokeh that the 40mm gave as well as the general image quality and build quality. But I'm worried about the difference between 2.8 and 1.8, especially given my 40D's pathetic ISO performance at 3200. The 1.8 allows me to do night shooting at ISO1600 but will the 2.8 be suitable for me?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2014-05-31 18:02</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Lee Joonmin,

good question, and I can't seem able to make up my own mind about this!

Maybe you could check the EXIF (metadata) of some of your old shots and see if there might have been room for another stop and a half - maybe your shutter speeds were faster than you think, or the ISO lower. You probably want to stay at a shutter speed of 1/60th to be safe, combined with a f/2.8 aperture and ISO 1600. If you are already pushing it at f/1.8 (lets say ISO 1600 and 1/30th), then f/2.8 might be tough. But also note that the shorter focal length helps reduce camera shake slightly at slow shutter speeds, as described in the article.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Nitish</name>
      <datetime>2014-06-18 06:56</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Erik I use a Canon 550D and already own a 50mm f/1.8 but I'm not very content with it as the angle of view is a problem when I want to get closer to the subject which usually is my wife and kid. I love to shoot portraits with the softer blur and good bokeh. Which lens would you advise me to go for. I was thinking of 28mm f/2, 40/mm f/2.8 and 35mm f/2. My dire need is portraits and couple shoots producing the softest blur and great bokeh. Also suggest me if any other lenses are better of than I mentioned above around the same budget. Thank you.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2014-06-21 23:18</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Nitish,

while I like the 40mm, I have the feeling it might be a bit too long in your case - and I am afraid I don't have any hands on experience with the other lenses you are considering. I do have an old 28mm lens though, and I find the focal length quite useful so personally I would look into that. By the way, have you considered the Sigma 18-35 f/1.8? That way, you have a quite flexible solution and don't have to stick to a single focal lenght.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>dimgeo</name>
      <datetime>2014-07-20 21:14</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Dear Eric
I have the canon 550d with 18-55 kit len and i would like to upgrade my equipment so as to work as a photographer in a club's events in my town.Which of the two lenses do you suggest and why;
Thank you for your time!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2014-07-23 18:59</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi dimgeo,

well, as always, it depends! The two lenses are not dramatically different; both have a fixed focal length and are good for portraits. While image quality is good with both, the fixed focal length is often limiting. Try setting the kit lens to 40 or 50 mm and see what it's like. If it feels comfortable, well, I prefer the superior build quality of the 40 mm. If you will shoot in dim light, the large aperture of the 50 mm will probably serve you better, however.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>dimgeo</name>
      <datetime>2014-07-23 19:13</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thank you for your quick response! I used to use external flash for my job so your i tring to find the most value for money new equipment.I think that 40 mm might be my solution,what do you think?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2014-07-23 19:24</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I am very fond of the 40 mm and not trying to make a secret out of it! ;) Hope you like it as well.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Andrew</name>
      <datetime>2014-08-07 19:29</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Erik. I dont have a question but I just want to say thanks for all your help! I am amazed at all your responses for each and every person/ situation. You are helping people capture beautiful memories. So thank you. :)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2014-08-07 19:39</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Andrew,
thank you for the kind words! Makes me feel all warm and fuzzy inside. ;)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Chan</name>
      <datetime>2014-08-16 06:53</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>i have 1100d . which one will be better . 40 mm ya 50mm?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2014-08-16 09:17</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Chan,
The ISO performance of the 1100D is not all too shabby, so I think I would have gone for compactness instead of speed, meaning taking the 40mm. If you feel otherwise (you probably have the kit lens already - does it feel slow in the short end?), the 50 mm would enable faster shutter speeds.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Andrei</name>
      <datetime>2014-08-20 06:21</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>@Nitish, the EF 85mm f/1.8 is an excellent choice for portraits and is not that expensive.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Anthony</name>
      <datetime>2014-09-24 05:58</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>In your opinion when lens do you think would work better for glamour shoots in tight locations. bedrooms, bathrooms, living rooms, or even suites?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2014-09-25 23:09</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Anthony,

A shorter lens is usually more convenient if you have little space, but also will be less flattering to the model. You might want to get the cheaper 50mm and then a flash gun for off-camera flash - it might get tight, but at least you have good light!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Amin</name>
      <datetime>2014-10-30 17:37</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Great article!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Mithun</name>
      <datetime>2014-11-04 06:39</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Erik,

Thanks for a detailed article. I was in a confusion which one to buy , but now i have decided to go with 40mm.

Once again thanks :)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Neto</name>
      <datetime>2014-11-11 18:42</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Erik

How about the new Canon EF-S 24mm f/2.8 STM Pancake?
In a Canon eos 100d, what would be the main/best use of these lens?
1) Canon EF 50mm 1:1.8 II
2) Canon EF 40mm f/2.8 STM pancake
3) Canon EF-S 24mm f/2.8 STM Pancake</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2014-11-11 19:57</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Neto,

today, I think I would rather go for the 24mm. I like the 40mm, but my main gripe is the slightly too long focal length. 24mm on a crop body should be very versatile. Anyway:

1. Lots of bokeh. Good for portraits and isolating subjects.
2. Good for travel thanks to small size and build quality. Also good for portraits.
3. Just as small as the 40mm. Better for general use and as walkaround lens because wider, less so for portraits.

I don't have the 24mm so I'm guessing a bit here. But it certainly looks pretty good!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Neto</name>
      <datetime>2014-11-12 00:45</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks a lot Erik!
So, the 24mm or 40mm pancakes are a good complement to canon 18-55 is stm original kit? For a amateur guy who likes street photo, travel photos And some landscape...</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Luisa</name>
      <datetime>2014-11-20 17:31</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Erik,
Thanks for the review. I have one quick question, I just bought my canon t5i recently, (the one with the 18-135 lens) so far it has been good, but I want to take portrait pictures the type where the background is blured, I feel I can`t get that with the one I own, Im new at this so I dont know if its the lens or Its just me not knowing how. Can you help me with this and is the 40mm the one for this types of picture, would it be a good purchase for what I want? I appreciate if you can get back to me asap because Im about to buy it and Im all the way in colombia so I wont be able to return it if it doesn work for me.!!! Thank you so much!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Luisa</name>
      <datetime>2014-11-20 17:36</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>sorry, Also, for night shots I havent been able to take clear pictures at night with my 18-135 unless I have the flash on and I dont think the pictures look good with flash, is the 40mm good for that?
thanks </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2014-11-20 20:29</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Luisa,

don't worry, getting used to new equipment takes time! You can try a few tricks with the lens you already have for more blur:

1. Make sure the mode dial is in Av (aperture priority) mode and that the aperture is fully open - meaning the smallest possible number.
2. The further the subject is from the backdrop, the stronger the blurring effect.
3. Use longer focal lengths. At 135mm, the effect should be more noticeable. Try shooting twice with the same composition, one at the shortest focal length (18mm) and one at the longest (135mm).

For night shots, stick to a large aperture and a short focal length and make sure the optical stabilizer (IS) is on. Consider using a tripod, or improvise one - for example, put the camera on a rock and use the 2 second timer.

The 40mm is good for portraits and should give you a little more blur. It is, however, only marginally faster than the 18-135 and it lacks IS, so it is not a given choice for night photography.

Hope this helps!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Neto</name>
      <datetime>2014-11-21 15:08</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Erik
Fpr you, the 24mm or 40mm pancakes are a good complement to canon 18-55 is stm original kit?
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Luisa</name>
      <datetime>2014-11-21 20:46</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Im so glad you answered, thank you very much!!!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>j</name>
      <datetime>2014-12-09 07:26</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>excellent comparison, made the decision so much easier. thank u Erik.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Drago</name>
      <datetime>2015-01-02 21:40</datetime>
      <website>http://dragoart.alle.bg</website>
      <message>Hello Erik,
first of all,I'd like to thank you for the reviews and photo samples,very professional!Could you please give me an advise for my case - I am a painter and I'd like to take "print-size" photos of my paintings. So my studio is very small (about 4x 4,5 m) and I am wondering which kind of lenses to choose.My camera is Canon 60D, the other lenses I have is Canon 17-55/2.8  Thank you very much in advance! </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2015-01-03 12:54</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Drago,

thank you! You will want to avoid distortion as much as possible, so you would probably want a fairly long quality lens, and you should stand back as far as you can. Also, a tripod helps. You might want to experiment with the lens that you have to find out far you will able to stand back and how long the lens can be (it also depends on the size of the paintings). If 50mm feels OK, you can get away with the cheap Plastic Fantastic - it should produce very little distortion and stopped down a bit, it is razor sharp.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Drago</name>
      <datetime>2015-01-03 13:35</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Many thanks for answering,
I tried one Plastic Fantastic and the result is..hm,ok.I think in the center it's sharp as hell, but at the corners it isnt what I want.My biggest paintings are 60x40 cm, so the 2-3 meters from target is an excellent distance
for shooting, with a solid tripod that I use. So, you said 40mm is sharp in whole picture and I am really interested in it.The bad thing is that I can't find one for test shoots, just have to blind-buying it...
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2015-01-03 13:43</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>It interests me as well. I might try to set up such a shot. Subscribe to the comments using the RSS feed to make sure you don't miss it. :)

In the meantime, you can have a look at this article where I compare the sharpness between different lenses:

http://www.erikmoberg.net/article/quick-sharpness-comparison</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Drago</name>
      <datetime>2015-01-03 14:26</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I checked it and it seems that 40mm is sharpest))) Would be really cool if you set up some shots (painting or some similar object in a room) - this will help me for sure.For this moment my sympathy is going to 40mm)))))))</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2015-01-04 21:34</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi again Drago,

I made you the comparison! The article pits the 40mm, 50mm and the kit lens against each other, shooting a 72x52 cm picture from 2-2.5 meters. Hope it helps:

http://www.erikmoberg.net/article/experiment-shooting-art-with-cheap-lenses</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Drago</name>
      <datetime>2015-01-05 17:06</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Wow,Erik,thank you very much, really appreciate it!!!!! Love the shoots, it made sense for me. I am still in 40mm, despite of distortion.It can be correct easily with photoshop.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2015-01-05 23:42</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>No problem. :) Hope the lens works for you!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Drago</name>
      <datetime>2015-01-08 09:59</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hey Erik,
what about Canon 50mm/1.4? Did you ever test this lens?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2015-01-08 21:05</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>No, never tried it. Your mileage may vary, but many reviews say that the 1.8 is about as good as the 1.4. Here, for example: http://www.slrlounge.com/school/canon-50mm-prime/</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Drago</name>
      <datetime>2015-01-09 13:06</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks a lot, my friend,it's very helpful !</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>lizzy</name>
      <datetime>2015-02-03 07:26</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi,

I have a 550 d and am looking to click some candid shots of a child and also if possible to use the same for some macro photography of nature and minute objects .

do correct of i am wrong but having lot difficulty in selecting one of teh two lenses discussed here

currently i have a kit lens and 18-55 and a 55-270 lens </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2015-02-06 18:35</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi, lizzy

hard to say! Neither of the lenses here are particularly great for macro. The 40mm might have an edge because it focuses a bit faster, and you can also let the lens auto-focus and then adjust the focus manually without changing any settings. This can be useful if the subject is moving around a lot.

You already have some decent gear there, think about what is really missing. If you like the flexibility of a zoom lens, you might want to stick to your guns. If you need more light and more bokeh, either of these should be good fun.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Ray</name>
      <datetime>2015-02-26 08:29</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi,

I recently got the 600D, kit lens, and the 50mm/1.8 lens, but I feel like it is too long for indoor shooting.  I still have the option to return it, would the 40mm or the 24mm pancake be a better option?

This is my first DSLR and I'm still new to photography.  Perhaps the kit lens would be good enough? What do you think?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2015-02-26 21:16</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Ray,

the 50mm definitely feels awkward indoors with an APS size sensor. But if you are aware if its limitations, it can be both fun to use and produce great results, especially for portraits. That said, the 24mm will most probably be more versatile. If you find yourself shooting close to the short range of the kit lens most of the time, the 24mm should provide better quality in a smaller package. Otherwise, just keep experimenting and learning with the 50mm. It might be a challenge to use sometimes, but in the right situation and some practice, it certainly delivers.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Albertho J.</name>
      <datetime>2015-03-26 16:44</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks a lot... I was undecided between the two lenses, buy now I know for sure which one is the better choice...</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Dale</name>
      <datetime>2015-04-18 00:54</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi,

I have a Canon 70d and was wondering which lens is better for </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Dale</name>
      <datetime>2015-04-18 01:07</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>(Cont.)...for photographing my young kids who are, as expected, on the move all the time - 40mm or 50mm? I've had the 50mm for just under a year and have been very happy with the pic quality, although I have struggled getting the focus right on a few occasions (blurred or not focusing on more than one subject - I shoot on automatic and scene - portrait). Yesterday I dropped the 50mm lens, hence the decision to replace it with the same lens or try something a little different (40mm).

I look forward to hearing from you. </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2015-04-19 12:53</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Dale,

subjectively, the 40mm tends to hunt for focus a bit less and also, it can take a bit of a beating! Unlike the 50mm, which fell apart after I dropped it - luckily I was able to push it back together again. So I think the 40mm might be a good option for you. Hope this helps!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Dip</name>
      <datetime>2015-06-05 11:51</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Eric,
Congratulations on the excellently written article. I need an advice from you. I have a Canon 1000D with 18-135 IS Lens. Additionally, I have a 40mm 2.8 STM with it. I generally prefer Street/General photography. Plz suggest me whether should I stick with the 40mm or look for the 50mm 1.8 or the 24mm 2.8? Moreover, can you please through a brief light about the merits of 24mm, 40mm and 50mm? Expecting a quick reply.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2015-06-06 11:03</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Dip,

thanks! Well I think it depends on your shooting style and where you feel the 40mm lacks. If you feel that it's too tight, the 24mm might be a better choice. With 24mm, for street photography, you will need to get closer to your subject, which might be a good thing. With the 50mm you may have to step back a bit, and it will also give a more shallow depth of field. However, the 50mm is not quite as compact, and has a sub par build quality.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Dip </name>
      <datetime>2015-06-06 20:02</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Dear Eric, thanks a lot for the reply. Well, as far as Portrait is concerned which one is better between the 24mm 2.8 and 40mm 2.8?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Dip </name>
      <datetime>2015-06-06 20:06</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Dear Eric, please refer to another query of mine. What are the main differences between the Canon 24mm 2.8 and 40mm 2.8? Is 40mm good enough to be used with 1000D?
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2015-06-06 20:07</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>The 40mm should be more flattering, as faces will look thinner. The shorter 24mm will distort faces a little, leading to big noses and the like.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2015-06-06 20:21</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>And the 40mm is a very good and sharp lens - not only considering its price point - and it works quite well on my 1000D.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Dip</name>
      <datetime>2015-06-07 06:50</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Dear Eric, thanks a lot for the reply. I prefer to stick with my 40mm 2.8 :-) Thanks a lot, once again.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Dip</name>
      <datetime>2015-06-07 20:15</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Dear Eric,

One more :-) Is there any need to use UV Filters with Canon Lenses? Personally I don't believe in these UV Filters. If I don't use them will the lenses get deteriorated? Please reply</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2015-06-07 22:10</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Dip,

I don't use UV filters and I don't see a good reason to. It might provide some protection, but so does a lens cap. Also, be aware that some (cheaper) filters can worsen the image quality quite a bit. Hope this helps!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Dip</name>
      <datetime>2015-06-08 19:36</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Dear Eric, Thanks a lot once again! :-) Thanks a lot for your lovely co-operation.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2015-06-08 20:29</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Glad to be of help!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Nastik</name>
      <datetime>2015-07-04 08:59</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hello Sir Please suggest me a good lens between 40mm-50mm for my canon 70d
uses Product shoot leather bags and mobile covers</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2015-07-06 19:14</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Nastik,

either one discussed in this article should do, but I tend to lean towards the 40mm (as you might have noticed).</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Prasun mondal</name>
      <datetime>2015-07-06 20:24</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>hi,
I am bit confused between 50mm 1.8 STM and 40mm 2.8STM.
Price wise both are same. Functionality wise i was shooting with my 60D at 50mm and 40mm with my 18-135 , but it did not seem to a lot of difference frame wise.
while comparing both the lenses the 50mm 1.8 STM appeared to be sharper beyond f4 till f11.
there seem to be a strange magenta glow on the corners in the 40mm 2.8 STM .
I shoot everything from closeup to landscape to portrait. for me sharpness is the priority. i had made up my mind to go for the 40mm but now i am more inclined to the 50mm.
please help me out.
thanks.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2015-07-08 19:31</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Prasun mondal,

the corner glow might be due to vignetting at large apertures, which is quite common. It should go away at f/4 or f/5.6 or so. Either way, if you have already tried the two lenses and liked the 50mm better, why not simply go for it? At the end of the day, both lenses are actually quite similar.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>laura</name>
      <datetime>2015-08-16 01:05</datetime>
      <website>http://dairyfreekids.ie</website>
      <message>Thanks very much, you answered the exact question I needed answering. I am now going to get the 40mm to go with my 600D. Excited to try it out. Thanks for taking the time to post this. </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Larry Miller</name>
      <datetime>2015-11-06 18:50</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I shoot with the Voigtlander 40mm/F2 pancake Aspherical lens. A truly outstanding lens. Sharpness that's unreal with a "Leica" look in the pics it produces. Kudos to the Voigtlander group for making this lens...</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>vimal rajpurohit</name>
      <datetime>2015-11-13 06:33</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hiii
 Erik its vimal from india .i want to ask that which one is better for potrait as eell as architectural photography.
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2015-11-13 18:05</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi vimal rajpurohit,

both are pretty good for portraits on a crop body. The 50mm will give you more background blur so it might be a better choice in some situations.

For architectural photography, none of these will really cut it as they are quite narrow and have no fancy features such as tilt-shift. However, either one will do fine to capture the small details - just be aware that none of these is a proper macro lens. The 40mm gets a bit closer than the 50mm though. Just make sure to also bring a wider lens along!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Mark</name>
      <datetime>2015-11-16 12:56</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Erik
Im a begginer in photograpy and our family loves to travel and we want to take pictures with us and on our background are the place weve visited, we want to carry 1 lens when we travel, what do you recommend?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2015-11-16 22:30</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Mark,

neither of these really suits your needs. I once brought only the 40mm on a trip abroad, which I thought was a bold and creative move, but it ended up being only very limiting. It often feels either to long or too short. If you are just starting out, use the kit lens for a while. 18-55 is a useful range and it will help you to get the shot almost every time.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>jakub</name>
      <datetime>2015-12-01 01:43</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>hi there!

nice article, well done !

I was just wondering if u had any chance to compare new STM version with 40mm one?

regards
jakub</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2015-12-04 21:16</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi jakub,

afraid not! It looks quite attractive though. If you want to sponsor me, feel free to send me one in the mail. I will make sure to give it a thorough review. ;)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Vicky</name>
      <datetime>2016-01-13 21:43</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hey Eric, I make videos for youtube and I was looking to purchase a new lens. I'm confused however, which lens would be better for that kind of shooting; indoor makeup videos. I also use the rebel t5. Would either of the lenses be compatible? </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2016-01-17 22:13</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Vicky,

either lens should work just fine with your camera. As you understand in the article, the lenses are quite similar, with more or less the same pros and cons.

It should be noted, however, that image stabilization may be of interest when shooting handheld video. You might want to use a tripod when recording video since neither of these lenses have optical stabilizers. You can experiment with this yourself by using the kit lens (which I assume that you already have) and switching IS on or off to see the difference. </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Sid</name>
      <datetime>2016-02-02 11:56</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Dear Erik,

I would like to say you are doing great job. Its such a eye opener for beginners like me.I  had question in my mind but found answers from one of your replies above.

Thank you so much Erik :)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Sanjay Sagar </name>
      <datetime>2016-05-18 17:39</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Erik,
I have bought a 40mm STM after reading your review and I am so happy to see the superb performances as well as image quality of this cute little honey of a lens. Today this lens has been my workhouse and I love to use this lens. Its my darling lens. Thanks for the review.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2016-05-18 21:27</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Sanjay Sagar, hi Sid,

glad to be of help! I have a few lenses, but the 40mm still stays on the most - for good reasons!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Manjit</name>
      <datetime>2016-07-17 09:40</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Erik

Was planning to buy the 50mm for my 700D, however after your review the 40mm will be in the collection soon.

Thank you for the excellent comparison and review.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Jasna</name>
      <datetime>2016-11-23 23:37</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I am just about to purchease Canon 750d with 18-135 lense as a kit - so no experience in DSLR area.
Yet my kid is in speed skating (poor lights, fast movement) and I have been warned that aperture of 3,5 will not satisfy my needs. That I need at least 2,8. Lenses with zoom and 2.8 aperture are very expensive. So I am thinking about fixed lense. I plan to be around 30 m away from the kids I want to take pictures of.

Which of the two 40 with 2,8 or 50 with 1.8 is better for me?

Thanks for good article!

Jasna

</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2016-11-26 14:11</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Jasna,

happy you liked the article! Between the two, the 50 mm is probably better since it's faster and the longer focal length lets you get closer to the subject. It might still be a bit short though, and like you mention, a fast (and long) zoom lens would probably be better - but the wallet definitely disagrees!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Santanu</name>
      <datetime>2016-11-27 07:52</datetime>
      <website>http://https://wordpress.com/stats/month/santanusays.wordpress.com</website>
      <message>Hi Erik,
Thank you for this beautiful insight.
I have Canon 600D accompanied by 18-55mm &amp; 55-250mm.
I was confused about a 50mm or a 40mm.
It appears to me that 40mm is the right choice.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Sami</name>
      <datetime>2017-02-23 09:12</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>sir, can you please tell me which lense between canon ef 50mm f1.8 STM and canon ef 40mm f2.4 STM will be better for making the best bokeh and for wedding photography?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2017-02-27 20:05</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Sami,

the 50mm will produce more background blur than the 40mm. You can actually tell from the shots of the leaves in the post above.

For wedding photography, it really depends - there is much more to it than just having a fast prime. Wedding shoots tend to be a tad chaotic - lots of stuff going on, limited time - and I think a good quality zoom lens might be the right tool for the job here, since it allows for more flexibility.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Suraj Tiwary</name>
      <datetime>2018-02-17 05:50</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Erik,

 I am a budding photographer. I have been learning for 1 year. I have 1300d. And I am using 18-55mm lens. Now I want to enhance my kit. So I am looking for a small aperture lens. What will be better choice 40mm or 50mm lens? As I am going for a wedding shoot or portrait. </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2018-02-20 19:08</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Suraj Tiwary,

either one should do fine! Also refer to my reply just above yours. Apart from a new lens, you might also want to consider an external flash gun so that you don't have to rely on available light.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Hank</name>
      <datetime>2018-03-14 21:52</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thank you. Great article. Now I know which I want to get. </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>hala sabet</name>
      <datetime>2018-08-06 16:01</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>hi..thanks for the review. i am an artist and would like to photograph my paintings and sculpture. which lens would be better the 40mm or 50mm.  i have the 500d camera.
thanks</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2018-08-08 20:11</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi hala sabet,

either one should probably do just fine, even though I usually lean toward the 40mm for its better build quality and sharpness. You might also want to look into getting a good tripod as well, if you do not have one already. It will get rid of any camera shake and help with composition. Hope this helps!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Suraj Tiwary</name>
      <datetime>2018-09-26 07:28</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks for the input Erik.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Ray</name>
      <datetime>2018-12-07 15:16</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks fpr this very excellent review!I

I would love to see your review on the newer Canon pancake 24mm lens.
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2018-12-07 16:16</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Ray,

I would like that too - because it would mean that I had the 24mm in my possession. Please let me know if you could help me with that! ;)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Aria</name>
      <datetime>2019-04-13 12:00</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I'm one of those people with a full-frame DSLR (and three crops, all four Canons), and I use the 40mm quite often, even over my much pricier other lenses.  I've got a 50mm, but get better results with the 40.  Sometimes it's not the lens, but how you use it and what you're using it for that makes all the difference.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Zo</name>
      <datetime>2019-06-13 14:24</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Erik,

Thanks for the review there. I'm a new photographer and was hoping to get some advice on lenses. I have the Canon M50 with the kit lens. I want to do photo and video which will be portraits, landscapes in both day and night and some indoor/outdoor and night time videos.

Which of the 2 should I get as an additional lens to complement the kit lens I have.  I ahve also been looking at Canon EF-M 22mm f/2 STM.

Thank you</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2019-08-14 22:19</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Zo,

the Canon EOS M50 uses the EF-M mount so these lenses will not fit without an adapter. Since the adapter and either of these lenses would cost more than the 22mm, just go with the 22mm. It should probably a better walkaround lens anyway.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Tino</name>
      <datetime>2020-08-17 18:23</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>The 50mm lens is commonly known as the "Nifty Fifty". For the amateur it is the go to lens when you start to move away from your standard stock lenses.

It is inexpensive, great quality photos and not too difficult to use.

However, you have to get real close to your subject if you wish to fill the lens.

Important: With the 50mm lens you have to shoot manual - to not use auto settings, you will never get close to that perfect shot.

I use my 50mm with flashes. I don't like using hot lights. With flashes you can get fascinating images, plus you can experiment a lot more than what is possible with hot lights.

Happy snappies !!

- Tino
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>John</name>
      <datetime>2020-11-15 14:39</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I own both the 40mm, and 50mm. Nice article but I think that the 50mm is sharper than you're showing in some of your pictures, especially the leaves.</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="homer_simpson_bao_song">
    <comment>
      <name>tlczek</name>
      <datetime>2013-05-06 22:36</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thank you! It did save me time!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-05-06 22:37</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Ha! I knew it would be useful to someone! :)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Holypip</name>
      <datetime>2013-09-24 18:25</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Yes! I was so disappointed when I couldn't find the song on Youtube. Thanks.</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="prevent_javascript_redirect_in_firefox">
    <comment>
      <name>Patrick Horn</name>
      <datetime>2013-05-29 17:28</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I had exactly the same problem with Jimdo .... thanks for the tipp with the AddOn!!! (Didn't found it with the Firefox AddOn Search).

But after trying it one time (and the message to deny appeared), it did not work the second time. Don't know why. I didn't added any permanent rules. I had to change the rule setting of the AddOn from "domain" to "host", then allow 2 internal links of Jimdo to be able to use the editing functions of the CMS, then it worked ... and I could delete my redirect-code ... </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-06-13 23:38</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks for your comment and the additional info! Glad to be of some help. :)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Adam</name>
      <datetime>2014-09-14 12:26</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thank you! Your topic was very useful. i had exactly same problem with Jimdo. </message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="suspended_droplets">
    <comment>
      <name>Dami&#xE1;n</name>
      <datetime>2013-07-26 17:02</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Super Bild!
Hast Du allein gearbeitet oder hat jemand f&#xFC;r dich fokussiert und ausgel&#xF6;st?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-07-26 17:14</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hallo Dami&#xE1;n,

danke!

alles selber gemacht. War ein bisschen arbeit, hat sich aber gelohnt. Fernausl&#xF6;ser hilft. ;)</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="new_lens_-_tamron_18-270_3.5-6.3_di_ii_vc">
    <comment>
      <name>Jan</name>
      <datetime>2013-08-22 12:03</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>hello Erik,

about the fact that the system "kicks in" and freezes the image. I just bought this same lense, and when focussing, the image in the viewfinder actually moves a fraction to the left down corner, and when releasing it again (without taking the shot) it moves back again. Do you notice the same effect happening?

thanks,
Jan</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-08-24 00:27</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Jan,

not sure it's the same thing as you describe, but with the camera on a tripod and image stabilization turned on, after focusing - and that's when the IS kicks in - it starts drifting around quite a bit. It keeps on doing that until the IS is deactivated after a few seconds. The effect is very noticeable at the long end and using live view. The stabilizer tries to correct errors that don't exist and end up creating errors on its own. It's normal for this type of lens; IS only works for fairly quick shutter speeds anyway, and makes no sense on a tripod. But it still looks weird. ;)</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="dslr-vs-cell-phone-camera-vs-digicam">
    <comment>
      <name>Vivek</name>
      <datetime>2013-08-29 10:35</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Nice comparison. I like it. </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-08-30 00:48</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Vivek,

thank you! If you have any questions, just me know.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Pamo</name>
      <datetime>2013-09-02 21:26</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hur kommer linsen att klara sig p&#xE5; telefonerna.
Typ damm och grus i fickan?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Robert</name>
      <datetime>2013-11-01 12:25</datetime>
      <website>http://www.snapp.de</website>
      <message>Hi Erik,

Cool post, not a very bright future for compact digital cameras I suppose. Let's catch up on Skype soon!

Cheers,
Robert</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>minnesh</name>
      <datetime>2014-12-08 07:03</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>i need some help, got a 600 d really having a difficult time getting the setting right, in door is a disaster, can u help with some advise
thank u kindly
minnesh</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="quick-sharpness-comparison">
    <comment>
      <name>oliveR</name>
      <datetime>2013-10-13 04:05</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Wow. This is quite a comparison. Thanks for sharing, great help to make a good decision.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Hashim</name>
      <datetime>2013-10-18 15:12</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks a lot for your comparsion Erik.

So as i see it the 50mm will not do good photos on f/1.8 if handheld,
so its better to go for the 40mm pancake.

and i read in your comparsion between the 40mm and 50mm that the 40mm pancake does not have stabilizer, how important is the stabilizer, for this lens?

Thanks</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Hashim</name>
      <datetime>2013-10-18 15:20</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>and one more question,
I have the 650D with 18-135 STM lens and the aperture goes to f/3.5,
will i see i different with the 50mm and 40mm when i take picture in indoor low light situation.

Thanks</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-10-19 00:39</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Hashim,

thank you for you comment. The reason why the 50mm is so blurry wide open is not because it's handheld in this case, but simply because it's not sharp at a fully open aperture (ie. not because of slow shutter speeds).

Regarding image stabilization, I blogged about that quite a while ago. I used the kit lens at 55mm and shot with and without IS at different shutter speeds. In conclusion, IS helps quite a bit (but of course, only if the scene is static). Read here:

http://www.erikmoberg.net/article/canon_image_stabilizer_is_test

For indoor low light shooting, if you stay at 18mm, you will not notice much difference to the 40mm. The 50mm is quite a bit faster and could suit better, if you can live with (or prefer) that fuzzy look it produces wide open. Still, it may not be able to freeze action (like kids moving around), so if that's your thing, hold on to that lens and get an external flash instead.

Happy shooting!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>ChrisC</name>
      <datetime>2013-11-29 19:41</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>That was Exactly the comparison I was looking for between the 50 and 40mm prime lens. Thank you!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>ClaesP</name>
      <datetime>2014-01-04 11:12</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Erik!

Thanks for your articles! They are very helpful!

I have a 550 D with a Canon EFS 18-135. I thinking of getting a 40 mm to reduce size and weight. Have you done any comparision between these two lenses in terms of sharpness?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2014-01-04 12:03</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi ClaesP,

thank you! :)

I do not own both lenses so I cannot make a comparison myself. However, both lenses have good enough quality, so maybe just skip the IQ question for now. The 40mm is very compact and much lighter, which is what you are actually looking for - if you are willing to sacrifice the zoom, of course.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>ClaesP</name>
      <datetime>2014-01-04 14:25</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi again!

Have you looked into a comparision of 40mm vs the new 35mm IS?
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2014-01-04 22:37</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi again ClaesP,

I'm afraid I haven't! I read some reviews of the 35mm and while it seems a tad more usable - having IS, larger aperture, and a visible focal scale - it's also larger, heavier and several times more expensive than the 40 mm. Sharpness should be about the same, possibly with the 35mm stopped down some. </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>ibler</name>
      <datetime>2014-02-10 10:39</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Great comparison! Thank you!!!

I've been scouring the net for a couple of weeks now trying to get as much information about theses lenses as possible. Now I'm getting the 40mm thanks to you!

I'm a newbie to photography and my greatest frustration is that I can't capture on camera what I see with my eyes. Impossible demand? Yes. That's the reason why I'm shopping around for a new lens but something that does not break my wallet. (I also am aware of the "you get what you pay for" adage so lets not go there. :) )

So now I'm honing my technical skills on the kit lens and composition skills on the 40mm.

Thank you again for this wonderful comparison! </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2014-02-10 20:44</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi ibler,

that sounds great, glad I could help!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>David</name>
      <datetime>2014-03-09 01:29</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thans for your reviews, very useful.

Could you comment on the landscape shots?   The water and sky don't pick up the blues on th 40 like the other lenses.  </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Nathanation</name>
      <datetime>2014-03-09 10:01</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Cheers for this comparison, I'm getting the 40mm for sure now, looks so much sharper in your comparison shots with a more pleasing amount of contrast!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2014-03-09 19:50</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>@David: For some reason, seems like the camera underexposed that shot by one stop. That would probably explain why the shade of the sky is different. I used aperture priority with auto ISO for all shots, so blame the 600D. ;)

@Nathanation: Sounds great, have fund with the lens!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Anastasia Roupakioti (Absinthia Stacy)</name>
      <datetime>2014-05-04 17:58</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Very interesting comparison!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>blaze</name>
      <datetime>2014-05-05 14:27</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>no more thinking. I am going to get a 40mm 2.8 STM and sell my 50mm 1.8.     I could not really get friends with the 50mm 1.8.   </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Andy</name>
      <datetime>2014-08-23 19:54</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I've been interested in the 40mm since I started last year. I ended up getting the 50mm as I needed a fast prime for an event, I do like the 50 but understand the issue with softness at 1.8.

The lowest I ever go is f2.8, I also find the 50mm is way too tight for me and not compact enough considering the 50mm is my lightweight travel setup. The noise from the AF motor is pretty silly aswell.

Decided I'm going to sell my 50mm and get the 40mm. Good job I slapped a cheap uv filter on it when I bought it and have babied it for the few months i've owned it so it's still in mint condition, should get my money back and invest some more into the 40mm and get what I wanted in the first place.

Thanks for helping me confirm my decision. :)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>abhishek</name>
      <datetime>2014-09-15 20:58</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi erik
I own a canon 1100d with the standard kit lens...I've purchased a 55-250 mm recently....its doing its wonders....feeling apprehensive about my next lens purchase bwn 40mm/50mm...I'm more into closeup shots, portraits and landscape..please advice</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2014-09-15 21:08</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>@Andy: Glad to help!

@abhishek: Neither of these are very good landscape or macro lenses, but great for portraits. The 50mm is a bit cheaper and faster, while the 40mm is more compact, has superior build quality and costs a little more. You can read more here:

http://www.erikmoberg.net/article/canon-ef-50mm-11-8-ii-vs-canon-ef-40mm-f-2.8-stm-which-to-get</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Amin</name>
      <datetime>2014-10-30 17:49</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks for the very nice article! My pancake is coming soon! Anyway, do you know how's the effect of lens filter on the 40mm? Should it be covered (hood or filter) or let it be free? What is the best filter which will not ruined the image quality?

Regards</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2014-10-30 22:45</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Amin,

Happy you liked it!

I don't use any filters or lens hoods on any of my lenses and I have never had any problems. I feel that lens hoods mostly add bulk (especially with this small lens it would), and even a high quality filter does degrade the quality some. The front element of the 40mm is not very exposed anyway so it's not really in need of protection.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Amin</name>
      <datetime>2014-10-30 23:42</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>That's true. Thanks Erik!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Vaibhav</name>
      <datetime>2015-01-06 08:38</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hello Erik,
Truely well done comparison. I am going to go on a cruise around sunset. the photos will be both landscape and portrait. I expect the lighting to be low for portraits. What would you recommend, 18-55 MM kits lens or the 50mm prime</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>satish</name>
      <datetime>2015-03-05 12:07</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>HI Erik,
It seems like 40mm pancake lens is much superior than canon 1.8, but would u tell me which one will be better for low light and concert photography.

Regards</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2015-03-15 10:55</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Better late reply than never, I guess...

@Vaibhav: I think you should bring both! The 50mm is great for portraits and low-light photography, but with the kit lens you will be being able to get wide sunset shots as well.

@satish: The 50mm is definitely faster so it's better on many low-light situations. But 50mm seems a bit short for concerts, no? You might want to look into a fast tele lens with image stabilizer. The Tamron mentioned in the post is OK, but probably too slow.
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Uttam</name>
      <datetime>2015-03-23 17:49</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I have a Canon DSLR 1200D. I intend to buy an inexpensive prime lens. I have been told that Canon 24mm 2.8f STM works better in such cropped body camera. My prime interest is in street photography and portrait. Please advise. </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2015-03-23 19:46</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Uttam,

The 24 mm is said to be a great lens too - compact, sharp and good build quality. It should also be well suited as a street photo lens, where the 40 mm might be a bit tight at times (depending on situation and shooting style). However, the shorter focal length will lead to less background blur, and also distortion - expect large noses on subject when doing close portraits. </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Uttam</name>
      <datetime>2015-03-24 07:44</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks Erik. Will it be reasonably ok in low lights too. I am still undecided if I should go for 50mm 1.8f or the 24mm 2.8f STM one. Would appreciate your views.
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2015-03-28 00:00</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Uttam,

tough one! I do find myself shooting more with the 40mm, also in low light - and I usually find it fast enough. Of course, the 50mm is a bit faster, and makes for nice artsy late night street shots. If you are specifically going for low-light without flash, then the 50mm might be the better choice. </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>ks</name>
      <datetime>2015-06-26 19:39</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Congratulations for doing a nice comparative review. I often wonder why many online journals and forums can't do such easy-to-understand reviews despite having some of best technical people around and a lot of money to spend.

I own 50 1.8 and 18-55 lenses. My own take is that 50mm is much sharper at 4.0 than 5.6 so perhaps a comparative analysis of photos at 4.0 might have brought the sharpness of 50mm ahead of other lenses. This in any case does not undermine your review and its findings. Just my two cents. </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2015-06-26 19:49</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi ks,

Glad you liked it, and thanks for the input! I might look into finding the sharpest aperture for the 50mm, it should make for an interesting article.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>ks</name>
      <datetime>2015-06-27 16:44</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Yes, kindly explore that setting and share your findings.

If I may suggest, kindly you also add Canon 24mm in your next review. That would be really interesting to a lot of people as I doubt any one has done a comparative image-by-image review of 4 lenses.  </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2015-06-27 23:16</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>That's a great idea and I'm quite interested in the 24mm. However, I can only review lenses that I own and I currently don't have any plans to pick up this lens. If any representative from canon reads this: Please send me the 24mm for free, I'm sure it will be worthwhile for you. ;)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Prasun</name>
      <datetime>2015-07-06 11:58</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>hello Erik,

your blog is the deciding factor for choosing the 40mm 2.8 stm.
i have a canon 60D with 18-135 IS and sigma 70-300. i do stock photography and was unhappy with the performance of the 18-135mm. overall it was soft. i shoot everything from macro , landscape . portrait.

the canon 50mm 1.8 seems soft wide open and unusable for stock photography.
i think i will go with the 40mm , hope i made the right choice.
thanks.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2015-07-06 19:18</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Prasun,

the 40mm is really quite sharp, I hope you will be happy with it. :)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Heather</name>
      <datetime>2015-11-14 05:58</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I've been a little confused about which lens to get (I'm upgrading to a canon 700d from a 1000d that I've owned for about 5yrs, previously only having my 2 kit lenses that came with the 1000d I'm ready to step my photography up a bit and get a bit more adventurous with shots!). I just also read your other article on the 40mm v 50mm. Thanks for putting everything in an easy to understand language and the side by side photos which is exactly what I've been searching for for a few days to make up my mind, technical specs don't phase me I needed to see in photos what the difference was. 40mm lens it is! Thanks again :)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Ankur</name>
      <datetime>2016-12-06 18:27</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thank you Erik. Out of so many blogs on net, your explaination is superb. I have been using Canon SX-20 (super Zoom) with 1:2.8 to 5.7 USM lens. Now I have bought 750d with 18-55 STM lens. I am not very happy with 750d. Reason could be either I need more time to adjust to new gear or the Kit lens is not that great as compaired to lens in SX-20. I am more in to portrait, closeups and landscape. As per your recomendation, 40mm STM seams to be a good choice. Can you suggest any good Zoom lens which is as sharp as 40 mm but with a range of 18- 50 and also not expensive than 40 mm STM.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Ankur</name>
      <datetime>2016-12-06 18:36</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Also I would like to add that I used to click photos at high Zoom (with Canon SX20) without my subject knowing that I am taking their photo, thus not making them consious and gettting natural shots. So should I Opt for 55-250 mm IS II? But I want my photos to be sharp as well. Please advice. 55-250 mm IS II or 40 mm STM.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2016-12-06 20:06</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Ankur,

happy you like my blog!

For the price of the 40mm, your choice of lenses is very limited. And especially if you are looking for a tack-sharp zoom lens! That said, the Tamron 17-50mm zoom lens is similar to the kit lens, but offers better optical quality and a faster f/2.8 aperture. It costs twice as much as the 40mm though.

The Canon 55-250 (or maybe the 70-300) could be a good choice since you get a lot of bang for the buck, but it will still not provide the optical quality you are looking for.

Try getting used to the kit lens first to try to figure out what you need. It's actually not such a bad lens at all. Or, just get the 40mm now and get used to a different kind of shooting - you will need to get closer, but sometimes getting up close and personal with your subjects can make for more interesting shots.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Ankur</name>
      <datetime>2016-12-14 09:53</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Erik,

Another question. There are two versions of 40 mm STM lens. One is aspherical lens (model no. 6310B005, 132 gms, 2012) and there is another Normal lens (model no. CNN_40mm F/2.8_CanonDSLR, 249 gms). I have mentioned weight to clarify that they are different with different price. Which one is better and what is the difference?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2016-12-14 19:59</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Ankur,

I was not aware that canon had another 40mm lens out. This post is about the lighter one. Do you have a link?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Ankur</name>
      <datetime>2016-12-15 03:16</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Erik,

I saw this on amazon.in when i searched for EF 40 mm. I have posted a query on amazon also as the discription given for heaver one does not seems correct.</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="canon_600d_and_memory_cards">
    <comment>
      <name>John insipid </name>
      <datetime>2013-10-14 13:50</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Exactly what I needed to read</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>HoverflyRC</name>
      <datetime>2013-12-31 17:16</datetime>
      <website>http://stores.ebay.co.uk/hoverflyrc</website>
      <message>Thanks For The Info As We Was Having Major Problems &amp; It Works A Treat Now </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>oliviajason</name>
      <datetime>2015-06-02 07:18</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>San Disk is one of the best manufacturing companies for micro SD card. I do agree with you; last time I was also using micro SD card and I faced great problem due to it. Then, I started to use SD card of company Easy replication and I had never face any problem.</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="easy-fix-for-google-nexus-4-sliding-off-surfaces-and-muffled-speaker">
    <comment>
      <name>Vati</name>
      <datetime>2014-03-27 19:36</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Sett och l&#xE4;rt!</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="met-lok-c-from-digitalrev">
    <comment>
      <name>Sofia Lucifairy Koutsouveli</name>
      <datetime>2014-05-04 17:41</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Wow, that was really great, I wish I could be with you and meet him too!</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="short-review-logitech-k400r-vs-plexgear-mediatrack-ergo">
    <comment>
      <name>Maktor</name>
      <datetime>2014-07-09 17:23</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Just the  comparison I was looking for,  thanks !  How  does  the trackball hold up  quality wise?    Is it exhausting for the  thumb to use  it for a couple of hours ? </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2014-07-09 19:02</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Maktor,

glad to be of help! I don't have the keyboard anymore, but I found the trackball a tad small and light to comfortably work with. I have two cheap Logitech trackballs here with much better ergonomics and precision. I still found it OK for controlling a media PC or for a short gaming session, but for extended, sustained use, you might want to look elsewhere.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Maktor</name>
      <datetime>2014-07-11 06:40</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Went with the k400 and like it a lot so far, thanks! </message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="responsive-image-gallery">
    <comment>
      <name>Cassidy</name>
      <datetime>2014-09-14 03:58</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Beautiful! Are you willing to share your secret?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2014-09-15 21:14</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Cassidy,

it's no secret! In the source code of this page, find and open the JS file "scripts.js.php". Scroll down to the part starting with "function RespGallery" and enjoy the messy JavaScript! ;)</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="new_camera_-_canon_eos_600d">
    <comment>
      <name>belle</name>
      <datetime>2014-10-20 06:28</datetime>
      <website>http://bellesmyl.fr</website>
      <message>combien co&#xFB;te t-il celle appareil??</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="aurora-borealis-hunt">
    <comment>
      <name>Robert</name>
      <datetime>2014-11-14 10:27</datetime>
      <website>http://www.snapp.de</website>
      <message>Wow, awesome pictures! Can only image how cold it was up there.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2014-11-15 09:51</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Why, thank you!

With -15&#xB0;C/5&#xB0;F it was basically like summer. ;)</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="fixing-broken-breaks-on-maclaren-techno-xlr-buggy">
    <comment>
      <name>Vati</name>
      <datetime>2016-07-10 22:10</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>K&#xE4;nns tryggt att vagnen g&#xE5;r att bromsa.
Ytterligare en s&#xE4;kerhetsdetalj f&#xF6;r sl&#xE4;ktens fortlevnad!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Irina</name>
      <datetime>2017-09-10 03:32</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>You are genius! I was ready to change wheels in my maclaren but this is much cheaper solution! Thank you for the article! </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2017-09-10 09:00</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Irina,

glad to be of help! We are still using the buggy without issues, now over a year later, so we are quite happy ourselves.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Kathryn</name>
      <datetime>2017-11-07 16:11</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Erik-
This is exactly what I need to do for my Maclaren. Did you find a place that sold the whole set like that, the 4 cogs and the star locks? or did you need to order the pieces individually. I'm searching and can't seem to find a kit like the one you have.
Thanks.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2017-11-07 21:51</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Kathryn,

even though I did not get this myself, it looks like the shop I bought the parts from also has a kit that I believe should work:

https://www.babyboom2000.co.uk/products/maclaren-techno-xt-xlr-rear-axle-repair-kit.html

The parts are sold individually also.

Good luck!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Andreas</name>
      <datetime>2017-11-12 17:15</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hey Erik,

Thanks for taking the time to write down your experience, it encouraged me to do the repair on a 7year old mc laren we bought second hand - and today the parts finally arrived and I could do the repair.

It involved turning my toolbox inside out to deal with the starlocks in both ways, but all worked out and after maybe 45 minutes everything was done.

Cheers,

Andreas</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2017-11-17 09:14</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Andreas,

I'm glad it worked out. And yes, those star locks are terrible to deal with! Better get a few spare ones when you order, just in case they get damaged while installing.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>nadja</name>
      <datetime>2018-08-24 14:02</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>hi Erik
is it possible to remove the wheels without damaging them? i got the replacement wheels but don't kn9w how to remove the old ones. </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2018-08-24 20:59</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi nadja,

no damage to the wheels themselves should be caused by following the instructions above. However, the star locks will probably be badly damaged and need to be replaced. But they are of course much less expensive than the wheels. I hope this helps!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Paul</name>
      <datetime>2019-02-05 10:50</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Erik,

Thanks a lot for your awesome write-up, wouldn&#x2019;t have known where to start without this. Really appreciate you taking the time to write this up. Buggy is as good as new &#x1F642;

Thanks,
Paul</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2019-02-06 12:57</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Paul,

exactly the reason I wrote this in the first place; to help someone else in my situation. Great to hear the buggy is alright again!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Alex</name>
      <datetime>2019-10-03 20:07</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Dear pros,
I have turned  internet with legs up to find the cogs online, but i couldn't.
Can you suggest, or someone sells me their old thinned cogs so i could cut/file them and glue to my also thinned cogs?

Thank you. Sasko.basko at gmail dot com</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2019-10-03 20:26</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Alex,

it seems that finding these parts is getting harder. The link I posted above also does not work anymore.

You could contact them directly, or check if they still have any other parts that might help you in any way: https://www.babyboom2000.co.uk/categories/spare-parts/maclaren-spares.html</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="velbon_sherpa_200r_review">
    <comment>
      <name>Joe</name>
      <datetime>2016-12-07 22:03</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi, I would like to say that I am using this tripod for a number of years and I am very satisfied with it. It is more than enough for my needs.
I do lots of filming, not too much photography and I like the fact that this tripod is smooth and easy to use as compared to other "high end" tripods.

Unfortunately it doesn't have the bubble level to adjust correctly your camera, but since you know already how much vertical your shots would be, I think it's very intuitive. It depends on your experience as well.

I like your review, by the way!</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="repairing-the-toshiba-regza-42xv556d-power-button">
    <comment>
      <name>Vati</name>
      <datetime>2017-05-09 18:19</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Ja j&#xF6;sses vad man kan hitta p&#xE5;!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Paul</name>
      <datetime>2021-09-16 21:04</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks Erik 

Was a great help!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>test1</name>
      <datetime>2021-12-13 22:03</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>test2</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="unity3d-replace-sprite-programmatically-in-animation">
    <comment>
      <name>jam</name>
      <datetime>2017-05-23 20:44</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Awesome! Worked right away, thanks for this!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2017-05-23 21:28</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi jam,

glad to be of help! It's funny - I was too busy and sort of gave up on this game quite some time ago, just to pick up the ball again only a few days ago. Coming to a store near you in... 2035??</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Dorian</name>
      <datetime>2017-08-04 02:40</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi, thank you so much for your code. I really search for that... but i have a problem... I recieve this : "KeyNotFoundException: The given key was not present in the dictionary.
System.Collections.Generic.Dictionary`2[System.String,UnityEngine.Sprite].get_Item (System.String key) (at /Users/builduser/buildslave/mono/build/mcs/class/corlib/System.Collections.Generic/Dictionary.cs:150)
SpriteSwapDemo.LateUpdate () (at Assets/Scripts/SpriteSwapDemo.cs:40)
"

What is the problem ? I don't understand the reaction of Unity.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Dorian</name>
      <datetime>2017-08-04 03:48</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>^^' I have found myself (I forgot to rename each sliced image with the same name)

Your code just work perfectly :) thank you so much for your help and time :)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2017-08-04 17:06</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Dorian,

glad you got it figured out. Good luck with your game!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Raitan Biz Rigon</name>
      <datetime>2017-08-26 02:28</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thank you, it worked fine! </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Dajka Ferenc</name>
      <datetime>2017-09-07 15:06</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi!
Could you share the source please? I can't reproduce this in my project, maybe the Animator has different settings.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2017-09-07 21:23</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Dajka Ferenc,

maybe there is a simple solution to it. At which step are you having trouble?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Lucas</name>
      <datetime>2018-01-11 15:55</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thank you so much! It works perfect! You saved me so much time.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Rafael</name>
      <datetime>2018-05-28 16:58</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>The code works perfectly, but the console keep showing this every frame:

ArgumentException: An element with the same key already exists in the dictionary.
System.Collections.Generic.Dictionary`2[System.String,UnityEngine.Sprite].Add (System.String key, UnityEngine.Sprite value) (at /Users/builduser/buildslave/mono/build/mcs/class/corlib/System.Collections.Generic/Dictionary.cs:404)
System.Linq.Enumerable.ToDictionary[Sprite,String,Sprite] (IEnumerable`1 source, System.Func`2 keySelector, System.Func`2 elementSelector, IEqualityComparer`1 comparer)
System.Linq.Enumerable.ToDictionary[Sprite,String,Sprite] (IEnumerable`1 source, System.Func`2 keySelector, System.Func`2 elementSelector)
SpriteSwapDemo.LoadSpriteSheet () (at Assets/Scripts/SpriteSwapDemo.cs:49)
SpriteSwapDemo.LateUpdate () (at Assets/Scripts/SpriteSwapDemo.cs:35)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2018-05-28 17:53</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Rafael,

you probably have to or more sprites with the same name in the same sprite sheet. Take a look at the first image in this guide. Click each sprite in the sheet and make sure the name is unique across the sprites in the sheet, such as "walk0", "walk1" etc. Then also make sure to name each sprite in the second sheet with the same name as in the first one. Hope this helps!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Obsession</name>
      <datetime>2018-09-04 20:48</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Life saver.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Martin</name>
      <datetime>2018-11-04 14:14</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Erik, thanks a lot for this, it is simply awesome! You helped me a lot.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Xenonq</name>
      <datetime>2019-07-10 17:29</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Does the sheet need to look exactly like yours. Sprite next to sprite?
[][][][][] &lt; your sheet
[]   []
[]   []   &lt; my sheet
can I have it like this?
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Xenon</name>
      <datetime>2019-07-10 17:50</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I did exactly what you showed and this came up KeyNotFoundException: The given key was not present in the dictionary.
System.Collections.Generic.Dictionary`2[System.String,UnityEngine.Sprite].get_Item (System.String key) (at /Users/builduser/buildslave/mono/build/mcs/class/corlib/System.Collections.Generic/Dictionary.cs:150)
SkinSwapper.LateUpdate () (at Assets/SkinSwapper.cs:41)
I don't know what to do pls help :(
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2019-08-14 22:11</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Xenon,

please check the answer above, Dorian had the same issue.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Shamahan</name>
      <datetime>2019-09-09 16:20</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Holy hell thank you so much for this piece of code, you wouldn't believe how long I searched for something like this, it is exactly what I needed!

One question - is there some way to make the sprite sheet change only once at the press of a button or does it have to constantly be in the LateUpdate function?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2019-09-10 21:18</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Shamahan,

that's great! And with the above code, the sprite sheet should only reload once if changed on the fly. Let me know if you have found that it doesn't.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>John</name>
      <datetime>2019-09-15 00:46</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Ok so I followed the instructions item by item, and have named each frame of both my sprite sheets individual cells to match each other, I am getting the same error as above:

KeyNotFoundException: The given key was not present in the dictionary.
System.Collections.Generic.Dictionary`2[TKey,TValue].get_Item (TKey key) (at &lt;7d97106330684add86d080ecf65bfe69&gt;:0)
Crowd_Sprite_Sheet_Swapper.LateUpdate () (at Assets/Crowd_Sprite_Sheet_Swapper.cs:40)

What's up fam?
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>John</name>
      <datetime>2019-09-15 03:18</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Just to update - got it working - thank you! But I'm getting spammed hard in the console:

ArgumentException: An item with the same key has already been added. Key: Crowd_Generic_0
System.Collections.Generic.Dictionary`2[TKey,TValue].TryInsert (TKey key, TValue value, System.Collections.Generic.InsertionBehavior behavior) (at &lt;7d97106330684add86d080ecf65bfe69&gt;:0)

Any idea why? </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2019-09-15 07:22</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi John,

probably, two sprites in the sprite sheet have the same name. Make sure each name only appears once ("walk1", "walk2"...). If you can't find the problem, try setting a debugging breakpoint in your code in visual studio. Then click "attach to unity" and start your game. Hopefully, stepping through the code will make the problem obvious. Hope this helps!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>John</name>
      <datetime>2019-09-16 14:10</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hey thanks for getting back to me so quickly. I can confirm that within the sheet, no sliced sprites are named the same. Each has a unique name (Crowd_Generic_0, Crowd_Generic_1, etc...)

So I am using the sprite swapping because I am emulating a large crowd (50+ NPCS). A crowd NPC is to use the same animation set, but I am swapping their sheets in order to avoid having to create unique animations over and over again for each NPC.

So essentially 50 NPCs are in the scene - all at once - all referencing one "leader" NPC's animations.

I appreciate the help!
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Tutmo</name>
      <datetime>2019-09-17 17:20</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hey John,

I ran into the exact same issue - all my Sprite names were unique per Sprite Sheet, but still getting the exception error.

After debugging in circles, I realized the issue (for me anyways) was that my initial Sprite in the Sprite Renderer was set to 'None'. I just needed to set the initial Sprite to any one of the Sprites in my Resource Sprite Sheets and the error went away. Hope that helps.

Thanks for the original post Erik! This was way clearer than anything else I've found after hours of Googling!!
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2019-09-17 17:39</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Tutmo,

that's great to know, let's hope it helps John - or someone else for that matter.

And happy to hear you found the post useful!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Tuan</name>
      <datetime>2019-09-21 09:29</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Erik,
I have 1 character with 7 spriteRenders for Head, hand, weapon, horse .... and I want change sprites for 1 or more of them, maybe change all of them.
I learn from your youtube , but when change sprite in Head and Body  Sprite Render, it have problem is run change 1st sprite and not others.
With multi spriteRenderer in one character, so I would like ask how is the best way to solve it?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Marcel</name>
      <datetime>2020-03-01 11:59</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>You're awesome thanks</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Maurilio Alves (@realeirosplay)</name>
      <datetime>2021-03-18 03:20</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Men, you save my project! kkkkkk
Thank you very much!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Hank</name>
      <datetime>2021-06-23 13:56</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Saved me tons of time!
THX so much</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Farn</name>
      <datetime>2021-07-28 22:05</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>This saved my life and probably hours and hours of work by not having to deal with animation overrides.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Jeff</name>
      <datetime>2021-08-18 09:59</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Anyone can help? I can swap the sprite just fine, but I spammed with this line

KeyNotFoundException: The given key was not present in the dictionary.
System.Collections.Generic.Dictionary`2[TKey,TValue].get_Item (TKey key) (at &lt;eae584ce26bc40229c1b1aa476bfa589&gt;:0)
SpriteSwap.LateUpdate () (at Assets/Farming RPG/Scripts/Misc/SpriteSwap.cs:41)

Line 41 is:
spriteRenderer.sprite = spriteSheet[spriteRenderer.sprite.name];

Anyone can help me?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Jeff</name>
      <datetime>2021-08-18 10:00</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>And yes, I'm not "falsely" naming my sprite, because everything works. Just spammed with those line</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2021-08-18 13:27</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Jeff,

strange if each slice is named correctly, but I think it still sounds like the problem that Dorian had above, check https://www.erikmoberg.net/article/unity3d-replace-sprite-programmatically-in-animation#comment-2

Hope this helps!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Jeff</name>
      <datetime>2021-08-19 06:33</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Erik thanks for your reply.

Well it's weird, I even test it by renaming each slice only with numbers (1 to 10) to make sure I'm not having a typo.

The error is still there from the moment I hit the play button (still not interacting with anything in my game).
I'm not using "this" in my code, don't know if it affects anything</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2021-08-19 07:12</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Jeff,

no, "this" should not be required, it's mostly a convention. 

Just make sure that each slice is named the same in every image - so that each slice for player 1 has the same name as for player 2 and so on. 

Usually when I'm having trouble I just set a breakpoint on the offending line and start the debugger, inspecting the variables should definitely help in your case as well.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Jeff</name>
      <datetime>2021-08-19 07:49</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>So my solution is I'm following the exact code from the youtube link you give.
It works fine too just like your code, except it does not give me any error warning.

Though I prefer your code, maybe for now I'll stick with the one on the video.

Thank you!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2021-08-19 09:01</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Sure Jeff, whatever floats you boat! Glad you got it working.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Camillo</name>
      <datetime>2021-08-22 15:07</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>'Sprite []' does not contain a definition of 'ToDictionary' and no accessible extension method 'ToDictionary' was found that accepts a first argument of type 'Sprite []'. Probably missing a directive using or a reference to the assembly. [Assembly-CSharp]</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>David from Ukraine</name>
      <datetime>2021-09-03 15:29</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hello Camillo! 
Try turn on the Linq (Language Integrated Query) feature in the header of your script.
*top of the script file*
using System.Linq; &lt;---
*script*

Hello Erik!
I'm really thankful to you for this great tutorial.
Thank you so much! :)
Have a success in your job and hobbies!

Hello from Ukraine! =)</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="hands-on-cheap-interchangeable-cell-phone-lenses">
    <comment>
      <name>Joie Gahum</name>
      <datetime>2017-09-28 20:50</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Great shots! Checkout roadeavour lens too! </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2017-09-30 22:12</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Joie Gahum,

thanks! However, I'm not sure I think the shots are that great. If I come across the roadeavour lenses, I might check them out in hope of better quality.</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="simple_photo_studio_at_home">
    <comment>
      <name>Gunther</name>
      <datetime>2017-11-05 14:08</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>thank you for your interesting suggestions refering to product shooting!

I have to take photos of objects outside, like houses,  and fixed interior. Do you have any simple suggestions for nonprofessionals for that?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2017-11-08 00:06</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Gunther,

for interior shots, usually an ultra wide angle lens (starting at 12 mm or so) is a good choice. To get decent lighting, have all available lights turned on and use fill flash. Put the camera on a tripod, keep the ISO low and shoot with a remote trigger. Experiment with taking several shots with different exposure settings, then create a composite image with Photoshop.

For architecture photography, you might want to look into tilt-shift lenses. They are usually quite expensive, but they can do cool things like parallax correction and let you capture tall buildings without perspective distortion.</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="wall-mounting-a-d-link-covr-ac1200-mesh-node">
    <comment>
      <name>Per-Erik</name>
      <datetime>2019-01-07 21:50</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Brilliant, Thanks !</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Chad</name>
      <datetime>2019-03-28 03:50</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Can&#x2019;t believe I looked this up for my dlink covrs lol. Good hack.

But would be better if these d kink had a google wifi style plug adaptor.

Anyone know if those exist or can be 3 d printed?
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Algernon</name>
      <datetime>2019-11-29 23:30</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I'm going to drill 2 different diameter "snow man" holes to hang it with screws from the bottom of a cabinet. Wish me luck. </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2019-11-29 23:49</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Good luck, Algernon!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Manu</name>
      <datetime>2020-01-29 02:43</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Actually this one option seems only viable one</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="rocket-league-split-screen-on-pc-with-keyboard-and-controller">
    <comment>
      <name>Renny</name>
      <datetime>2020-01-10 01:35</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Muchas gracias amigo, solucion&#xF3; el problema a la perfecci&#xF3;n :)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>FormularSumo</name>
      <datetime>2020-04-28 17:39</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>This only worked for me when I extracted x360ce 64 bit version to my Win64 folder. I think that's because the DX11 version of the game (which I use) is 64 bit.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2020-05-20 14:35</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi FormularSumo,

thanks for the heads up! I have updated the post.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Matthew from NZ</name>
      <datetime>2020-05-24 08:16</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks for the help, works perfectly :-) </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Kieron</name>
      <datetime>2020-06-17 16:32</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Very useful article, especially if you have friends round but only have 1 pc!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Si Chkoupi</name>
      <datetime>2020-06-20 19:38</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thank you hbibi</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>I like marin</name>
      <datetime>2020-08-19 20:18</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>hot</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Jim</name>
      <datetime>2020-08-21 09:24</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks mate</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>JEFFERSON</name>
      <datetime>2020-09-10 12:41</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi when i join a game the keyboard and controller have a split screen but the controller controls both screens. Any Solutions?
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2020-09-27 21:44</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Jefferson,

didn't have this problem. Maybe go through the settings again in x360ce and make sure that the first controller is has "Map To" set to 1, and the second controller set to 2.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Massu</name>
      <datetime>2020-10-23 06:51</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Massu</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Viktor</name>
      <datetime>2021-03-19 23:17</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Had to disable controller support in Steam to make it work however even with that my controller was controlling both players.

Tried https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qlRZ-1CZTIE and it seem to have worked with it.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Samhan Mansoor</name>
      <datetime>2021-06-19 13:56</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hey! I tried this with another controller - PowerA Enhanced Wired Controller (Xbox). I was able to start as Player 2, but I encountered the following issue:

I started moving forward using RT and when I released it, the car started moving backwards and it continued to move in reverse without any buttons being pressed! Holding RT again didn't move the car forward; it only stopped the car from moving backwards. And releasing RT again caused the car to move in reverse....

I hope this can be solved... :)</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="google-play-violation-of-usage-of-android-advertising-id-policy">
    <comment>
      <name>Starpilot</name>
      <datetime>2021-07-13 22:08</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>interesting, i imagine google assumes you use user data. XD</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
</articlecomments>
