<?xml version="1.0"?>
<articlecomments>
  <comments articlename="comments_enabled">
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2010-04-18 15:49</datetime>
      <message>It works! ;)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Robert</name>
      <datetime>2010-04-19 11:04</datetime>
      <message>Finally! Keep up the nice work. I like the way your site is evolving. </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Pesito</name>
      <datetime>2010-04-21 17:12</datetime>
      <message>Ich freue mich schon auf den RSS-Feed. In 3 Jahren dann ungef&#xE4;hr? ;-)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2010-04-21 23:43</datetime>
      <message>RSS-Feed habe ich schon mal &#xFC;berlegt. Mal sehen. ;)</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="rss_feed_added">
    <comment>
      <name>Robert</name>
      <datetime>2010-04-28 13:33</datetime>
      <website>http://www.cms-testlabor.de</website>
      <message>Woo Hoo, Erik was listening to me :-) &#xD;
I've added you to my feed reader.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Robert</name>
      <datetime>2010-04-28 14:28</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Oh, I have a design suggestion for your website, maybe you'll like it: http://bit.ly/bBeZC7</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2010-04-30 16:51</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Yeah, I guess some animated gifs and looping background music could really add something to my site. :)</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="windows7_backup_error_code_0x810000ff">
    <comment>
      <name>Robert</name>
      <datetime>2010-06-11 11:11</datetime>
      <website>http://www.cms-testlabor.de/blog</website>
      <message>I have also setup a regular backup on my external hard drive, so far without any weird error hex codes.&#xD;
But I am also experimenting with Microsofts SkyDrive, which gives you 25 GB (!) of free storage. So far it worked really well. This way if my place burns down or I am travelling with my laptop I will still keep my important files :-)</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="sony_ericsson_xperia_x10_mini_pro_hands-on_review">
    <comment>
      <name>Robert</name>
      <datetime>2010-07-30 10:33</datetime>
      <website>http://www.cms-testlabor.de</website>
      <message>Nice review! I really is a pretty decent phone. &#xD;
I am a bit shocked by a max of 2 days battery life, though. My HTC Magic can make 3 days if I don't use it much.&#xD;
Totally agree on the crappy music player that comes with it - I recently installed Mort Player (free), which seems to be a lot better.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2010-08-01 14:03</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>About battery life: I learned it the hard way after the phone died on me - after just some 36 hours of usage. NES emulation seems to need a lot of juice. YMMV, as always.&#xD;
&#xD;
I also use and can warmly recommend the Mort Player. Look at the picture of the phone in this review - the upper right shortcut actually points to Mort and not the default player (you can tell by the icon).</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>P&amp;Atilde;&amp;curren;r</name>
      <datetime>2010-08-07 18:20</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Emulation is a battery hog. Usually the emulator is written in a way that it doesn't sleep at all and is running the emulated CPU etc. all the time. &#xD;
I don't know what the official standby time is but the journalist tech geeks seems to charge their cellphones every evening.&#xD;
Only android 1.6... that ain't new... but it may be easier on the batteries with less features.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2010-08-09 21:06</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Yeah, 1.6 may not sound very exciting - it does work pretty well though so I can't really complain. But I am secretly looking forward to that rumored 2.x upgrade. Let's just wait and see.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-03-12 22:47</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Just to make things clear, an Android 2.1 update is available for this phone since several months back and it is working well. It does not slow down the phone (noticeably) and it fixes some problems - some web pages not working properly in the browser before now show up as expected, for example.</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="plantronics_.audio_995_vs_creative_hs-1200">
    <comment>
      <name>rob</name>
      <datetime>2011-01-03 20:48</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hey man great review.  I was actually considering buying both these products and returning the one I didn't like but now I don't need to.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Hab</name>
      <datetime>2011-02-13 00:56</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hey man, graet review. I just have 1 question. You say the Plantronic one is not chargable while using it. Is that becuase of the range of the USB cable or the fact that it has no power in it while its battery is dead? I mean if I were to buy a longer miniusb to usb cable and the headset died, could I plug that on in, w8 10 min and use it while being charge?&#xD;
&#xD;
Thanks fpr reading // Hab</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-03-12 22:42</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Sorry for taking so long time replying to this, but better late than never I guess. Fact is, the headset cannot be used when charging at all, it basically stays switched off while charging. The Creative headset does not suffer from this.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Don McGuiney</name>
      <datetime>2011-04-03 05:23</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I really enjoyed your review. I have a problem. I bought the Plantronics unit but it won't play any sound. It installed very easyband shows in the control panel but I can't use them. Any suggestions?&#xD;
Thanks,</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-04-03 15:41</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Don,&#xD;
&#xD;
there are a few things you can do to make sure things are set up properly. A common problem is that Windows is sending sound to the wrong device, since the OS can only direct sound output to one device at a time.&#xD;
&#xD;
After connecting the USB dongle and having turned on the headset, right click the speaker icon next to the Windows clock and select "Playback devices". The headset should show up in the list. Now, select the headset and click the "Set Default" button (or select "Default communication device" if you only want to use it with Skype and the like). Click "Properties" and make sure the volume is not set to zero (under the "Levels" tab).&#xD;
&#xD;
For mic setup, just select "Recording devices" instead of "Playback devices" and you will be able to figure out the rest.&#xD;
&#xD;
The changes should take effect immediately, but in some cases you may have to restart the application playing sounds (Windows Media Player, Skype or whatever).&#xD;
&#xD;
If this doesn't help, try using the headset with another PC.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>rex</name>
      <datetime>2011-09-18 20:01</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>i was wondering if i had more than 1 pair of 995 headphones&#xD;
can i pair both of them to the one usb dongle if both paired  ?&#xD;
thank you</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-09-21 19:11</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi rex,&#xD;
&#xD;
according to Plantronics, the dongle does not support multipoint. Thus, it is only possible to connect one headset, not two.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Barry</name>
      <datetime>2011-10-19 22:04</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Erik,&#xD;
Wanted to thank you for your help with the Windows Media, but also wanted to add that I had to change the option in Windows Media Player under Tools, Options, Devices, Speakers, Properties and select the Plantronics headset under that.&#xD;
thnx</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-10-19 22:21</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Barry,&#xD;
glad to be of help. :) And you have a good point - often the audio device can be selected directly from within the application in question. Skype is another example.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>richard</name>
      <datetime>2013-01-18 13:09</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>i bought 995h audio wireless,unfortunately when i play my songs cannot hear by other party specially on skype? TY.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-01-19 16:10</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Richard,&#xD;
&#xD;
to make sure that Skype is using the headset, go to Tools-&gt;audio settings and select the Plantronics as both microphone and speakers. Also see tip above in comments regarding setting the default audio devices in Windows.</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="shiny_icon_maker_-_new_features">
    <comment>
      <name>Erik Jonson</name>
      <datetime>2011-01-08 12:21</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>No need using fancy graphics program. This do the work in a minute.&#xD;
Thanks!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik Jonson</name>
      <datetime>2011-01-08 12:26</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Tweaking suggestion :-)&#xD;
It would be nice to have a digit showing what font size (and rotation) value is selected.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-01-08 20:18</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks for the feedback! The suggested functionality has been implemented, just waiting to be tried out. ;)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Robert (WebsiteToolTester)</name>
      <datetime>2011-01-11 11:25</datetime>
      <website>http://www.websitetooltester.com</website>
      <message>Cool new features! I'll give your icon maker a test run and write an article about it soon.</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="save_a_bundle_using_old_camera_lenses">
    <comment>
      <name>AJ Velazco</name>
      <datetime>2011-01-14 04:36</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Nice information...Excellent pictures</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Mithun Basak</name>
      <datetime>2011-07-08 15:05</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I like this Camera...........</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-07-09 13:27</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Yeah, it's pretty cool. ;)</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="getting_started_with_star_trails">
    <comment>
      <name>Henrik</name>
      <datetime>2011-02-18 21:04</datetime>
      <website>http://henrikpettersson.blogg.se</website>
      <message>Nicely done! I have tried this to, but only with one long exposure. They are - as you probably know - not that good. Even at ISO100 is there a lot of grain and all those annoying hot pixels on the sensor are visible. And just as you&#xB4;ve written will parts of the image be overexposed by the surrounding city lights. I don&#xB4;t have a remote shutter (besides the IR) and will thus keep this project in mind for the future.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-03-12 22:55</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks! I think I will give this a shot again sometime - I just got myself a brand new tripod just waiting to be tried out. ;)</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="diy_drop_handlebars_to_bullhorns">
    <comment>
      <name>Pamo</name>
      <datetime>2011-03-20 15:32</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Ser ju riktigt elegant ut!&#xD;
-M&#xE5;ster testas!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Ilja</name>
      <datetime>2011-03-24 19:39</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>V&#xE4;lt&#xE4;nkt och v&#xE4;lutf&#xF6;rt. Fem ringklockor av fem m&#xF6;jliga.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-03-24 19:46</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Man tackar! S&#xE5;gen l&#xF6;ser alla problem, som man ju s&#xE4;ger.</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="ask_731sp_3g_smartpad_review">
    <comment>
      <name>Raphael</name>
      <datetime>2011-03-22 16:32</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hia, &#xD;
&#xD;
I have the same thing, i got it when i went to hong-kong, but i hate android 2.1&#xD;
&#xD;
is there a way to root this thing?&#xD;
&#xD;
Thnx!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-03-23 18:44</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Well, I'm not sure rooting it will really solve any of the inherent limitations of 2.1 - the lack of flash support is a major flaw, and I have yet to find a working solution.&#xD;
&#xD;
But rooting is fun, so why not? I recommend you head over to the nice people at android tablets, they have a lot of good tips:&#xD;
&#xD;
http://www.androidtablets.net/forum/&#xD;
&#xD;
As for myself, I may do it sometime in the future. However, I'm not risking bricking this thing yet. ;)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>mark</name>
      <datetime>2011-04-09 01:25</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I purchased the ASK smart pad at HG as well. Have the keyboard as well. Can anyone tell me how to activate it?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-04-09 01:25</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>To use the keyboard, you need to activate USB Host mode. Go to Settings, select "USB Mode Select" and tick "Host Mode". The keyboard (or other USB devices, like USB sticks) can now be connected.&#xD;
&#xD;
After a reboot, the setting is reset and need to be reactivated. Apparently, it draws a lot of power so this should be a "good thing".</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>julie clarke</name>
      <datetime>2011-04-28 16:28</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I have one, my husband just brought it back from Hong Kong.  Its an ASK 741 SP if that helps.  I cant wait to get playing on it but I cant get it to log in to our wifi at home.  It finds it but then says its weak and drops off.  I know our wifi is strong and so I dont know what to do to get on and start playing.  Please please help</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-04-28 19:48</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Julie,&#xD;
&#xD;
tough one. I had zero problems setting mine up. The router was set to use WPA2 with AES and a pre-shared key. My network showed up in the list (Wireless &amp; network settings), I chose it, left security to auto, entered password and it just worked.&#xD;
&#xD;
I would do the usual things; reboot the router, play around a bit with the security settings (on both ends), and, if nothing helps, try the tablet on a friend's network. Maybe the tablet just doesn't play nice with your router. Also, I have heard that there are compatibility issues between some 802.11n devices, 802.11b/g (slower/older router) should be fine though. &#xD;
&#xD;
Hope this helps.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Alexander</name>
      <datetime>2011-05-07 10:27</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Erik, hi&#xD;
I've bought ASK 741SP (not 731SP)&#xD;
Device don't work, don't load OS - only start page&#xD;
Serviceman say that it's necessary to upgrade (firmware is damaged) , but manufacturer refused to upload firmware in order to I can solve my problem. Have U a firmware for 741SP, can U help me?&#xD;
&#xD;
Thanks a lot! </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-05-08 13:25</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Alexander,&#xD;
&#xD;
I'm afraid I will have to disappoint you. I don't have the firmware for 741, neither do I know which one it uses or how to acquire it. If it's under warranty, just exchange for a new one.&#xD;
&#xD;
If that is not an option, you can find a lot of information on how to install firmware/fixing bricked tablets here:&#xD;
&#xD;
http://www.slatedroid.com&#xD;
&#xD;
Please note that you always flash at your own risk.&#xD;
&#xD;
Good luck!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>edgar</name>
      <datetime>2011-06-16 09:39</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi erik,&#xD;
Hi bought 741 sp in HK, can you teach me how to remove the web site in the history, i want to remove some of the sites that i browsed but i don't know how. Please help. Thanks.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-06-18 10:58</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi edgar,&#xD;
&#xD;
to clear the history, open the browser and tap the menu button (top right of the screen, as always). From the menu, tap "more", then "Settings". Scroll down to "Privacy". From here, cache, history and cookies can be deleted.&#xD;
&#xD;
Google also saves your search history, which you can delete separately. From the Google start page, tap the "Settings" link. Scroll down to "Search history" and tap "Clear saved searches".&#xD;
&#xD;
Hope this helps.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Nigel</name>
      <datetime>2011-06-20 00:34</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I bought a 741 in HK and every time you swithch it on it say for all applications eg - The application AK Notepad (process com akproduction.notepad) has stopped unexpectedly. Please try again. Then is has  FORCE CLOSE. what has gone wrong, any ideas ?? Thanks </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-06-20 19:15</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Nigel,&#xD;
&#xD;
I am not familiar with the AK Notepad myself, but I guess it's possible that it just doesn't work on the SmartPad. This just tends to happen sometimes - it is a quite cheap product with almost zero support, after all. I'm afraid the only tip I can give you is to reinstall the app, and if that doesn't work, try to find an alternative (there should be plenty).</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Paul T</name>
      <datetime>2011-06-22 14:15</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Eric&#xD;
I have a 7" Tablet (Optus ZTE) It came with Android 2.1 but I upgraded it to 2.2. Only problem is 2.1 had a 'Host Mode' option in settings and the Case/Keyboard worked fine, but in 2.2 there is no Host Mode option in settings, and now the Keyboard case, doesn't work when I plug in the micro usb connector?&#xD;
Any Suggestions?&#xD;
Thanks.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-07-09 13:21</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Paul,&#xD;
&#xD;
I have yet to try to upgrade my device, and this is one reason. I have not been able to find any info on how to do this. Hopefully, a helpful soul will find your post and provide an answer.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Kate</name>
      <datetime>2011-08-15 14:34</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi&#xD;
I also bought ASK 731SP 3G in Hong Kong. Disappointed with it but would accept even being able to use it as a Kinder! Can I download my own selection of books from Amazon and if so HOW!! Please help.&#xD;
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-08-15 20:25</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Kate,&#xD;
&#xD;
sure thing! (Assuming you mean Kindle.) Just use the ASK and open the Android Market, then search for "Amazon Kindle" or something similar. The official Kindle app should show up. Download and install, then start the application. Log on with your Amazon username and password, and you are good to go. They have a few free samples (classics like Dracula or Pride and Prejudice) that you can try first.&#xD;
&#xD;
The application runs just fine on the ASK, maybe a bit sluggish when flipping but perfectly acceptable.&#xD;
&#xD;
Have fun!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Ronald Fung</name>
      <datetime>2011-09-15 11:42</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Do it has a root?  My 741 sp do not run root apps.  How can I fix it?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-09-17 13:47</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Ronald,&#xD;
&#xD;
I've been playing around with this, but no dice so far. I gave SuperOneClick a shot but it just kept hanging. :(</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Lilac </name>
      <datetime>2011-10-05 15:17</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Erik, &#xD;
I found the tablet turns itself back on very often. It uses more battery. I only installed Aldiko as my bookreader and  juice defender. I couldn't work out what cause the problem.&#xD;
Any idea?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-10-11 23:05</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Lilac,&#xD;
&#xD;
weird problem. My tablet only turns itself on when I plug in the charger, which seems to be a "feature". If you feel bored, you might try a factory reset, it's always a blast. ;)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>alex</name>
      <datetime>2011-10-16 05:43</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Eric. I have bought ASK 741 in HK this summer. Very nice item...but...the same problems with skype that you posted above. Please tell me could you solve this problem to use the skype application on ASK? Thank you in advance.&#xD;
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-10-16 15:52</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Alex,&#xD;
&#xD;
I have not been able to resolve this issue. Skype on Android is still immature and crashes on many devices (it works great on my SonyEricsson X10 Mini Pro though). Just keep updating to the latest version, I hope they will have these issues sorted out soon.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Bryanna</name>
      <datetime>2011-11-10 03:01</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I also bought a 3gSmart pad from HK. It is okay to play games and read books but the battery life is only about 1 hour. There was a message sent to it to say to click here and upgrade your battery life which I did. I have downloaded the file and it is in the book marks but now I can't find where the bookmarks are&#xD;
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Yuifann</name>
      <datetime>2011-11-22 13:33</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Everyone,&#xD;
&#xD;
Android 2.3 to 3.0 upgrade is available for ASK 741SP.&#xD;
I've dropped off the device to the local technical support center 2 weeks ago...approved the wifi connection as well &#xD;
***Required to drop off the smartpad for at least 3-5 days/Technician works part-time; therefore, expect pick up the other days later***</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-11-22 20:56</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Sounds interesting. Is there any way to upgrade the 731SP as well? It's running 2.1 which really starts to show its age.&#xD;
&#xD;
Anyway, post back here and let us know how it worked.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Christopher</name>
      <datetime>2012-01-05 04:24</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message> Hi Eric,I have a problem with my ASK 7 inch 3G Smartpad, model: ASK 741SP. I cannot unlock now for I attempted to unlock it for more than 5 times. It's advised now to sign-in with my GOOGLE account but I cannot because the unit is not activated to get WIFI signal. My other option is to reset the unit or go back to it's original factory setting....Please help me.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-01-08 21:27</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hello Christopher,&#xD;
&#xD;
I'm very sorry to hear that! I've never had this problem myself, but this thread at AndroidTablets may be of some help:&#xD;
&#xD;
http://www.androidtablets.net/forum/android-tablet-usage-tips-tricks/6280-forgot-your-unlock-pattern.html&#xD;
&#xD;
If you are still stuck, try searching the forum for other threads or open up a new one. A lot of helpful people over there.&#xD;
&#xD;
Hope it works out!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>mark</name>
      <datetime>2012-01-27 18:26</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>hi can u help me because every tym i open  my ask 741sp only start page what im doing to do?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-01-30 22:48</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi mark,&#xD;
&#xD;
I'm not quite sure what you mean. If it does not boot up at all and you just got it, it may be a hardware of firmware problem. Try contacting the shop where you bought it to see if you can get a new one. By the way, a corrupt firmware can usually be fixed by downloading the latest one from the manufacturer and extracting it to the root of the SD card. I'm afraid I don't know where to get the firmware though. Try contacting ASK. Their home page address is:&#xD;
http://uthk.com</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Yuifann</name>
      <datetime>2012-02-03 13:38</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Mark &amp; Erik,&#xD;
&#xD;
You may contact the Technican at ASK (support at uthk dot com)&#xD;
&amp; I advise to upgrade your OS to Android 3.0 ....Things will be solve out &gt;&gt;&gt; Remember to download it by Desktop PC &amp; connect your smartpad by OTG later on</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Yuifann</name>
      <datetime>2012-02-03 13:53</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Christopher,&#xD;
&#xD;
The device is required to sign in by gmail's account (first time use...won't ask again) Android - free OS is connect with google's &amp; gmail is now free for register.  Afterward, you'll able to access to Wifi connection...If you need dump screens, please leave your email's contact or write to me (dreamycloset at gmail dot com)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-02-04 17:27</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Yuifann,&#xD;
 &#xD;
and thanks for your interest in this article. Now, you did link to a Honeycomb system image which I highly doubt will work right off the bat for the SmartPad. To avoid people bricking their devices, I removed the download link. Please let me know (using the contact form) if you have successfully updated the device to 3.0 using the image. If so, I apologize and will re-add the link.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>mark</name>
      <datetime>2012-02-04 19:25</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Yuifann, &#xD;
&#xD;
Hi yuifann u have a link of Android 3.0 so i can download the file  to upgrage my os thx....</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>wildlizard</name>
      <datetime>2012-02-10 01:32</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>i have same to but there is a log-in how can i remove the log-in</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>joven</name>
      <datetime>2012-06-30 05:12</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>how to hard reset this pad...please tell me</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-06-30 09:42</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Joven,&#xD;
&#xD;
you can find instructions in doing a factory reset here:&#xD;
&#xD;
http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kqOSicNPFIY&#xD;
&#xD;
BTW: A regular reset, that is, restarting the unit if it freezes, is simply done by inserting a pin into the hole marked "Reset" next to the power button.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>J. Lab,</name>
      <datetime>2012-09-08 23:32</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi, I bought a ASK 750 SP in HK in May. I am looking for the owner manual, if there is one.&#xD;
Glad to read you soon.&#xD;
Thanks.&#xD;
JL.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-09-09 01:37</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi J. Lab,&#xD;
&#xD;
not sure there is one! It should work just like any "standard" Android 4.0 device though, so if you are having specific questions about the software, googling it should do it. Plenty of forums and blogs around with info on Android 4.0. Otherwise, just contact ASK directly: &#xD;
http://uthk.com</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Nkay</name>
      <datetime>2012-09-13 16:20</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hello Erik,&#xD;
just got an ASK 755SP and its in chinese. been trying to change to english language please can you help</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>J. Lab,</name>
      <datetime>2012-09-14 01:24</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi,&#xD;
good idea. Thanks.&#xD;
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-09-15 20:45</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Nkay,&#xD;
&#xD;
simply check out this video which contains instructions on how to change language from Chinese to English on Android 4:&#xD;
&#xD;
http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=M_LR5mFGDsw&#xD;
&#xD;
Good luck. :)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Wagne</name>
      <datetime>2012-12-30 01:10</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I  had ASK 750SP 3G running Android 4.0.  The pad contains a HDMI Out Port and the package comes with a HDMI cable.  When I connected the cable to TV and changed TV source to HDMI.  The TV displayed "No Signal".  Please advise how to use TV as a display screen?&#xD;
&#xD;
Thank you. </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-01-07 23:28</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Wagne,&#xD;
&#xD;
sorry for the late reply... and for not having an answer! I have a Gemei G9 tablet, and I have never gotten  the HDMI port on it to work. Apparently, just connecting it to the TV and switching TV to the correct HDMI port should do it. Maybe another TV and cable would solve it?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Morph</name>
      <datetime>2013-01-14 01:41</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi, I recently got an ASK 913SP tablet and I forgot the password to my google account and the lock pattern. Are you familiar on how to reset this unit back to factory defaults. I have been googling a lot but this unit seems not popular&#xD;
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-01-14 19:04</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Morph,&#xD;
&#xD;
I will check with ASK on how to do this. In the meantime, maybe you should simply try to recover the password for the Google account? Go here:&#xD;
&#xD;
https://accounts.google.com/RecoverAccount</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="fake_raindrops_macro_photography">
    <comment>
      <name>Robert</name>
      <datetime>2011-04-07 17:32</datetime>
      <website>http://www.snapp.de</website>
      <message>Good stuff, where's the Like button?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-04-07 19:11</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks! And to answer your question: nowhere - yet. Facebook integration should be a piece of cake though, maybe I'll have a look at it this weekend or so.</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="getting_linux_on_that_dingoo">
    <comment>
      <name>Erik F.</name>
      <datetime>2011-04-12 13:10</datetime>
      <website>http://threemilesfinal.com</website>
      <message>Nice article and great site!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-04-12 19:52</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks! And nice name, by the way. ;)</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="the_social_network">
    <comment>
      <name>Robert</name>
      <datetime>2011-04-26 10:48</datetime>
      <website>http://www.snapp.de</website>
      <message>I really liked the movie, so you won't get a like this time ;-)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-04-26 22:30</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>There are other options as well. If you don't Like it - Tweet it!</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="vignetting_with_the_gimp">
    <comment>
      <name>Marky T</name>
      <datetime>2011-05-05 13:51</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Excellent way to make a subtle effect. Just what I was looking for so thanks for the info.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-05-07 13:13</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Glad to be of help. :)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>G</name>
      <datetime>2012-08-27 07:37</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>This is too easy, thanks for sharing.  Method 2 is surely my favourite.</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="diy_dslr_camera_sling_strap">
    <comment>
      <name>Henrik</name>
      <datetime>2011-05-15 21:53</datetime>
      <website>http://henrikpettersson.blogg.se</website>
      <message>I was close to buy a Blackrapid RS-4 for the hideous price of 700 SEK. Until a found that my the bag to my new lens came with a basic sling strap. Everyone should have a sling strap, because it&#xB4;s just better! &#xD;
Get an extra strap and fasten to your tripod aswell. It isn&#xB4;t perfect but it makes life a bit easier.&#xD;
Great article btw.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-05-17 22:12</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Good idea about a tripod strap. I like my tripod, it was definitely a big upgrade from the el cheapo I had before. But the better they are, the bigger and heavier they get (mostly). Next DIY project, maybe?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Benjamin</name>
      <datetime>2012-05-10 17:21</datetime>
      <website>http://www.idea27.net</website>
      <message>Hey dude this article is great.&#xD;
&#xD;
Something I wanted to add, I have a nikon d700 and I think all nikon's have on their sides triangular "keychains" placed to attach your strap. I managed to place my hook directly on it, eliminating the need for the tripod base.&#xD;
&#xD;
Keep up the good work&#xD;
Ben</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-05-10 19:38</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Benjamin,&#xD;
&#xD;
why, thank you. :) And yeah, that makes things easier. Just don't let it fall, it's a great body!</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="dingoo_a320_-_first_impressions">
    <comment>
      <name>Sebastian</name>
      <datetime>2011-07-12 22:08</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Yeah I just ordered one last night I got it black because the wite ones where expensive</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-07-13 22:07</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Kinda the same here, they had no white ones in stock where I got it. On the other hand, I like black devices better than white ones. Makes one stand out from the Apple crowd. ;)</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="photo_gift_tips_3_items_for_100_eur_each">
    <comment>
      <name>Robert</name>
      <datetime>2011-11-14 10:24</datetime>
      <website>http://www.snapp.de</website>
      <message>Ok, nice stuff. But where can I get it?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-11-14 19:38</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I often get my stuff from Amazon. It may cost a bit more, but they are reliable and usually deliver fast. Check the links above.&#xD;
&#xD;
Seems like they don't have the Nissin SpeedLite Di622 Mark I anymore though. You will need to pay up a bit to get the Mark II, but the new features should be worth it.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Robert</name>
      <datetime>2011-11-16 14:30</datetime>
      <website>http://www.snapp.de</website>
      <message>Cool, just ordered the lens. Wasn't able to use your link, though. They don't ship to Germany...</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-11-16 20:49</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Aw, that's too bad. But anyway, great choice buddy! Have fun with the lens. :)</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="photo_sunday_illusion">
    <comment>
      <name>quimby</name>
      <datetime>2012-03-04 18:26</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I think that this is really awesome.&#xD;
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-03-05 18:57</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thank you quimby! :)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>karina</name>
      <datetime>2012-06-23 22:27</datetime>
      <website>http://vk.com</website>
      <message>how to do that??&#xD;
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-06-24 01:22</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Karina,&#xD;
&#xD;
it's quite simple actually - for folding instructions, just follow the link:&#xD;
&#xD;
http://www.coolopticalillusions.com/illusions/coolprinttriangle.pdf&#xD;
&#xD;
I found using a fairly a long lens (&gt;100mm) helps "flatten" the look of the triangle. Getting the right angle is critical. Put the triangle on the floor or on a table and walk around it to find the right spot. Mount the camera on a tripod there. The tripod helps, since you can make small adjustments to the angle and composition without having to start over every time. Hand-holding gets very tiresome. Keep shooting and adjusting until you get it right.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>mohsin</name>
      <datetime>2012-09-11 18:42</datetime>
      <website>http://grafixyard.com</website>
      <message>well done </message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="sweet_dreams">
    <comment>
      <name>Henrik</name>
      <datetime>2012-03-14 22:29</datetime>
      <website>http://www.henrikpettersson.nu</website>
      <message>Grymt kreativt och inte minst snyggt. Saknar fotos&#xF6;ndag en del. Jag vet, jag ligger p&#xE5; latsidan. Eller ja, tiden g&#xE5;r &#xE5;t till annat om man ska skylla p&#xE5; n&#xE5;got. Bra jobbat iaf!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-03-15 22:39</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Tackar tackar! Jo, jag f&#xF6;rst&#xE5;r att du har en del annat att g&#xF6;ra. Men att ta kort &#xE4;r skoj, gl&#xF6;m inte det! Fotar vatten nu i min hemmastudio byggd av en stol och ett bord. Handduken &#xE4;r n&#xE4;ra till hands. ;)</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="gemei_g9_android_tablet_hands-on">
    <comment>
      <name>MrTasselhof</name>
      <datetime>2012-04-10 04:43</datetime>
      <website>http://www.youtube.com/user/mrtasselhof?feature=mhee</website>
      <message>Decent run down of the device.  Sorry to hear you have had some of those build quality type issues, but glad to hear it is workable for you.  In regards to your article here are some things that may you or your readers out.&#xD;
1) Head on over to SlateDroid.com Forums.&#xD;
 - You will find plenty of threads and support for the Gemei G9 in it's own section&#xD;
2) Download the ICS firmware posted there and install it&#xD;
3) Run the "SuperScript" and you can open up the market and compatibility along with rooting and tweaking.&#xD;
&#xD;
In regards to Skype, there is a fully working previous version 2.5.x.x posted in a separate thread that you can download and install to have working video both ways.&#xD;
&#xD;
The battery life on the device is already great, but can be made even better by downloading SetCPU and following the settings guide thread in the Benchmark section of SlateDroid.&#xD;
&#xD;
Keep up the good work!&#xD;
&#xD;
Tasselhof</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-04-11 19:11</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks for the feedback! I will try out what you suggested; I might post another article about it later on how it went.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Spaceman</name>
      <datetime>2012-08-15 09:50</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Erik,&#xD;
I have tried getting the HDMI connection to work also but I also get nothing (please post something if you have any update to why).</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-08-16 20:30</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Spaceman,&#xD;
guess I'm not the only one then. ;) I'll post info here if I get it to work.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Jon</name>
      <datetime>2012-10-12 18:45</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Have you heard of the GemeiG9T?... you should probably do a review on that!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-10-12 18:50</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Jon,&#xD;
&#xD;
thanks for the info. Since my G9 is faulty (broken buttons), I will try to have it replaced or repaired. Maybe I could pay a little extra to get the G9T? Will have a look next time I'm in Hong Kong.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-12-18 20:14</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Just a quick update - they let me change the G9 in Hong Kong for a new one. The buttons now work, and the built-in browser is much more stable. :)</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="canon_eos_600d_vs_1000d">
    <comment>
      <name>Alix</name>
      <datetime>2012-08-30 23:02</datetime>
      <website>http://https://www.facebook.com/hufaholder</website>
      <message>Awesome comparison between the Canon EOS 600D and 1000D! I just wanted to leave a quick comment to let you know about our awesome gadget for photographers of every level. :) The Hufa Holder lens cap clip was designed by photographers after they had, like many other photographers do, lost a TON of lens caps. The nifty little device just clips right on your strap and keeps your cap in place while you're shooting! Turns out, we lose a whole lot less lens caps this way! :) This also works no matter what camera you are using. Here is a video for you to check it out http://bit.ly/Nu7FPx. Thanks again for sharing your Canon EOS comparison! Hope you'll check out our gadget when you get a chance.&#xD;
&#xD;
Have a great day,&#xD;
Alix&#x2028;&#xD;
www.facebook.com/HufaHolder&#xD;
www.hufaholder.com</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-09-01 19:22</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Alix&#x2028;,&#xD;
&#xD;
I usually don't tolerate advertising disguised as comments, but the item seems fairly nifty so I'll let it slip. However, I have been using my DSLR for over three years and I have never lost a lens cap.</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="shiny_icon_maker_-_more_new_features">
    <comment>
      <name>Jon</name>
      <datetime>2012-10-12 18:42</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I love this.. it is really cool. </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-10-12 18:46</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks Jon. :)</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="canon_50mm_1.8_stuck_on_camera_body">
    <comment>
      <name>Suliman</name>
      <datetime>2012-10-29 20:24</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>I just had the same problem in my canon 550D. My 50mm 1.8 II fell on the ground. I did not check it after that and inserted it into the camera. The lens stuck in the camera. After few attempts I forced the lens and end up with the same result you show on the picture. Happy that my camera is woking perfectly without a problem.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-11-11 20:47</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Suliman,&#xD;
&#xD;
sorry to hear you had the same problem, but happy you solved it without any nasty side effects! I noticed that my camera has started to sporadically have problems communicating with some lenses afterwards - seems like the pins inside the mount took a beating. :(</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="installing_android_2.3_gingerbread_on_sonyericsson_xperia_x10_mini_pro">
    <comment>
      <name>power ranger</name>
      <datetime>2012-12-18 14:10</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>is there any safer way?</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-12-18 20:11</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi power ranger,&#xD;
&#xD;
let me put it this way: If you feel worried about doing this, don't do it! It's unsupported and will void your warranty. The main reason I did this was because my phone felt old. If a new version of Android could breathe new life into it, great - if only for a few months. And if I would brick it, I would just be looking forward for a new Christmas gift for myself.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Pelle</name>
      <datetime>2012-12-20 17:11</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hej Erik!&#xD;
In English:&#xD;
I rooted my phone, using SuperOneClick. Downloaded xRecovery installer from "Google Play", ran it, get the same look as on the guide you linked to. However when I click to install, only thing that happens is that the three little icons turn into crossed red rings. Do I have to do something before this step?&#xD;
Thanks</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-12-20 20:24</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Pelle,&#xD;
&#xD;
I did not point this out in my guide, but the AddictiveTips page I link to states that BusyBox need to be preinstalled. This might be you problem. Check out this thread:&#xD;
&#xD;
http://androidforums.com/sony-ericsson-xperia-x10/265818-having-trouble-installing-xrecovery.html&#xD;
&#xD;
I will update this article to point that out.&#xD;
&#xD;
Good luck!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Simon </name>
      <datetime>2012-12-21 07:26</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hey Erik&#xD;
&#xD;
This is a great guide, thanks for this. I am from Denmark, but will write in English for the sake of the wide world. Pelle says that when installing xRecovery he gets just red rings. As far as I understand from the comments on xRecovery, this is because read/write permission is needed on the rooted device, and not because of a lack of Busybox. I will continue to play with it:-)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Pelle</name>
      <datetime>2012-12-21 10:39</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hej Erik,&#xD;
I did have Busybox. What I did was instead to download a Root Manager Lite and put the files directly into /system/bin instead of using the failing installer. It worked fine! Simon you can try it!&#xD;
&#xD;
Now I am on MiniCM7Pro V21 of CM for 2.3.7. It's like a fresh phone! Why did you opt to use another mod, Erik?&#xD;
&#xD;
My Swedish (physical) keyboard is mismatching BTW. Did you solve that?&#xD;
&#xD;
Tack&#xD;
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Pelle</name>
      <datetime>2012-12-21 14:45</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>More: I tried the app Mini ROM Manager and changed HW Keyboard layout to qwerty-se-fi, according to some tips, but it still didn't work, no &#xE5;&#xE4;&#xF6; etc. Rebooted, the setting is kept, but keyboard is still wrong. Just to add to the above...</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-12-21 22:05</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>@Simon: Have fun!&#xD;
&#xD;
@Pelle: Should work. The only thing I can think of is that under "Language &amp; Keyboard" in the settings, the keyboard should be set to "Default input". Hope this helps.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Simon</name>
      <datetime>2012-12-22 08:34</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hey again, &#xD;
thanks for the tips on this site. After spending quite a long time on this, I finally got another mod to work but only to find out that it did not fix the thing where my touchscreen stops working when I use the keyboard. That means I will have to buy some Galaxy now:-)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2012-12-24 11:00</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi Simon,&#xD;
&#xD;
thanks! :) Just a matter of time until I replace it myself. Currently leaning towards the Huawei Ascend P1.&#xD;
&#xD;
Merry Christmas!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>tanvay</name>
      <datetime>2013-01-11 23:32</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hey,&#xD;
@Pelle: have you used this mod (MiniCM7Pro V21 of CM for 2.3.7. ) for x10 mini pro ?&#xD;
</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>rob7000</name>
      <datetime>2013-01-23 21:12</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi, I have to access the Service menu but the numer  *#*#7378423#*#* doesn't work anymore ! probably because the file ServiceMenu.apk is not installed with this ROM... I have problems with my internal speaker and I have to go on this secret menu to try fixing it. I found a file ServiceMenu.apk  2.3.3 but my phone tels me "App not installed" , my phone is rooted..</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>shimanto</name>
      <datetime>2013-02-15 18:13</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>hey Erik,&#xD;
thanks for your help and advise. i'm from bangladesh. i've sony ericsson x10 (not mini). i want to upgrade android 2.3. how can i do that . will you help me to do that  </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2013-02-15 23:05</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hi shimanto,&#xD;
&#xD;
I cannot help you directly with that, but do take a look at these forum SonyEricsson X10 forum sections at CyanogenMod and XDA Developers:&#xD;
&#xD;
http://forum.cyanogenmod.org/forum/438-sony-ericsson-xperia-x10/&#xD;
http://forum.xda-developers.com/forumdisplay.php?f=614&#xD;
&#xD;
They should provide all information you need. Have fun!</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
</articlecomments>
