<?xml version="1.0"?>
<articlecomments>
  <comments articlename="comments_enabled">
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2010-04-18 15:49</datetime>
      <message>It works! ;)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Robert</name>
      <datetime>2010-04-19 11:04</datetime>
      <message>Finally! Keep up the nice work. I like the way your site is evolving. </message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Pesito</name>
      <datetime>2010-04-21 17:12</datetime>
      <message>Ich freue mich schon auf den RSS-Feed. In 3 Jahren dann ungef&amp;Atilde;&amp;curren;hr? ;-)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2010-04-21 23:43</datetime>
      <message>RSS-Feed habe ich schon mal &amp;Atilde;&amp;frac14;berlegt. Mal sehen. ;)</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="rss_feed_added">
    <comment>
      <name>Robert</name>
      <datetime>2010-04-28 13:33</datetime>
      <website>http://www.cms-testlabor.de</website>
      <message>Woo Hoo, Erik was listening to me :-) &#xD;
I've added you to my feed reader.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Robert</name>
      <datetime>2010-04-28 14:28</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Oh, I have a design suggestion for your website, maybe you'll like it: http://bit.ly/bBeZC7</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2010-04-30 16:51</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Yeah, I guess some animated gifs and looping background music could really add something to my site. :)</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="windows7_backup_error_code_0x810000ff">
    <comment>
      <name>Robert</name>
      <datetime>2010-06-11 11:11</datetime>
      <website>http://www.cms-testlabor.de/blog</website>
      <message>I have also setup a regular backup on my external hard drive, so far without any weird error hex codes.&#xD;
But I am also experimenting with Microsofts SkyDrive, which gives you 25 GB (!) of free storage. So far it worked really well. This way if my place burns down or I am travelling with my laptop I will still keep my important files :-)</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="sony_ericsson_xperia_x10_mini_pro_hands-on_review">
    <comment>
      <name>Robert</name>
      <datetime>2010-07-30 10:33</datetime>
      <website>http://www.cms-testlabor.de</website>
      <message>Nice review! I really is a pretty decent phone. &#xD;
I am a bit shocked by a max of 2 days battery life, though. My HTC Magic can make 3 days if I don't use it much.&#xD;
Totally agree on the crappy music player that comes with it - I recently installed Mort Player (free), which seems to be a lot better.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2010-08-01 14:03</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>About battery life: I learned it the hard way after the phone died on me - after just some 36 hours of usage. NES emulation seems to need a lot of juice. YMMV, as always.&#xD;
&#xD;
I also use and can warmly recommend the Mort Player. Look at the picture of the phone in this review - the upper right shortcut actually points to Mort and not the default player (you can tell by the icon).</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>P&amp;Atilde;&amp;curren;r</name>
      <datetime>2010-08-07 18:20</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Emulation is a battery hog. Usually the emulator is written in a way that it doesn't sleep at all and is running the emulated CPU etc. all the time. &#xD;
I don't know what the official standby time is but the journalist tech geeks seems to charge their cellphones every evening.&#xD;
Only android 1.6... that ain't new... but it may be easier on the batteries with less features.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2010-08-09 21:06</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Yeah, 1.6 may not sound very exciting - it does work pretty well though so I can't really complain. But I am secretly looking forward to that rumored 2.x upgrade. Let's just wait and see.</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="plantronics_.audio_995_vs_creative_hs-1200">
    <comment>
      <name>rob</name>
      <datetime>2011-01-03 20:48</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Hey man great review.  I was actually considering buying both these products and returning the one I didn't like but now I don't need to.</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="shiny_icon_maker_-_new_features">
    <comment>
      <name>Erik Jonson</name>
      <datetime>2011-01-08 12:21</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>No need using fancy graphics program. This do the work in a minute.&#xD;
Thanks!</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik Jonson</name>
      <datetime>2011-01-08 12:26</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Tweaking suggestion :-)&#xD;
It would be nice to have a digit showing what font size (and rotation) value is selected.</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Erik</name>
      <datetime>2011-01-08 20:18</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Thanks for the feedback! The suggested functionality has been implemented, just waiting to be tried out. ;)</message>
    </comment>
    <comment>
      <name>Robert (WebsiteToolTester)</name>
      <datetime>2011-01-11 11:25</datetime>
      <website>http://www.websitetooltester.com</website>
      <message>Cool new features! I'll give your icon maker a test run and write an article about it soon.</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <comments articlename="save_a_bundle_using_old_camera_lenses">
    <comment>
      <name>AJ Velazco</name>
      <datetime>2011-01-14 04:36</datetime>
      <website/>
      <message>Nice information...Excellent pictures</message>
    </comment>
  </comments>
</articlecomments>
